<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Visual Studio on Funky Si's Blog</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/tags/visual-studio/</link><description>Recent content in Visual Studio on Funky Si's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2014 20:00:45 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.funkysi1701.com/tags/visual-studio/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>In the Zone</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2014/in-the-zone/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2014 20:00:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2014/in-the-zone/</guid><description>&lt;p>On Friday night I had the urge to fire up Visual Studio and tomorrow (Monday) I move house.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What’s with that? Why am I in a programming mood when I have boxes to pack and shelves to take apart?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For the last few weeks I have been too busy with other things to do much programming or when I had the time I felt more like relaxing than learning anything new.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>How do I get into the programming zone, what was it about this particular weekend that made me want to? Was it just the fact I had no time to concentrate on it, or is there some more useful factor that controls my desire to code?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I can think of a few factors that I should make note of.&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Peace and quiet – Friday night I had the place to myself so I could concentrate and do whatever I wanted.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Ideas – Before I started I had some ideas, why don’t I try doing x. Once I have a coding idea I need to investigate it and see where it goes.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Break from routine – Friday night was the start of a whole week away from work, this gives me more time to forget about the daily stress of the office and think about other things.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Goals – Work annoyed me on Friday and if I want to achieve my goal of working in development more then I need to work at it.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>I am not sure how I can put these into practise so that I spend more time on development but we will see. One thing I want to achieve in my new home is a quiet place to concentrate and think without distractions, I have a few options which I will investigate over the next few weeks.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Anyway need to get back to packing boxes.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>