<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>2014 on Funky Si's Blog</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/2014/</link><description>Recent content in 2014 on Funky Si's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2014 20:00:45 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.funkysi1701.com/2014/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>To boldly go where no SQL has gone before</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2014/to-boldly-go-where-no-sql-has-gone-before/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2014 20:00:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2014/to-boldly-go-where-no-sql-has-gone-before/</guid><description>&lt;p>My last post proved quite popular so I am wondering if I can combine a post about IT and Star Trek.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Years ago I used to have lists of Star Trek episodes, which included such information like original air date, production number, episode title and brief description.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>One thing that was hard to keep track of was how many episodes were written by a specific person. This is because episodes are written by multiple people. A column called writer would then need to contain multiple people, another option would be to have columns called writer1, writer2 etc. This wouldn’t help either as you wouldn’t know which column a specific writer had been saved in.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img class="img-fluid" alt="" src="https://storageaccountblog9f5d.blob.core.windows.net/blazor/wp-content/uploads/2014/10/manytomany.jpg?w=559&amp;amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy"
/>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The relationship between writer and episode is known as a many to many relationship. An episode can have many writers and a writer can have written many episodes. To achieve this structure in a SQL database you will need three database tables as it is not possible to create a many to many join between two tables. The first table will contain all the episodes, the second table will contain all the writers, the third table known as a junction table, will contain the relationship between the two.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Let’s do an example so we can see how this would work. Gene Roddenberry creator of Star Trek wrote the pilot episode ‘The Cage’. So Gene would be added to the writers table with an id of 1 and The Cage would be added to the episode table with an id of 1. In the junction table, it has two columns episode and writer, so we would enter 1 and 1 into these columns.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;">&lt;code class="language-sql" data-lang="sql">&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>&lt;span style="color:#66d9ef">Select&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#f92672">*&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#66d9ef">from&lt;/span> Episode e
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>&lt;span style="color:#66d9ef">Join&lt;/span> EpisodeWriter ew &lt;span style="color:#66d9ef">on&lt;/span> e.id &lt;span style="color:#f92672">=&lt;/span> ew.EpisodeId
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>&lt;span style="color:#66d9ef">Join&lt;/span> Writer w &lt;span style="color:#66d9ef">on&lt;/span> w.id &lt;span style="color:#f92672">=&lt;/span> ew.WriterId
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>&lt;p>But if Gene Coon and Gene Roddenberry had writing credits on The Cage we would need to add Gene Coon to the writing table and add an extra entry to the episodewriter table.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I am going to do more posts based on this as I expand the database structure to include other information, I may go on to create stored procedures for bringing back certain information or I may use this as an example to talk about coding a user interface.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Destination Star Trek</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2014/destination-star-trek/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2014 20:00:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2014/destination-star-trek/</guid><description>&lt;p>As a break from my usual topics I am going to talk about what I did over the weekend.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img class="img-fluid" alt="" src="https://storageaccountblog9f5d.blob.core.windows.net/blazor/wp-content/uploads/2014/10/10670061_10152884492389155_77781042960777157_n.jpg" loading="lazy"
/>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I am a huge star trek fan, so me and my wife Laura went to Destination Star Trek, a convention held in London. This is a picture of us in costume, my wife created a tribble costume (A tribble is an alien race that just consists of a ball of fur) and I am wearing an original series captains uniform. We had a great time.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There are several things that made this trip special.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Friends&lt;/strong>: After the last convention I remember thinking how much better the convention would be with a group of friends. Shortly afterwards I started listening to the trekmate podcast, eventually this lead to me helping out with their website and making friends via twitter with many of the hosts. This weekend was the first time I met up with them and it was great to put faces to names (or twitter names)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Writers and Directors&lt;/strong>: Star Trek has a great philosophy. In the future human beings will put their differences aside and work together to explore the galaxy, this is one reason why Star Trek is so popular even after almost 50 years. This philosophy has been created by the writers and other creative staff over the years. My favourite Star Trek film is Wrath of Khan which was directed by Nicholas Meyer, this weekend I got my DVD signed by him and was able to tell him how I still enjoyed that film over 30 years after it was made. He said that he really appreciated me saying that. Listening to his talk later on, it was fascinating to hear his insights into making my favourite film. It is the writers and directors that make our favourite characters who they are, the actors themselves aren’t allowed to ad lib, all they do is flesh them out with a bit of emotion or a mannerism, it is the writer that create our favourite lines or situations that we remember.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Seven of Nine&lt;/strong>: During my teenage years I had lots of posters of Seven on my walls. Seven of Nine was the ex-borg that walked around the ship in a skin tight catsuit, but she was also highly intelligent and continued to explore what it was to be human. It was great to have my photo taken with her, even if it was rushed due to the large number of people that wanted their picture taken.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Trivia&lt;/strong>: On the Friday of the convention, Laura took part in the beginners trivia challenge, she won. On Saturday I took part in the intermediate trivia challenge, I did really badly only got 3 correct, On Sunday I took part in the captain level challenge and I won. I really wasn’t expecting that, after I did so badly the day before. Thanks Marc Stamper and Destination Star Trek for organising that it was great fun, and also fun to meet the other trekkies who I had been competing against via twitter.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Party!&lt;/strong>: On Saturday night we went to a party, we had Romulan Ale to drink, we had some of the actors performing songs (James Darren was particularly good), and some of the actors mingled with fans, it was great to see the actors relaxing and if you were lucky you could chat to them, I asked Vaughn Armstrong how he was enjoying the music, he loved it.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>This is just a taste of what I got up to, there was lots more, like seeing alien costumes, listening to talks, sitting on a mockup of the bridge. Only one way to end this post, &lt;strong>Live Long and Prosper!&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Windows 9 or do I mean 10</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2014/windows-9-or-do-i-mean-10/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2014 20:00:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2014/windows-9-or-do-i-mean-10/</guid><description>&lt;p>Like many systems administrators I watched as the news came out yesterday about the latest version of windows. What would it be like? What would it be called? Would it be better or worse than previous versions?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I was shocked when the name of the new operating system was revealed to be Windows 10. What really!? At first I though someone had tweeted a photoshopped image of the press conference, but no it was really going to be called Windows 10.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img class="img-fluid" alt="Windows 10" src="https://storageaccountblog9f5d.blob.core.windows.net/blazor/wp-content/uploads/2014/10/windows_10_fullwidth.jpg?w=800&amp;amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy"
/>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Windows 10 is the next operating system to be released after windows 8, many had been calling it windows 9 or windows Threshold.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Microsoft has never had a fixed naming convention for its OSes, so should we really be that surprised at its new name.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Windows 1.0 (1985)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Windows 2.0 (1987)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Windows 3.0 (1990)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Windows 95 (1995)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Windows 98 (1998)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Windows ME (2000)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Windows XP (2001)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Windows Vista (2007)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Windows 7 (2009)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Windows 8 (2012)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Windows 10 (2015)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>One reason Microsoft may have gone with with Windows 10 is because they wanted to signify that the coming Windows release would be the last “major” Windows update. What does it mean to be the last major update?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you look at the list of OSes above you will see that between XP and Vista was a huge 6 years, this gap is/has caused a huge headache for IT professionals (me included). Software was written for XP because that is all that was available, when XP moved out of support earlier this year it caused loads as problems as people tried to get this software to work on more modern OSes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If windows 10 is around for a long time we may end up with a similar situation to XP, in that loads of software will run only on it and cause problems if you try and port it to whatever comes next. I am only a trainee developer so I don’t know what is involved with building an OS, but I would imagine there must be things that are very difficult or almost impossible to fix without ripping them out and starting again which is what happens when a new version of an OS is written.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Only time will tell if Windows 10 really is the last version of windows and what will happen to the OS in the future. What ever the case I am downloading a preview so I can have a look (I want my start menu back!)&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>What is the difference between Development and Operations?</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2014/what-is-the-difference-between-dev-and-ops/</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Sep 2014 20:00:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2014/what-is-the-difference-between-dev-and-ops/</guid><description>&lt;p>I want to learn Development and eventually move into a development role. But what is the difference between development and what I already do?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Put simply Development or programming is the creation of new programs, websites or databases.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>IT Operations or System Administration is the administration of existing servers, websites or databases.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I have been doing System Administration since I started my job back in 2006. What you do as part of this role can be very simple like setting up new users or computers to something very complex like upgrading the version of Exchange that the company uses for its emails.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As part of my role I have done a lot of tasks that could be described as development. I have created databases and built new database structures like tables, views and stored procedures. I have also assisted the development department with testing, setting up visual studio, building websites and databases from code.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Can I describe myself as a developer? I would say yes, I have done plenty of work that is development work.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Can I get a job as a developer? Possibly but it would depend on the role. I have many of the skills that developers use, but I have limited knowledge in many areas. What I need to do is concentrate my efforts onto the development work I do and delegate as much administration work as I can so my knowledge can increase.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A Buzz word in IT at the moment is DevOps. I have lost count of the number of times .NetRocks or RunAsRadio have mentioned it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>DevOps is the integration of IT Development and Operations, it emphasises the need for the two departments to work closely together to achieve common goals. In big companies the two departments can pull against each other if you are not careful, but in my case as I do both roles, it would be very difficult for the development side of myself to blame the operations side of myself for a problem.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This I think puts me in a good position, I just need to learn more development and I will make a valuable addition to someone’s development team.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>I love Nagios</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2014/i-love-nagios/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2014 20:00:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2014/i-love-nagios/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://storageaccountblog9f5d.blob.core.windows.net/blazor/wp-content/uploads/2014/09/nagios.png" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">&lt;img class="img-fluid" alt="Nagios" src="https://storageaccountblog9f5d.blob.core.windows.net/blazor/wp-content/uploads/2014/09/nagios.png?resize=212%2C50" loading="lazy"
/>
&lt;/a>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You may not have heard of Nagios but it has saved my bacon quite a few times.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Nagios is an open source server monitoring application that runs on many linux flavours.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I can’t remember exactly when I first installed nagios but I am guessing it was sometime in 2007/8. My boss gave me a book about it (which I never read) and told me to create a system to monitor the companies servers.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Nagios is not simple to set up. It relies on setting up various Hosts and services. Hosts are usually physical servers that you want to monitor and services are all the services you want to monitor. As this is a linux program all these can be configured by editing the right config file&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Nagios is very flexible and can be expanded easily with the use of plugins, if you want to monitor something there is usually a plugin available. If you have a dell server running openmanage software there is even a plugin that allows the temperature of your server to be monitored.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you want to monitor windows servers the use of nsclient++ is a real advantage. This is a simple client that runs as a service on your windows server. This allows nagios to track memory, cpu, disk space, performance and services, in fact almost everything that you would want to monitor.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Over the years I have kept a close eye on Nagios and added extra checks as new services were added or problems encountered. A few years ago I dabbled with sending alerts out via SMS message and once I got a smart phone found an app to keep track of Nagios 24/7.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But recently I have started wondering if Nagios is the best way to monitor modern servers like 2012 or remote services like Azure. I want something that is easy to expand as your IT infrastructure expands. Something that relies on running on a linux OS requires your IT staff have a knowledge of linux and you keep that server maintained and updated.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My question is: Is Nagios still the best way to monitor my servers?&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>