<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Source Control on Funky Si's Blog</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/tags/source-control/</link><description>Recent content in Source Control on Funky Si's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 25 Jul 2022 18:00:45 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.funkysi1701.com/tags/source-control/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>A brief history of Source Control</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2022/a-brief-history-of-source-control/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Jul 2022 18:00:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2022/a-brief-history-of-source-control/</guid><description>&lt;p>I have been thinking back to when I started using source control and some of the different tools I have used over the years.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When I was learning to code it was some time after I had learned the basics that I learnt about source control. Back when I started writing webpages I would have a folder containing all my html, css, images etc and I would FTP these up to my web server. If I made a change to a file I would reupload the file I changed, or reupload all my files to make sure I didn&amp;rsquo;t miss anything.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It was sometime later that I learnt about source control. I can&amp;rsquo;t remember exactly when, but I suspect it was after I had used it at work. (between 2006 and 2010 as a best guess, my oldest repo says it is 12 years old!)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Source control (or version control) is the practice of tracking and managing changes to code. These tools provide a running history of code development and help to resolve conflicts when merging.&lt;/p>
&lt;img src="https://www.funkysi1701.com/images/svn.jpg" width="400px" align="left" />
&lt;p>The first source control tool I remember using was subversion. The windows client for this was called &lt;a href="https://tortoisesvn.net/downloads.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">TortoiseSVN&lt;/a>
and is still available today. I know this as my current job has some legacy code which still uses it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Back then, to use Subversion you needed to set up a linux server with subversion on it, and you would then connect over your LAN to it from your development machine. This was before the days of github, where everything was hosted on a SaaS service somewhere. I do not remember the process of getting everything setup, but with it being linux, there was no doubt a load of config files to edit, and different dependencies to install.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Over the years I installed various web interfaces to allow &amp;ldquo;&lt;em>browsing&lt;/em>&amp;rdquo; of source code, some even had bug trackers built in. The ones I can remember are &lt;a href="https://trac.edgewall.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Trac&lt;/a>
and &lt;a href="https://www.redmine.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Redmine&lt;/a>
. Both look to still be available and you can probably install them if you want to remember way back when.&lt;/p>
&lt;img src="https://storageaccountblog9f5d.blob.core.windows.net/blazor/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/github-octocat.png?resize=300%2C158&amp;ssl=1" width="400px" align="right" />
&lt;p>The first hosted source control tool I remember using was &lt;a href="https://bitbucket.org/product/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">bitbucket&lt;/a>
and this as far as I can tell has only ever supported git. So I am guessing I imported my subversion repos into git ones at this point. The reason for bitbucket was chosen was it allowed private repositories for free, at that point github was probably available but only provided public repositories.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After bitbucket the git repos where moved to Azure DevOps or Visual Studio Team Services as it was called back then. This move was mainly to take advantage of the builds and releases feature and to decommission some aging build servers.&lt;/p>
&lt;img src="https://www.funkysi1701.com/images/azuredevops.png" align="left" width="400px" />
&lt;p>This brings me to today where I have a mix of public repos on github and private repos on Azure DevOps. For building my code I use a mix of github actions and Azure Pipelines. As Microsoft own both services now, there is a fair amount of crossover between the two services, however it is far from certain which service is the future.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Wow, my code has moved around a lot over the years. From no source control, to subversion, to git, to Bitbucket to Azure DevOps!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Github Vs Bitbucket Vs Visual Studio Team Services</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2017/github-vs-bitbucket-vs-vsts/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2017 20:00:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2017/github-vs-bitbucket-vs-vsts/</guid><description>&lt;p>As a developer using source control and git is bread and butter of what we do. Github is probably the most popular and widely known hosting service for source control but I have also used Bitbucket and Visual Studio Team Services. Lets have a look at each one and what they offer. Note while I have included prices I have only tried out the free versions.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="github">Github&lt;a class="anchor ms-1" href="#github">&lt;i class="fas fa-link">&lt;/i>&lt;/a>&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;img class="img-fluid" alt="" src="https://storageaccountblog9f5d.blob.core.windows.net/blazor/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/github-octocat.png?resize=300%2C158&amp;amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy"
/>
&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>URL: &lt;a href="https://github.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://github.com/&lt;/a>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Private Repositories: Not Available for free&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Public Repositories: Unlimited&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Team Size: Unlimited&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Prices: $7 per month for unlimited private repositories, $25 per month for 5 users then $9 per month per user&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>This is probably the most widely used service for hosting code. Over 13 million repositories of code. This is an ideal solution if you want your code to be publicly viewable, but take care not to publish passwords, private keys or your companies trade secrets. Every developer should have a Github account for displaying bits of code they are proud of.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There are a number of externally built APIs that link into Github for doing extra features, like building, code coverage etc&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="bitbucket">Bitbucket&lt;a class="anchor ms-1" href="#bitbucket">&lt;i class="fas fa-link">&lt;/i>&lt;/a>&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;img class="img-fluid" alt="" src="https://storageaccountblog9f5d.blob.core.windows.net/blazor/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/d8TRzzL.png?resize=150%2C150&amp;amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy"
/>
&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>URL: &lt;a href="https://bitbucket.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://bitbucket.org/&lt;/a>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Private Repositories: Unlimited&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Public Repositories: Unlimited&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Team Size: Less than 5&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Prices: $10 per month for 10 Users, $100 per month for 100 Users, $200 per month for Unlimited Users&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>At my last job we used Bitbucket extensively for all our projects. All the code was private so only the team could access it, however before I left we were approaching the 5 user limit (but looking at these prices cost seems very reasonable)&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="visual-studio-team-services">Visual Studio Team Services&lt;a class="anchor ms-1" href="#visual-studio-team-services">&lt;i class="fas fa-link">&lt;/i>&lt;/a>&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;img class="img-fluid" alt="" src="https://storageaccountblog9f5d.blob.core.windows.net/blazor/wp-content/uploads/2016/11/Visual-Studio-Team-Services.png?resize=300%2C136&amp;amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy"
/>
&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>URL: &lt;a href="https://www.visualstudio.com/team-services/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://www.visualstudio.com/team-services/&lt;/a>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Private Repositories: Unlimited&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Public Repositories: Not Available&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Team Size: Less than 5&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Prices: $30 per month for 10 users, and other features paid for via Azure Invoices&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Visual Studio Team Services or VSTS is Microsoft’s version control solution and I have only just started using it, however what I have seen I like. There are lots of options for building your code so VSTS is more than just hosting your code it is verging on a Continuous Integration/Delivery solution. Being a Microsoft product there are numerous links to Azure and it is easy to deploy stuff to that platform.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>All three have options for tracking issues but VSTS have options to add Stakeholder users which would allow none developers to add and keep track of issues and progress with them.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If I want to run tests, look at code coverage VSTS is probably the solution I would go for, if I want something that is public I would go for Github. What do you think which of these is your favourite?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>What should be in Source Control?</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2016/what-should-be-in-source-control/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Nov 2016 20:00:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2016/what-should-be-in-source-control/</guid><description>&lt;p>I am currently working on source code that is over 5Gb in size. This is mostly due to a poorly thought out folder structure, there are code files, images and Excel files all jumbled together. I think a clear distinction should be made between source code and data.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="source-code">Source Code&lt;a class="anchor ms-1" href="#source-code">&lt;i class="fas fa-link">&lt;/i>&lt;/a>&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>I will define source code as anything that is written in order to compile and run the project. If it is a webpage it will be all the HTML, CSS and Javascript or any file used to produce these. I would also include any configuration files and files used to build/deploy the website or project. Anything that is compiled from your source files can safely be ignored.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="data">Data&lt;a class="anchor ms-1" href="#data">&lt;i class="fas fa-link">&lt;/i>&lt;/a>&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>I would define data as anything that is added to the project during its life. So if you have an upload option, anything that is uploaded I would describe as data. The site should still function without (or very little) data.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="images">Images&lt;a class="anchor ms-1" href="#images">&lt;i class="fas fa-link">&lt;/i>&lt;/a>&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Images can fit into both groups. Any icons or images attached to the functionality of the project I would class as source code. However anything that is uploaded should be classed as Data.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="databases">Databases&lt;a class="anchor ms-1" href="#databases">&lt;i class="fas fa-link">&lt;/i>&lt;/a>&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The database should also be classed as both. The data, anything that is inside a database table should normally be classed as data. Stored Procedures, Functions and Views are all Source Code and would benefit from version control.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="source-control--backup">Source Control != Backup&lt;a class="anchor ms-1" href="#source-control--backup">&lt;i class="fas fa-link">&lt;/i>&lt;/a>&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Source control is not an excuse not to backup things. Don’t just commit files to source control so you know you can restore them if you need to. Files in general in source control are there so you can see how they changed over time as the code base changed. Files in you backup are a snapshot of what the application was at a point in time and will include ALL the data.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>One last point before I end. If you are hosting on a Cloud Computing platform like Azure it gives you an easy way to distinguish between Data and Code.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Anything in your&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Web App = Code&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Blob Storage = Data&lt;/li>
&lt;li>SQL = Data/Code&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Each project is unique and there will always be exceptions to these suggestions but I think this is a good goal to have. What do you think?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Clever things with MS Access</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2016/clever-things-ms-access/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2016 20:00:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2016/clever-things-ms-access/</guid><description>&lt;p>I hate MS Access and especially developing with it as you can’t do any thing clever with it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Wrong, Wrong, Wrong!&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There are a few clever things I have been able to script to make developing with it passable. I still would rather use Visual Studio but this improves the experience a fair bit.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="source-control">Source Control&lt;a class="anchor ms-1" href="#source-control">&lt;i class="fas fa-link">&lt;/i>&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Access files are binary (I use the ADP/ADE file format but I assume other Access file formats have the same problem) and so you can’t diff them to see what has changed. This is bad.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>However there is a solution to this. A tool called Access SVN and can be downloaded from &lt;a href="https://accesssvn.codeplex.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://accesssvn.codeplex.com/&lt;/a>
, this gives you a way to extract to text files all the forms and reports that are in Access. Before every commit I would manually run this tool on my ADP file and extract to text files, then I would commit these text files to source control and could easily see what had changed in each commit.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Despite the name Access SVN, the tool is not tied to subversion, you can use any source control system, I use git.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Also included in this tool is a way to do this with the command line, so you can make this a build step on your build server. I have not used this extensively yet, but the syntax is fairly simple&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;">&lt;code class="language-bash" data-lang="bash">&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>asvn.exe e &lt;span style="color:#e6db74">&amp;#34;path to Access file&amp;#34;&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#e6db74">&amp;#34;path to txt files&amp;#34;&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#e6db74">&amp;#34;*.*&amp;#34;&lt;/span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>&lt;p>The filter at the end &lt;em>.&lt;/em> allows you to specify what to extract so you could extract all forms/reports beginning with D with &amp;ldquo;&lt;em>.D&lt;/em>&amp;rdquo;. I had trouble using &lt;em>.&lt;/em> because the names of my forms/reports contain characters not allowed in a windows file name. I am sure there is a way round this but I haven’t had chance to look into it further yet.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="testing-ms-access">Testing MS Access&lt;a class="anchor ms-1" href="#testing-ms-access">&lt;i class="fas fa-link">&lt;/i>&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Surely testing is not possible with MS Access? I would have agreed with that statement the other day until I found a neat way of testing if a feature is enabled.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Firstly a bit of background. I develop using MS Access 2003 because the design view is far easier to use, however because it is out of support all my users use MS Access 2010. MS Access 2010 has a feature called Tabbed Documents which allows all forms and reports to open in new tabs so you can easily switch between them. This feature can only be enabled in MS Access 2010 and has no effect if opening with MS Access 2003.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you use Access SVN on your Access file with tabbed documents turned on and off you will see UseMDIMode: 0 and UseMDIMode: 1 show up in the Database properties file. UseMDIMode: 0 means that tabbed documents is turned on.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In powershell I can now write a test to see if UseMDIMode: 0 can be found in the database properties file&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;">&lt;code class="language-powershell" data-lang="powershell">&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>Get-Content &lt;span style="color:#e6db74">&amp;#34;General\Database properties.dbp.txt&amp;#34;&lt;/span> | Select-String &lt;span style="color:#e6db74">&amp;#34;UseMDIMode: 0&amp;#34;&lt;/span> -quiet
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>&lt;p>If the test passes True will be returned, if it fails null will be returned.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On my build server I scripted the extraction of Database properties.dbp.txt from the ADP file with asvn.exe before running this test. While not strictly needed as Database properties.dbp.txt should be in source control, it is possible that someone could forget to extract the text files from the ADP, with this step you are always testing what is enabled in the binary file.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="ms-access-connection-strings">MS Access Connection Strings&lt;a class="anchor ms-1" href="#ms-access-connection-strings">&lt;i class="fas fa-link">&lt;/i>&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>While developing with MS Access I often swap the database connection to point to my local machine or a build server. I always try and remember to only ever commit with this set to the live database to avoid obvious problems.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The other day I found on &lt;a href="https://stackoverflow.com/questions/16411430/change-access-server-connection-from-command-line" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">stackoverflow&lt;/a>
a way to script this. I love this! I can include this step in my deployment process and it will overwrite what ever the connection string is in source control with what your production environment needs.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>All you need to run this step is, (note it is spaces between the parameters not commas)&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;">&lt;code class="language-bash" data-lang="bash">&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>cscript connect.vbs Project.adp &lt;span style="color:#e6db74">&amp;#34;ServerName&amp;#34;&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#e6db74">&amp;#34;DatabaseName&amp;#34;&lt;/span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>&lt;p>The contents of connect.vbs can be found on the &lt;a href="https://stackoverflow.com/questions/16411430/change-access-server-connection-from-command-line" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">stackoverflow article&lt;/a>
. It is also possible to pass username and password if your environment requires this.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="compiled-ade">Compiled ADE&lt;a class="anchor ms-1" href="#compiled-ade">&lt;i class="fas fa-link">&lt;/i>&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The last clever thing I do with MS Access is convert my ADP file into the compiled ADE version. To manually do this there is an option in the tools menu.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To automate this I run&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;">&lt;code class="language-bash" data-lang="bash">&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>cscript createADE.vbs &lt;span style="color:#e6db74">&amp;#34;path to ADP&amp;#34;&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#e6db74">&amp;#34;path to ADE&amp;#34;&lt;/span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>&lt;p>The contents of createADE came from this &lt;a href="https://social.msdn.microsoft.com/Forums/office/en-US/01fd48a9-258e-4405-86f1-adfb2f1057ee/create-an-access-2007-ade-from-a-adp-via-commandline?forum=accessdev" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">forum post&lt;/a>
, the only change I made was to comment out some of the echo statements so it would run silently as part of my build process. It should be noted that cscript and wscript are almost identical and either will run these scripts however in a command line environment cscript is preferable, and wscript should be used in a windows environment.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I am quite surprised at how much I have managed to do in terms of scripting the build and deployment process for MS Access. I still don’t like developing with Access but this has definitely improved things.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Automatic Git Tagging</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2016/automatic-git-tagging/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Jun 2016 20:00:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2016/automatic-git-tagging/</guid><description>&lt;p>One of the features of git is the ability to tag a point in my change history with a tag. For a while now I have been manually tagging my code whenever I do a release, so I can easily work out what has changed by doing a diff between two tags.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now that I am automating my release process with TeamCity I am thinking about how to manage my tags better.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>TeamCity has a setting called VCS Labeling which comes in very handy.
&lt;img class="img-fluid" alt="" src="https://storageaccountblog9f5d.blob.core.windows.net/blazor/wp-content/uploads/2016/06/Untitled.jpg?w=1595&amp;amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy"
/>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Configuring it is fairly simple as it only has three settings.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>VCS root to label&lt;/strong>: This is obviously the url to your git repository
&lt;strong>Labeling pattern&lt;/strong>: This is the text of the label to be added.
&lt;strong>Label successful builds only&lt;/strong>: Do you really want to add a tag if the build failed?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A tag needs to have a unique name, so adding a tag just called &lt;strong>deployed&lt;/strong> won’t work. When I used to add tags manually I used the naming convention of &lt;strong>deployedyyyymmdd&lt;/strong>. While this naming convention is possible with TeamCity I use something a bit more complex to provide more information about what has been deployed.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>TeamCity provides lots of parameters that can be used in your build steps and also in the Labeling pattern box. I started off using &lt;strong>deployed-build-%system.build.number%&lt;/strong> as my tag which just marks git with the TeamCity build number.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When I run a TeamCity deployment I don’t always use the same configuration options, I deploy locally, to a test server or to production and sometimes I just deploy the frontend or the backend. How cool would it be to include this information in the tag text?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Well the next step was to change my Labeling pattern to &lt;strong>deployed-build-%system.build.number%-%ServerName%-%DatabaseName%-%FrontEndPath%&lt;/strong>, this adds the backend database config settings and the path the frontend was deployed to. Now when looking at git you can see commits marked with multiple tags, one for each deployment that succeeded and the tag will indicate the settings used during that deployment.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now I will never forget to add the tag after a release as the adding of a tag is part of the deployment process, if the deployment fails the tag won’t be added. I can test my deployment to test and git will show if this has been successful, and when I deploy live this will also show up.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>How do you use tags? Do you mark successful builds with a tag? Why not let me know or leave a comment below.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Revisiting Team City</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2016/revisiting-teamcity/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2016 20:00:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2016/revisiting-teamcity/</guid><description>&lt;p>Last year I blogged about &lt;a href="http://www.funkysi1701.com/2015/04/01/teamcity/">Team City&lt;/a>
, well I have been looking at it again recently. In that time they have even changed their logo!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Lets start with thinking about what I want my Continuous Integration server to do.&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Check out my code from source control (usually master but all feature branches would be even better)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Configure specific setting for build&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Build my code&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Build my databases&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Run any unit tests&lt;/li>
&lt;li>(Optional) Run deployment to Azure Test/Live site&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>There are probably other things I want to achieve but I will start with these six.&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Checking out code from source control is something Team City does out of the box, so I can safely say I have done this now. It even monitors a branch for changes and initiates a new check out.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Team City allows you to create specific build steps so in theory you can have multiple builds for every variation of settings that you want for your code. I have not tried this yet apart from building with the default config, but I don’t expect it will be too difficult.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>I have managed to get my code to build with Team City, it took a bit of tweaking the different build steps but wasn’t too difficult. Team City has a visual studio build agent which takes you solution file and does what it needs to. The one problem I have found with this step is that I get errors with my tests if I select a Debug config instead of Release.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Databases are always the problem part of the deployment. So far I have manually deployed my databases but I intend on revisit this step. A &lt;a href="https://stackoverflow.com/questions/21555038/how-can-i-execute-sql-scripts-using-teamcity" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">stackoverflow&lt;/a>
post suggests that I can run SQL code via Team City in the following way by creating a command line executable:&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;">&lt;code class="language-bash" data-lang="bash">&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>Command executable: c:&lt;span style="color:#ae81ff">\P&lt;/span>rogram Files&lt;span style="color:#ae81ff">\M&lt;/span>icrosoft SQL Server&lt;span style="color:#ae81ff">\1&lt;/span>00&lt;span style="color:#ae81ff">\T&lt;/span>ools&lt;span style="color:#ae81ff">\B&lt;/span>inn&lt;span style="color:#ae81ff">\s&lt;/span>qlcmd.exe
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>Command parameters: -S &lt;span style="color:#f92672">[&lt;/span>ServerName&lt;span style="color:#f92672">]&lt;/span> -i &lt;span style="color:#f92672">[&lt;/span>PathToSQLScript&lt;span style="color:#f92672">]&lt;/span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>&lt;p>I have yet to try this but I am hopefully that it will just work. Dropping a database and restoring a back and then running different SQL scripts is all possible from TSQL, so I should be OK. Watch this space for more details.&lt;/p>
&lt;ol start="5">
&lt;li>Running the unit tests got me stuck for a while. I tried setting it up using VSTest or MSTest neither worked mainly because a config file wasn’t being copied with the test binaries. When I tried using NUnit it just worked. The tests that failed gave me a few config settings to change.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>I have powershell scripts that deploy to Azure websites, I think that these could form the basis of a deployment to Azure. Again the difficult step here may end up being deploying all the different databases to Azure. This is also the riskiest step as I need to connect to live servers which is why I will leave this to last, at the very least I could generate scripts that do a full deployment.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>That’s it for now. Once I have this all working I will revisit again with details of the database steps as I am expecting a few challenges to overcome. What have you used a CI Server for? Are there other things I want to achieve from a project like this? Why not contact me or leave a comment below&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>My git repository is too large!</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2016/my-git-repository-is-too-large/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Feb 2016 20:00:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2016/my-git-repository-is-too-large/</guid><description>&lt;p>Today I did a clone of one of my git repositories and it took ages to download. Looking into what got downloaded it was easy to see why. The .git folder was over 500Mb in size.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I know how this has happened. This repository was created in 2013 and has been used by me as a dumping ground for lots of things related to the code which never should have been committed.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Since 2013 I have learnt a lot more about coding and git so the current version of the files in git isn’t too bad. But git keeps the history of changes for every file so bad practices like this are kept.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What can I do about this? Well what does google suggest? I found this &lt;a href="http://stevelorek.com/how-to-shrink-a-git-repository.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">blog post&lt;/a>
.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It suggests ways of listing all the large files that are stored in git and a way to remove them. As I am the only person that regularly commits to this repository I see no problem with giving it a go.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I will summarise the steps here.&lt;/p>
&lt;pre tabindex="0">&lt;code>git clone url
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;p>Now you need all the remote branches so there is a bash script to run&lt;/p>
&lt;pre tabindex="0">&lt;code>#!/bin/bash
for branch in `git branch -a | grep remotes | grep -v HEAD | grep -v master`; do
git branch –track ${branch##*/} $branch
done
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;p>Another bash script then lists the top 10 large files&lt;/p>
&lt;pre tabindex="0">&lt;code>#!/bin/bash
#set -x
# Shows you the largest objects in your repo’s pack file.
# Written for osx.
#
# @see http://stubbisms.wordpress.com/2009/07/10/git-script-to-show-largest-pack-objects-and-trim-your-waist-line/
# @author Antony Stubbs
# set the internal field spereator to line break, so that we can iterate easily over the verify-pack output
IFS=$’\n’;
# list all objects including their size, sort by size, take top 10
objects=`git verify-pack -v .git/objects/pack/pack-*.idx | grep -v chain | sort -k3nr | head`
echo “All sizes are in kB. The pack column is the size of the object, compressed, inside the pack file.”
output=“size,pack,SHA,location”
for y in $objects do
# extract the size in bytes
size=$((`echo $y | cut -f 5 -d ‘ ‘`/1024))
# extract the compressed size in bytes
compressedSize=$((`echo $y | cut -f 6 -d ‘ ‘`/1024))
# extract the SHA
sha=`echo $y | cut -f 1 -d ‘ ‘`
# find the objects location in the repository tree
other=`git rev-list –all –objects | grep $sha`
#lineBreak=`echo -e “\n”`
output=“${output}\n${size},${compressedSize},${other}”
done
echo -e $output
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;p>After running the script you will see details of your largest files. I had *.msi and *.exe files in the mix. To remove them run the following, where filename is the path to the file that needs removing.&lt;/p>
&lt;pre tabindex="0">&lt;code>git filter-branch –tag-name-filter cat –index-filter ‘git rm -r –cached –ignore-unmatch filename’ –prune-empty -f — –all
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;p>To reclaim the disk space run the following commands&lt;/p>
&lt;pre tabindex="0">&lt;code>rm -rf .git/refs/original/
git reflog expire –expire=now –all
git gc –prune=now
git gc –aggressive –prune=now
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;p>Now push your changes back to the remote server.&lt;/p>
&lt;pre tabindex="0">&lt;code>git push origin –force –all
git push origin –force –tags
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;p>Now if you do a clone it will be much smaller than before and you can get back to coding much quicker, without having to wait.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Common git commands</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2015/common-git-commands/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Aug 2015 20:00:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2015/common-git-commands/</guid><description>&lt;p>I use git as my source control system. Here are some of the most common git commands in no particular order.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Check Out a git Repository &lt;strong>git clone /path/to/repository&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add files to commit &lt;strong>git add &lt;filename>&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Commit files to &lt;strong>git git commit -m “Commit message”&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Push changes to server &lt;strong>git push origin master&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Show status &lt;strong>git status&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Create new branch &lt;strong>git checkout -b &lt;branchname>&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Switch to a branch &lt;strong>git checkout &lt;branchname>&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Get remote changes &lt;strong>git pull&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Merge a different branch into the current one &lt;strong>git merge &lt;branchname>&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>View merge conflicts &lt;strong>git diff&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Temporarily stash uncommitted changes &lt;strong>git stash&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Undo a commit &lt;strong>git reset –hard &lt;commit>&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Show details about a commit &lt;strong>git show &lt;commit>&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Show version history of current branch &lt;strong>git log&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Gets all remote branches &lt;strong>git fetch origin&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Most of the time I use the &lt;a href="https://sourceforge.net/projects/gitextensions/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">git extensions&lt;/a>
tools to do my git work, but there are times when only the command line will do.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Writing better Git commit messages</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2015/writing-better-git-commit-messages/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Jul 2015 20:00:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2015/writing-better-git-commit-messages/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img class="img-fluid" alt="" src="https://storageaccountblog9f5d.blob.core.windows.net/blazor/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/git_commit.png?w=439&amp;amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy"
/>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I always use source control for my coding changes, however some of my commit messages leave something to be desired.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I always try to write a commit message but I often think that the change themselves should be enough to indicate what I did. I also don’t need to include who made the change or the time and date and that gets included automatically.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Here are some tips I have found that may help me in the future.&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Ask yourself why you are making this change. The Who, When and What are already being covered so it is only the why that needs including in the commit message.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>If your commit breaks something or causes side affects or a new dependency this should be included in the commit message. If your commit breaks functionality, consider if you really need to commit it yet, maybe only commit once fixed?&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>If your commit includes a long list of changes consider if the commit needs splitting into several commits. It is easy to only commit one or two files write a specific commit message and then commit the rest of the changes separately.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Consider including a subject for larger commits. The following comes from the git manual.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;pre tabindex="0">&lt;code>Though not required, it’s a good idea to begin the commit message with a single short
(less than 50 character) line summarizing the change, followed by a blank line and then
a more thorough description. The text up to the first blank line in a commit message
is treated as the commit title, and that title is used throughout Git.
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;ol start="5">
&lt;li>If you use a subject follow the following conventions:&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Limit of 50 characters&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Start with a capital letter&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Do not end with a full stop&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Use the imperative mood i.e. write as if issuing a command&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item></channel></rss>