<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>StarTrek on Funky Si's Blog</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/tags/startrek/</link><description>Recent content in StarTrek on Funky Si's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Oct 2017 20:00:45 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.funkysi1701.com/tags/startrek/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Discovery – My thoughts so far</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/discovery-my-thoughts-so-far/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Oct 2017 20:00:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/discovery-my-thoughts-so-far/</guid><description>&lt;p>I tried to resist but I am going to have to write about the new Star Trek series Discovery. Warning this post is going to include SPOILERS. If you read on you have been warned.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I watched the first two episodes of the brand new Star Trek TV show. As I am an international viewer I used Netflix, if you are from the US you need to use CBS All Access. &lt;img class="img-fluid" alt="" src="https://storageaccountblog9f5d.blob.core.windows.net/blazor/wp-content/uploads/2017/05/DAD0hTKUAAAUkTP.jpg?resize=662%2C366&amp;amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy"
/>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I have heard a lot of complaining that the show is not free to watch. CBS is making Star Trek Discovery to make money, if they don’t make money they will stop making it. Its as simple as that.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.netflix.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Netflix&lt;/a>
costs £5.99 per month and &lt;a href="https://www.cbs.com/all-access/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">CBS All Access&lt;/a>
costs $5.99 per month. I don’t believe this is a lot of money. The 5.99 above allows you to watch any of the 726 Star Trek episodes at any time of day whenever you want as many times as you want, plus you have access to all the other movies or TV shows available. I don’t think this is too much to ask.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Back to Discovery. I loved it! It felt like Star Trek. I had feared it might only share the name and would be an action filled TV show that had little in common with what he had seen before. I was wrong this is definitely a show that can proudly call itself Star Trek.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>The Klingons&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When it was first announced that the Klingons would feature in the new show I was a bit “meh”. We had done lots with the Klingons before and they had never been my favourite alien race. &lt;img class="img-fluid" alt="" src="https://storageaccountblog9f5d.blob.core.windows.net/blazor/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/star-trek-discovery-klingons-1002567-1280x0.jpg?resize=300%2C165&amp;amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy"
/>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The look of the Klingons was also going to be changed, I have to admit this didn’t bother me. Klingons have had their look updated before. In 1966 Klingons had dark faces and smooth foreheads, in 1979 the forehead ridges were added as the first Star Trek movie was made, and now Discovery has removed all hair from Klingons. I can explain it away as productional changes, I don’t need an on screen explanation like we had on Enterprise (or even DS9).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What I have seen so far is a menacing alien race that fits with what we have seen before with lots of references to honor, Kahless and speaking Klingon. I must admit reading all the subtitles is getting a bit tiresome, but that is a minor issue.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Conflict&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Historically Star Trek has not featured conflict between the main starfleet characters due to the idea that humanity has evolved beyond this. DS9 got round this by having Odo and Kira who are not starfleet characters so can have a little bit of conflict. Discovery has completely abandoned this idea.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In the pilot episode, the Michael Burnham commits mutiny on her captain, even attacking her with a vulcan nerve pinch. In the third episode we finally meet the discovery crew. Gone are the TNG days where the ships crew are like a family, I am not sure I can think of a single character that would call another character “friend”. We are in a time of war so this would be expected, however I do hope we see deepening friendships form between characters.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I am OK with the change to feature more conflict. I must admit the darkness of the third episode, did stop to make me think a bit, however by the fourth episode I was won over.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Cast&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The story is concentrated around Michael Burnham, so I do worry that other characters won’t get a look in. However from what I have seen Michael Burnham is a great character. She is a strong female character, with a intriguing back story relating to Sarek and possibly also Spock.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Saru the alien character on the show, played by the very tall Doug Jones is great. From the trailers he was all about sensing death, but there is far more to him than that. I am looking forward to learn more about him and his threat ganglia.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As the show has gone on we have started to learn about the other characters like Captain Lorca, Tilly and Paul Stamets.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Title Sequence&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I don’t like the opening title sequence, it feels very cheap like a draft version which hasn’t been finished yet. I was looking forward to a title sequence that would show off the USS Discovery, maybe like TNG where it warps around our own solar system. What we see is some of the tech that features in Star Trek which is nice but I want more. The theme tune while great that it features parts from the classic theme doesn’t stand on its own. I can hum all the other TV shows themes, and now after 4 episodes would struggle to do that.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>However I expect that after a while I will grow to like this more.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Overall&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I like Discovery and I will keep watching it. I want to find out what happens to the characters. There are no annoying characters like other shows have had. There is character development, none of the characters are going to finish where they started. I want more friendship between characters, but I expect that will come, I want more exploring and doing Star Trek stuff, but most of all I want more episodes, roll on next weeks show.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Other things I noticed&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Sound effects on the bridge are awesome, it makes me feel at home&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The USS Discovery doesn’t feature in the first two episodes despite being the title of the show.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Others have noted that Captain Georgiou has books on her shelf which feature classic episode titles&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Star Trek is back with Discovery</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/star-trek-is-back-with-discovery/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Sep 2017 20:00:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/star-trek-is-back-with-discovery/</guid><description>&lt;p>In &lt;a href="https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/star-trek-is-back-in-2017">November 2015&lt;/a>
it was announced that a new Star Trek series was going to be launched. It has been a long wait with multiple delays but Star Trek Discovery is finally here.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Star Trek Discovery launches in the US on 24th September and in the UK on 25th September.&lt;/p>
&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/UoV3kc05Nwc?rel=0" width="560" height="315" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen">&lt;/iframe>
&lt;p>Lets have a look back how we got here.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Star Trek was created by Gene Roddenberry in the 1960s. He imagined a show where we would explore the galaxy while also exploring the human condition. He described it as a wagon train to the stars. However it was cancelled after 79 episodes and three seasons due to budget cuts and low viewers.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After cancellation its popularity boomed in reruns. In the mid 1970s an animated series was created. But demand for Star Trek continued until a new Star Trek show was commissioned called Phase Two.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In 1977 Star Wars came out, and the phase two idea was cancelled and turned into a movie. In 1979 we got Star Trek The Motion Picture. It went massively over budget and failed to really capture the Star Trek spirit.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A much cheaper sequel was created in 1982 Star Trek II: The Wrath of Khan with Roddenberry taking more of a back seat. A film widely considered to be one of the best trek films. Four more feature films starring the original cast were made.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>However in 1987 Gene Roddenberry teamed up with Rick Berman and The Next Generation was created with a brand new cast. The series ran for seven seasons set roughly a century after the adventures of Kirk and Spock.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Popularity of Star Trek soured and this led Rick Berman to help create the spin off series Deep Space 9, Voyager and lastly Enterprise along with four feature films continuing the adventures of the TNG cast. When Enterprise was cancelled in 2005, Star Trek appeared to be dead after 18 years on TV.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>However in 2009 movie creator JJ Abrams recast the classic crew for the big screen. The film was big on action, but took place in an alternative timeline allowing for familiar characters to have new adventures without interfering with events depicted in the TV shows.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Two sequels to this film have been produced and are bringing Star Trek back into popularity. This has given rise to Discovery. Star Trek is returning to the TV screen and it is going to be great.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img class="img-fluid" alt="Discovery" src="https://storageaccountblog9f5d.blob.core.windows.net/blazor/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/gqojtfz1dhmxoiri7g8p.png?resize=662%2C372&amp;amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy"
/>
&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Star Trek is back (in 2017)</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/star-trek-is-back-in-2017/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Nov 2015 20:00:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/star-trek-is-back-in-2017/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img class="img-fluid" alt="3f448330857e4ca7ba40ab5465a3c2cb62cdb98c" src="https://storageaccountblog9f5d.blob.core.windows.net/blazor/wp-content/uploads/2015/11/3f448330857e4ca7ba40ab5465a3c2cb62cdb98c.png?resize=620%2C260" loading="lazy"
/>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As you have probably heard Star Trek is coming back to TV. I recently joined with the Sci Fi Waffle podcast to discuss.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sci Fi Waffle: Episode 12 – STAR TREK IS BACK!!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In this episode we discuss the great news that Star Trek IS BACK!!.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Shawn and I are joined again by James Roberts and TrekMates News feed Editor Simon Foster to speculate about the announcement of a new Star Trek TV series due to debut in January 2017.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>James can be found on our sister podcast &lt;a href="http://www.trekmate.org.uk/category/the-battle-bridge/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">The Battle Bridge&lt;/a>
and Simon can be found on Twitter &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/funkysi1701" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">@funkysi1701&lt;/a>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To listen go &lt;a href="http://www.trekmate.org.uk/sci-fi-waffle-episode-11-star-trek-is-back/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">http://www.trekmate.org.uk/sci-fi-waffle-episode-11-star-trek-is-back/&lt;/a>
, to leave feedback go &lt;a href="http://forum.trekmatefamily.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">http://forum.trekmatefamily.com/&lt;/a>
&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>