<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>StarTrek on Funky Si's Blog</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/tags/startrek/</link><description>Recent content in StarTrek on Funky Si's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 18 Mar 2022 18:00:45 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.funkysi1701.com/tags/startrek/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Temporal Trek Podcast</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2022/temporal-trek-podcast/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Mar 2022 18:00:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2022/temporal-trek-podcast/</guid><description>&lt;p>Earlier this year I was a guest on the Temporal Trek Podcast.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet">&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr">Your Inquiry is recognised.&lt;br>Here is this weeks episode of The Temporal Trek.&lt;br>“Dead Stop” part 2 of the unofficial Battle Damage two parter.&lt;br>&lt;br>Special Guest &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/funkysi1701?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@funkysi1701&lt;/a> who was paid with three containers of warp plasma. Bargain!&lt;a href="https://t.co/up4zAKOpZy">https://t.co/up4zAKOpZy&lt;/a> &lt;a href="https://t.co/0EUTAWmqgl">pic.twitter.com/0EUTAWmqgl&lt;/a>&lt;/p>&amp;mdash; The Temporal Trek Podcast(s) (@rider_coattail) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/rider_coattail/status/1504830089002897414?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">March 18, 2022&lt;/a>&lt;/blockquote> &lt;script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8">&lt;/script>
&lt;p>Here is the episode I recorded:
&lt;a href="https://podcasts.apple.com/gb/podcast/the-temporal-trek-podcast-season-3-episode-30-dead/id1499160640?i=1000554428633" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Temporal Trek Podcast Season 3 episode 30 Dead Stop&lt;/a>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This week &amp;ldquo;Dan Dan&amp;rdquo; are joined by long time friend of the show, formerly from The Ten Forward Podcast, Simon Foster.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We discuss whether this is&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>A part two of a two-parter, last of a four parter or a previosuly unseen part 5 to the Tessek Prime Quintology?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Rogue full-AI or just a really super advanced computer?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Station seen again in Voyager?&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Oh and by the way has anyone seen the guy who flies the ship, you know the one, tall bloke, loves a good prank, Space Boomer, answers to &amp;lsquo;Travis&amp;rsquo;?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img class="img-fluid" alt="Temporal Trek Podcast" src="https://www.funkysi1701.com/images/podcast.jpg" loading="lazy"
width="268" height="268"
/>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It was great fun to record and I hope you enjoy giving it a listen.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="">View on DevTo&lt;/a>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="">View on Hashnode&lt;/a>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>A Comparison of All Good Things... and Star Trek Picard</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2021/a-comparison-of-all-good-things-and-star-trek-picard/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Dec 2021 20:00:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2021/a-comparison-of-all-good-things-and-star-trek-picard/</guid><description>&lt;p>The final episode of Star Trek: The Next Generation features a few scenes set 25 years into the future. That episode aired May 1994. The newest Star Trek TV show Star Trek Picard has just aired its first episode and this is 25 years and 8 months after that episode. This article may contain minor spoilers for the first episode of Star Trek Picard, you have been warned.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I thought it would be interesting to compare the two time periods.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="fate-of-picards-crew">Fate of Picards crew&lt;a class="anchor ms-1" href="#fate-of-picards-crew">&lt;i class="fas fa-link">&lt;/i>&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In All Good Things&amp;hellip; all of Picards crew are still alive except one. Deanna Troi passed away but it is never revealed how.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In Star Trek Picard, we know Data has died as featured in the feature file Star Trek Nemesis. From the trailers we know Riker and Troi are still alive. We do not know the fate of Crusher, LaForge and Worf yet, but I am going to assume they are still alive somewhere.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In both timelines we have one dead crew member.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="living-arrangements">Living arrangements&lt;a class="anchor ms-1" href="#living-arrangements">&lt;i class="fas fa-link">&lt;/i>&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In both time lines Picard is living in France at his vineyard.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In All Good Things&amp;hellip; we do not know who Picard is living with, it is assumed he lives alone, which is why Geordi feels the need to check on him, once he learns about his Irumodic Syndrome.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In Star Trek Picard we learn that Picard is living with a Romulan couple, due to the involvement Picard made to save the Romulan people when their star went supernova. Picard appears older but for the most part in good health, he can&amp;rsquo;t for example run up a flight of stairs (he is 92 so not surprising really!) and is plagued by dreams from his past.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="romulan-neutral-zone">Romulan Neutral Zone&lt;a class="anchor ms-1" href="#romulan-neutral-zone">&lt;i class="fas fa-link">&lt;/i>&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In All Good Things&amp;hellip; there is no Neutral Zone, the Romulan empire has been taken over by the Klingons.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In Star Trek Picard one would assume there is no Neutral Zone as well because the Romulan star system was destroyed. A handful of Romulans survived mostly due to the actions of Picard.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="looks">Looks&lt;a class="anchor ms-1" href="#looks">&lt;i class="fas fa-link">&lt;/i>&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>As we have seen Patrick Stewart does not appear to be ageing. Below is a comparison of how he looks in the two time frames.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img class="img-fluid" alt="All Good Things.." src="https://storageaccountblog9f5d.blob.core.windows.net/blazor/wp-content/uploads/2018/08/all-good-things.jpg?w=584&amp;amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy"
/>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img class="img-fluid" alt="Star Trek Picard" src="https://storageaccountblog9f5d.blob.core.windows.net/blazor/wp-content/uploads/2022/picard.jpeg" loading="lazy"
/>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I really enjoyed the first episode of Star Trek Picard and it is going to be interesting seeing what other similarities and differences there are between it and All Good Things&amp;hellip;&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Picard is back!</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2019/picard-is-back/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2019 20:00:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2019/picard-is-back/</guid><description>&lt;p>It has just been announced at the annual Star Trek Las Vegas (&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/STLV" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">#STLV&lt;/a>
) convention that Patrick Stewart is going to return to his role as Jean-Luc Picard in a new TV Show.&lt;/p>
&lt;iframe type="text/html" width="662" height="373" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/aCKQp1sGVRQ?version=3&amp;amp;rel=1&amp;amp;fs=1&amp;amp;autohide=2&amp;amp;showsearch=0&amp;amp;showinfo=1&amp;amp;iv_load_policy=1&amp;amp;wmode=transparent" allowfullscreen="true" style="border:0;">&lt;/iframe>
&lt;p>Few other details have been announced other than the TV show will take place 20 years after the film Star Trek: Nemesis and will feature the character of Jean-Luc Picard.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Lets run though a few things I would like to see from this new show.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="low-on-action">Low on Action&lt;a class="anchor ms-1" href="#low-on-action">&lt;i class="fas fa-link">&lt;/i>&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Star Trek: Discovery is a great show and has brought Star Trek back to our TV shows. However it is an action show, it zooms along so fast and with so much action I would appreciate a show that can takes its time a bit more.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I want a show that can show Picard carefully considering some moral issue and making a decision. Something we were used to seeing on TNG.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="feature-picards-excellent-speeches">Feature Picard’s excellent speeches&lt;a class="anchor ms-1" href="#feature-picards-excellent-speeches">&lt;i class="fas fa-link">&lt;/i>&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>One of the best features I can think of Jean-Luc Picard is his ability to make speeches about one issue or other.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Lets look at a few examples:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Insurection&lt;/strong> : Picard speaks about the forced relocation of a group of people.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>How many people does it take, Admiral, before it becomes wrong? Hmm? A thousand, fifty thousand, a million? How many people does it take, Admiral?&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>First&lt;/strong> &lt;strong>Contact&lt;/strong> : Picard is hell bent on revenge for what the Borg have done to him and refuses to destroy the Enterprise to save his crew.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>“I will not sacrifice the Enterprise. We’ve made too many compromises already. Too many retreats. They invade our space and we fall back. They assimilate entire worlds, and we fall back. Not again! The line must be drawn here, …this far, no further! And I will make them pay for what they’ve done.”&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Measure of a Man&lt;/strong> : Picard argues for the rights of Data.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>“You see, he’s met two of your three criteria for sentience, so what if he meets the third. Consciousness in even the smallest degree. What is he then? I don’t know. Do you? (to Riker) Do you? (to Phillipa) Do you? Well, that’s the question you have to answer. Your Honour, the courtroom is a crucible. In it we burn away irrelevancies until we are left with a pure product, the truth for all time. Now, sooner or later, this man or others like him will succeed in replicating Commander Data. And the decision you reach here today will determine how we will regard this creation of our genius. It will reveal the kind of a people we are, what he is destined to be. It will reach far beyond this courtroom and this one android. It could significantly redefine the boundaries of personal liberty and freedom, expanding them for some, savagely curtailing them for others. Are you prepared to condemn him and all who come after him to servitude and slavery? Your Honour, Starfleet was founded to seek out new life. Well, there it sits. Waiting. You wanted a chance to make law. Well, here it is. Make a good one.”&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h2 id="ask-important-questions">Ask important questions&lt;a class="anchor ms-1" href="#ask-important-questions">&lt;i class="fas fa-link">&lt;/i>&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>We live in uncertain times. There are lots of pressures on today’s world and we need to acknowledge these. Picard is an excellent character to use to ask important questions of the day.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What does it mean to be human?&lt;br>
How should we treat people that are different to us?&lt;br>
How should we react to extremism?&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="deal-with-his-age">Deal with his age&lt;a class="anchor ms-1" href="#deal-with-his-age">&lt;i class="fas fa-link">&lt;/i>&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In the last episode of TNG a future version of Picard is shown 25 years into the future. This is a similar time period so it will be interesting to compare the two. Have Picard look back on his life and ask questions about his life choices.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img class="img-fluid" alt="Picard" src="https://storageaccountblog9f5d.blob.core.windows.net/blazor/wp-content/uploads/2018/08/all-good-things.jpg?w=662&amp;amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy"
/>
&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="be-consistent-with-his-past">Be consistent with his past&lt;a class="anchor ms-1" href="#be-consistent-with-his-past">&lt;i class="fas fa-link">&lt;/i>&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Picard is a well known character. So writers please don’t change him. I want a character we know, not a character that looks like Picard but acts in a way contrary to what we would expect.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Picard has a history we know, he served on the stargazer and of course the Enterprise, he has an artificial heart, he was assimiliated by the Borg. All&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="reference-50-years-of-star-trek">Reference 50 years of Star Trek&lt;a class="anchor ms-1" href="#reference-50-years-of-star-trek">&lt;i class="fas fa-link">&lt;/i>&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Discovery and Enterprise are TV shows which have a problem. There is Trek going on after them which imposes a few rules on what can and can’t be done.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is a TV Show that will take place after every other Trek TV and Film and can do whatever the creators want. This gives freedom, but it also gives the responsibility to reference what has gone before.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img class="img-fluid" alt="Picard" src="https://storageaccountblog9f5d.blob.core.windows.net/blazor/wp-content/uploads/2018/08/download.jpg?w=662&amp;amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy"
/>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The 2009 Star Trek film features the destruction of Romulus and Spock travelling back in time. How about Picard dealing with surviving Romulans helping rebuild their society, continuing the work that Spock started in the TNG episode Unification.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I look forward to finding out what the Star Trek production team has in store for us. If they have Patrick Stewart convinced I am sure it is going to be good.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Discovery – My thoughts so far</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2017/discovery-my-thoughts-so-far/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Oct 2017 20:00:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2017/discovery-my-thoughts-so-far/</guid><description>&lt;p>I tried to resist but I am going to have to write about the new Star Trek series Discovery. Warning this post is going to include SPOILERS. If you read on you have been warned.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I watched the first two episodes of the brand new Star Trek TV show. As I am an international viewer I used Netflix, if you are from the US you need to use CBS All Access. &lt;img class="img-fluid" alt="" src="https://storageaccountblog9f5d.blob.core.windows.net/blazor/wp-content/uploads/2017/05/DAD0hTKUAAAUkTP.jpg?resize=662%2C366&amp;amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy"
/>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I have heard a lot of complaining that the show is not free to watch. CBS is making Star Trek Discovery to make money, if they don’t make money they will stop making it. Its as simple as that.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.netflix.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Netflix&lt;/a>
costs £5.99 per month and &lt;a href="https://www.cbs.com/all-access/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">CBS All Access&lt;/a>
costs $5.99 per month. I don’t believe this is a lot of money. The 5.99 above allows you to watch any of the 726 Star Trek episodes at any time of day whenever you want as many times as you want, plus you have access to all the other movies or TV shows available. I don’t think this is too much to ask.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Back to Discovery. I loved it! It felt like Star Trek. I had feared it might only share the name and would be an action filled TV show that had little in common with what he had seen before. I was wrong this is definitely a show that can proudly call itself Star Trek.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>The Klingons&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When it was first announced that the Klingons would feature in the new show I was a bit “meh”. We had done lots with the Klingons before and they had never been my favourite alien race. &lt;img class="img-fluid" alt="" src="https://storageaccountblog9f5d.blob.core.windows.net/blazor/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/star-trek-discovery-klingons-1002567-1280x0.jpg?resize=300%2C165&amp;amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy"
/>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The look of the Klingons was also going to be changed, I have to admit this didn’t bother me. Klingons have had their look updated before. In 1966 Klingons had dark faces and smooth foreheads, in 1979 the forehead ridges were added as the first Star Trek movie was made, and now Discovery has removed all hair from Klingons. I can explain it away as productional changes, I don’t need an on screen explanation like we had on Enterprise (or even DS9).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What I have seen so far is a menacing alien race that fits with what we have seen before with lots of references to honor, Kahless and speaking Klingon. I must admit reading all the subtitles is getting a bit tiresome, but that is a minor issue.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Conflict&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Historically Star Trek has not featured conflict between the main starfleet characters due to the idea that humanity has evolved beyond this. DS9 got round this by having Odo and Kira who are not starfleet characters so can have a little bit of conflict. Discovery has completely abandoned this idea.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In the pilot episode, the Michael Burnham commits mutiny on her captain, even attacking her with a vulcan nerve pinch. In the third episode we finally meet the discovery crew. Gone are the TNG days where the ships crew are like a family, I am not sure I can think of a single character that would call another character “friend”. We are in a time of war so this would be expected, however I do hope we see deepening friendships form between characters.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I am OK with the change to feature more conflict. I must admit the darkness of the third episode, did stop to make me think a bit, however by the fourth episode I was won over.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Cast&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The story is concentrated around Michael Burnham, so I do worry that other characters won’t get a look in. However from what I have seen Michael Burnham is a great character. She is a strong female character, with a intriguing back story relating to Sarek and possibly also Spock.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Saru the alien character on the show, played by the very tall Doug Jones is great. From the trailers he was all about sensing death, but there is far more to him than that. I am looking forward to learn more about him and his threat ganglia.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As the show has gone on we have started to learn about the other characters like Captain Lorca, Tilly and Paul Stamets.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Title Sequence&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I don’t like the opening title sequence, it feels very cheap like a draft version which hasn’t been finished yet. I was looking forward to a title sequence that would show off the USS Discovery, maybe like TNG where it warps around our own solar system. What we see is some of the tech that features in Star Trek which is nice but I want more. The theme tune while great that it features parts from the classic theme doesn’t stand on its own. I can hum all the other TV shows themes, and now after 4 episodes would struggle to do that.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>However I expect that after a while I will grow to like this more.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Overall&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I like Discovery and I will keep watching it. I want to find out what happens to the characters. There are no annoying characters like other shows have had. There is character development, none of the characters are going to finish where they started. I want more friendship between characters, but I expect that will come, I want more exploring and doing Star Trek stuff, but most of all I want more episodes, roll on next weeks show.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Other things I noticed&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Sound effects on the bridge are awesome, it makes me feel at home&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The USS Discovery doesn’t feature in the first two episodes despite being the title of the show.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Others have noted that Captain Georgiou has books on her shelf which feature classic episode titles&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Star Trek is back with Discovery</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2017/star-trek-is-back-with-discovery/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Sep 2017 20:00:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2017/star-trek-is-back-with-discovery/</guid><description>&lt;p>In &lt;a href="https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/star-trek-is-back-in-2017">November 2015&lt;/a>
it was announced that a new Star Trek series was going to be launched. It has been a long wait with multiple delays but Star Trek Discovery is finally here.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Star Trek Discovery launches in the US on 24th September and in the UK on 25th September.&lt;/p>
&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/UoV3kc05Nwc?rel=0" width="560" height="315" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen">&lt;/iframe>
&lt;p>Lets have a look back how we got here.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Star Trek was created by Gene Roddenberry in the 1960s. He imagined a show where we would explore the galaxy while also exploring the human condition. He described it as a wagon train to the stars. However it was cancelled after 79 episodes and three seasons due to budget cuts and low viewers.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After cancellation its popularity boomed in reruns. In the mid 1970s an animated series was created. But demand for Star Trek continued until a new Star Trek show was commissioned called Phase Two.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In 1977 Star Wars came out, and the phase two idea was cancelled and turned into a movie. In 1979 we got Star Trek The Motion Picture. It went massively over budget and failed to really capture the Star Trek spirit.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A much cheaper sequel was created in 1982 Star Trek II: The Wrath of Khan with Roddenberry taking more of a back seat. A film widely considered to be one of the best trek films. Four more feature films starring the original cast were made.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>However in 1987 Gene Roddenberry teamed up with Rick Berman and The Next Generation was created with a brand new cast. The series ran for seven seasons set roughly a century after the adventures of Kirk and Spock.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Popularity of Star Trek soured and this led Rick Berman to help create the spin off series Deep Space 9, Voyager and lastly Enterprise along with four feature films continuing the adventures of the TNG cast. When Enterprise was cancelled in 2005, Star Trek appeared to be dead after 18 years on TV.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>However in 2009 movie creator JJ Abrams recast the classic crew for the big screen. The film was big on action, but took place in an alternative timeline allowing for familiar characters to have new adventures without interfering with events depicted in the TV shows.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Two sequels to this film have been produced and are bringing Star Trek back into popularity. This has given rise to Discovery. Star Trek is returning to the TV screen and it is going to be great.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img class="img-fluid" alt="Discovery" src="https://storageaccountblog9f5d.blob.core.windows.net/blazor/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/gqojtfz1dhmxoiri7g8p.png?resize=662%2C372&amp;amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy"
/>
&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Star Trek is back (in 2017)</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2015/star-trek-is-back-in-2017/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Nov 2015 20:00:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2015/star-trek-is-back-in-2017/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img class="img-fluid" alt="3f448330857e4ca7ba40ab5465a3c2cb62cdb98c" src="https://storageaccountblog9f5d.blob.core.windows.net/blazor/wp-content/uploads/2015/11/3f448330857e4ca7ba40ab5465a3c2cb62cdb98c.png?resize=620%2C260" loading="lazy"
/>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As you have probably heard Star Trek is coming back to TV. I recently joined with the Sci Fi Waffle podcast to discuss.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sci Fi Waffle: Episode 12 – STAR TREK IS BACK!!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In this episode we discuss the great news that Star Trek IS BACK!!.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Shawn and I are joined again by James Roberts and TrekMates News feed Editor Simon Foster to speculate about the announcement of a new Star Trek TV series due to debut in January 2017.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>James can be found on our sister podcast &lt;a href="http://www.trekmate.org.uk/category/the-battle-bridge/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">The Battle Bridge&lt;/a>
and Simon can be found on Twitter &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/funkysi1701" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">@funkysi1701&lt;/a>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To listen go &lt;a href="http://www.trekmate.org.uk/sci-fi-waffle-episode-11-star-trek-is-back/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">http://www.trekmate.org.uk/sci-fi-waffle-episode-11-star-trek-is-back/&lt;/a>
, to leave feedback go &lt;a href="http://forum.trekmatefamily.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">http://forum.trekmatefamily.com/&lt;/a>
&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>To boldly go where no SQL has gone before Part 2</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2014/to-boldly-go-where-no-sql-has-gone-before-part-2/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2014 20:00:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2014/to-boldly-go-where-no-sql-has-gone-before-part-2/</guid><description>&lt;p>Let’s continue looking at a database schema for storing details of every Star Trek Episode. If you are new to databases, a schema is just the design of the structure of the database.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We have three tables, Episode, EpisodeWriter and Writer. See my last post for more details of these. It has been suggested that a slight change to this structure would enable storage of more of the creative staff.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Lets rename Writer and call it Credit, and rename EpisodeWriter and call it EpisodeCredit. Now any creative staff member involved in an episode can be stored in the Credit table. Lets alter EpisodeCredit and add an extra column called CreditType. CreditType is just a text field that stores the role that creative person had on that episode, it can be anything from Director, Writer, Actor, Science Consultant etc.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In case anyone wants to recreate the databases I have described here, I have saved the SQL on a separate page which can be found here.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We now have the ability to store information relating to the episode in the episode table and any creative people in the credit table. What else can we add to the database? How about a table that can be used to record when an episode was last watched. I am probably weird but sometimes I want to watch a Star Trek episode that I like but I haven’t watched in ages.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The last watched table is really simple and just have a datetime field and episodeId. This can be further expanded to have a userId field if you wanted to keep track of what episodes your friends had been watching.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Another idea could be to tag episodes with certain themes or topics like Klingon episodes or meaning of life episodes or Kirk talks a computer to death episodes. Again this is fairly simple table containing TagName and EpisodeId.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>To boldly go where no SQL has gone before</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2014/to-boldly-go-where-no-sql-has-gone-before/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2014 20:00:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2014/to-boldly-go-where-no-sql-has-gone-before/</guid><description>&lt;p>My last post proved quite popular so I am wondering if I can combine a post about IT and Star Trek.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Years ago I used to have lists of Star Trek episodes, which included such information like original air date, production number, episode title and brief description.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>One thing that was hard to keep track of was how many episodes were written by a specific person. This is because episodes are written by multiple people. A column called writer would then need to contain multiple people, another option would be to have columns called writer1, writer2 etc. This wouldn’t help either as you wouldn’t know which column a specific writer had been saved in.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img class="img-fluid" alt="" src="https://storageaccountblog9f5d.blob.core.windows.net/blazor/wp-content/uploads/2014/10/manytomany.jpg?w=559&amp;amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy"
/>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The relationship between writer and episode is known as a many to many relationship. An episode can have many writers and a writer can have written many episodes. To achieve this structure in a SQL database you will need three database tables as it is not possible to create a many to many join between two tables. The first table will contain all the episodes, the second table will contain all the writers, the third table known as a junction table, will contain the relationship between the two.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Let’s do an example so we can see how this would work. Gene Roddenberry creator of Star Trek wrote the pilot episode ‘The Cage’. So Gene would be added to the writers table with an id of 1 and The Cage would be added to the episode table with an id of 1. In the junction table, it has two columns episode and writer, so we would enter 1 and 1 into these columns.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;">&lt;code class="language-sql" data-lang="sql">&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>&lt;span style="color:#66d9ef">Select&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#f92672">*&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#66d9ef">from&lt;/span> Episode e
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>&lt;span style="color:#66d9ef">Join&lt;/span> EpisodeWriter ew &lt;span style="color:#66d9ef">on&lt;/span> e.id &lt;span style="color:#f92672">=&lt;/span> ew.EpisodeId
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>&lt;span style="color:#66d9ef">Join&lt;/span> Writer w &lt;span style="color:#66d9ef">on&lt;/span> w.id &lt;span style="color:#f92672">=&lt;/span> ew.WriterId
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>&lt;p>But if Gene Coon and Gene Roddenberry had writing credits on The Cage we would need to add Gene Coon to the writing table and add an extra entry to the episodewriter table.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I am going to do more posts based on this as I expand the database structure to include other information, I may go on to create stored procedures for bringing back certain information or I may use this as an example to talk about coding a user interface.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Destination Star Trek</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2014/destination-star-trek/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2014 20:00:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2014/destination-star-trek/</guid><description>&lt;p>As a break from my usual topics I am going to talk about what I did over the weekend.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img class="img-fluid" alt="" src="https://storageaccountblog9f5d.blob.core.windows.net/blazor/wp-content/uploads/2014/10/10670061_10152884492389155_77781042960777157_n.jpg" loading="lazy"
/>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I am a huge star trek fan, so me and my wife Laura went to Destination Star Trek, a convention held in London. This is a picture of us in costume, my wife created a tribble costume (A tribble is an alien race that just consists of a ball of fur) and I am wearing an original series captains uniform. We had a great time.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There are several things that made this trip special.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Friends&lt;/strong>: After the last convention I remember thinking how much better the convention would be with a group of friends. Shortly afterwards I started listening to the trekmate podcast, eventually this lead to me helping out with their website and making friends via twitter with many of the hosts. This weekend was the first time I met up with them and it was great to put faces to names (or twitter names)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Writers and Directors&lt;/strong>: Star Trek has a great philosophy. In the future human beings will put their differences aside and work together to explore the galaxy, this is one reason why Star Trek is so popular even after almost 50 years. This philosophy has been created by the writers and other creative staff over the years. My favourite Star Trek film is Wrath of Khan which was directed by Nicholas Meyer, this weekend I got my DVD signed by him and was able to tell him how I still enjoyed that film over 30 years after it was made. He said that he really appreciated me saying that. Listening to his talk later on, it was fascinating to hear his insights into making my favourite film. It is the writers and directors that make our favourite characters who they are, the actors themselves aren’t allowed to ad lib, all they do is flesh them out with a bit of emotion or a mannerism, it is the writer that create our favourite lines or situations that we remember.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Seven of Nine&lt;/strong>: During my teenage years I had lots of posters of Seven on my walls. Seven of Nine was the ex-borg that walked around the ship in a skin tight catsuit, but she was also highly intelligent and continued to explore what it was to be human. It was great to have my photo taken with her, even if it was rushed due to the large number of people that wanted their picture taken.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Trivia&lt;/strong>: On the Friday of the convention, Laura took part in the beginners trivia challenge, she won. On Saturday I took part in the intermediate trivia challenge, I did really badly only got 3 correct, On Sunday I took part in the captain level challenge and I won. I really wasn’t expecting that, after I did so badly the day before. Thanks Marc Stamper and Destination Star Trek for organising that it was great fun, and also fun to meet the other trekkies who I had been competing against via twitter.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Party!&lt;/strong>: On Saturday night we went to a party, we had Romulan Ale to drink, we had some of the actors performing songs (James Darren was particularly good), and some of the actors mingled with fans, it was great to see the actors relaxing and if you were lucky you could chat to them, I asked Vaughn Armstrong how he was enjoying the music, he loved it.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>This is just a taste of what I got up to, there was lots more, like seeing alien costumes, listening to talks, sitting on a mockup of the bridge. Only one way to end this post, &lt;strong>Live Long and Prosper!&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>