<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>StarTrek on Funky Si's Blog</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/tags/startrek/</link><description>Recent content in StarTrek on Funky Si's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 18 Mar 2022 18:00:45 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.funkysi1701.com/tags/startrek/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Temporal Trek Podcast</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2022/temporal-trek-podcast/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Mar 2022 18:00:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2022/temporal-trek-podcast/</guid><description>&lt;p>Earlier this year I was a guest on the Temporal Trek Podcast.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet">&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr">Your Inquiry is recognised.&lt;br>Here is this weeks episode of The Temporal Trek.&lt;br>“Dead Stop” part 2 of the unofficial Battle Damage two parter.&lt;br>&lt;br>Special Guest &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/funkysi1701?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@funkysi1701&lt;/a> who was paid with three containers of warp plasma. Bargain!&lt;a href="https://t.co/up4zAKOpZy">https://t.co/up4zAKOpZy&lt;/a> &lt;a href="https://t.co/0EUTAWmqgl">pic.twitter.com/0EUTAWmqgl&lt;/a>&lt;/p>&amp;mdash; The Temporal Trek Podcast(s) (@rider_coattail) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/rider_coattail/status/1504830089002897414?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">March 18, 2022&lt;/a>&lt;/blockquote> &lt;script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8">&lt;/script>
&lt;p>Here is the episode I recorded:
&lt;a href="https://podcasts.apple.com/gb/podcast/the-temporal-trek-podcast-season-3-episode-30-dead/id1499160640?i=1000554428633" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Temporal Trek Podcast Season 3 episode 30 Dead Stop&lt;/a>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This week &amp;ldquo;Dan Dan&amp;rdquo; are joined by long time friend of the show, formerly from The Ten Forward Podcast, Simon Foster.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We discuss whether this is&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>A part two of a two-parter, last of a four parter or a previosuly unseen part 5 to the Tessek Prime Quintology?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Rogue full-AI or just a really super advanced computer?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Station seen again in Voyager?&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Oh and by the way has anyone seen the guy who flies the ship, you know the one, tall bloke, loves a good prank, Space Boomer, answers to &amp;lsquo;Travis&amp;rsquo;?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img class="img-fluid" alt="Temporal Trek Podcast" src="https://www.funkysi1701.com/images/podcast.jpg" loading="lazy"
width="268" height="268"
/>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It was great fun to record and I hope you enjoy giving it a listen.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>A Comparison of All Good Things... and Star Trek Picard</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2021/a-comparison-of-all-good-things-and-star-trek-picard/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Dec 2021 20:00:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2021/a-comparison-of-all-good-things-and-star-trek-picard/</guid><description>&lt;p>The final episode of Star Trek: The Next Generation features a few scenes set 25 years into the future. That episode aired May 1994. The newest Star Trek TV show Star Trek Picard has just aired its first episode and this is 25 years and 8 months after that episode. This article may contain minor spoilers for the first episode of Star Trek Picard, you have been warned.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I thought it would be interesting to compare the two time periods.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="fate-of-picards-crew">Fate of Picards crew&lt;a class="anchor ms-1" href="#fate-of-picards-crew">&lt;i class="fas fa-link">&lt;/i>&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In All Good Things&amp;hellip; all of Picards crew are still alive except one. Deanna Troi passed away but it is never revealed how.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In Star Trek Picard, we know Data has died as featured in the feature file Star Trek Nemesis. From the trailers we know Riker and Troi are still alive. We do not know the fate of Crusher, LaForge and Worf yet, but I am going to assume they are still alive somewhere.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In both timelines we have one dead crew member.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="living-arrangements">Living arrangements&lt;a class="anchor ms-1" href="#living-arrangements">&lt;i class="fas fa-link">&lt;/i>&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In both time lines Picard is living in France at his vineyard.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In All Good Things&amp;hellip; we do not know who Picard is living with, it is assumed he lives alone, which is why Geordi feels the need to check on him, once he learns about his Irumodic Syndrome.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In Star Trek Picard we learn that Picard is living with a Romulan couple, due to the involvement Picard made to save the Romulan people when their star went supernova. Picard appears older but for the most part in good health, he can&amp;rsquo;t for example run up a flight of stairs (he is 92 so not surprising really!) and is plagued by dreams from his past.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="romulan-neutral-zone">Romulan Neutral Zone&lt;a class="anchor ms-1" href="#romulan-neutral-zone">&lt;i class="fas fa-link">&lt;/i>&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In All Good Things&amp;hellip; there is no Neutral Zone, the Romulan empire has been taken over by the Klingons.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In Star Trek Picard one would assume there is no Neutral Zone as well because the Romulan star system was destroyed. A handful of Romulans survived mostly due to the actions of Picard.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="looks">Looks&lt;a class="anchor ms-1" href="#looks">&lt;i class="fas fa-link">&lt;/i>&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>As we have seen Patrick Stewart does not appear to be ageing. Below is a comparison of how he looks in the two time frames.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img class="img-fluid" alt="All Good Things.." src="https://storageaccountblog9f5d.blob.core.windows.net/blazor/wp-content/uploads/2018/08/all-good-things.jpg?w=584&amp;amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy"
/>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img class="img-fluid" alt="Star Trek Picard" src="https://storageaccountblog9f5d.blob.core.windows.net/blazor/wp-content/uploads/2022/picard.jpeg" loading="lazy"
/>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I really enjoyed the first episode of Star Trek Picard and it is going to be interesting seeing what other similarities and differences there are between it and All Good Things&amp;hellip;&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Picard is back!</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2019/picard-is-back/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2019 20:00:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2019/picard-is-back/</guid><description>&lt;p>It has just been announced at the annual Star Trek Las Vegas (&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/STLV" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">#STLV&lt;/a>
) convention that Patrick Stewart is going to return to his role as Jean-Luc Picard in a new TV Show.&lt;/p>
&lt;iframe type="text/html" width="662" height="373" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/aCKQp1sGVRQ?version=3&amp;amp;rel=1&amp;amp;fs=1&amp;amp;autohide=2&amp;amp;showsearch=0&amp;amp;showinfo=1&amp;amp;iv_load_policy=1&amp;amp;wmode=transparent" allowfullscreen="true" style="border:0;">&lt;/iframe>
&lt;p>Few other details have been announced other than the TV show will take place 20 years after the film Star Trek: Nemesis and will feature the character of Jean-Luc Picard.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Lets run though a few things I would like to see from this new show.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="low-on-action">Low on Action&lt;a class="anchor ms-1" href="#low-on-action">&lt;i class="fas fa-link">&lt;/i>&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Star Trek: Discovery is a great show and has brought Star Trek back to our TV shows. However it is an action show, it zooms along so fast and with so much action I would appreciate a show that can takes its time a bit more.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I want a show that can show Picard carefully considering some moral issue and making a decision. Something we were used to seeing on TNG.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="feature-picards-excellent-speeches">Feature Picard’s excellent speeches&lt;a class="anchor ms-1" href="#feature-picards-excellent-speeches">&lt;i class="fas fa-link">&lt;/i>&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>One of the best features I can think of Jean-Luc Picard is his ability to make speeches about one issue or other.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Lets look at a few examples:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Insurection&lt;/strong> : Picard speaks about the forced relocation of a group of people.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>How many people does it take, Admiral, before it becomes wrong? Hmm? A thousand, fifty thousand, a million? How many people does it take, Admiral?&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>First&lt;/strong> &lt;strong>Contact&lt;/strong> : Picard is hell bent on revenge for what the Borg have done to him and refuses to destroy the Enterprise to save his crew.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>“I will not sacrifice the Enterprise. We’ve made too many compromises already. Too many retreats. They invade our space and we fall back. They assimilate entire worlds, and we fall back. Not again! The line must be drawn here, …this far, no further! And I will make them pay for what they’ve done.”&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Measure of a Man&lt;/strong> : Picard argues for the rights of Data.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>“You see, he’s met two of your three criteria for sentience, so what if he meets the third. Consciousness in even the smallest degree. What is he then? I don’t know. Do you? (to Riker) Do you? (to Phillipa) Do you? Well, that’s the question you have to answer. Your Honour, the courtroom is a crucible. In it we burn away irrelevancies until we are left with a pure product, the truth for all time. Now, sooner or later, this man or others like him will succeed in replicating Commander Data. And the decision you reach here today will determine how we will regard this creation of our genius. It will reveal the kind of a people we are, what he is destined to be. It will reach far beyond this courtroom and this one android. It could significantly redefine the boundaries of personal liberty and freedom, expanding them for some, savagely curtailing them for others. Are you prepared to condemn him and all who come after him to servitude and slavery? Your Honour, Starfleet was founded to seek out new life. Well, there it sits. Waiting. You wanted a chance to make law. Well, here it is. Make a good one.”&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h2 id="ask-important-questions">Ask important questions&lt;a class="anchor ms-1" href="#ask-important-questions">&lt;i class="fas fa-link">&lt;/i>&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>We live in uncertain times. There are lots of pressures on today’s world and we need to acknowledge these. Picard is an excellent character to use to ask important questions of the day.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What does it mean to be human?&lt;br>
How should we treat people that are different to us?&lt;br>
How should we react to extremism?&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="deal-with-his-age">Deal with his age&lt;a class="anchor ms-1" href="#deal-with-his-age">&lt;i class="fas fa-link">&lt;/i>&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In the last episode of TNG a future version of Picard is shown 25 years into the future. This is a similar time period so it will be interesting to compare the two. Have Picard look back on his life and ask questions about his life choices.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img class="img-fluid" alt="Picard" src="https://storageaccountblog9f5d.blob.core.windows.net/blazor/wp-content/uploads/2018/08/all-good-things.jpg?w=662&amp;amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy"
/>
&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="be-consistent-with-his-past">Be consistent with his past&lt;a class="anchor ms-1" href="#be-consistent-with-his-past">&lt;i class="fas fa-link">&lt;/i>&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Picard is a well known character. So writers please don’t change him. I want a character we know, not a character that looks like Picard but acts in a way contrary to what we would expect.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Picard has a history we know, he served on the stargazer and of course the Enterprise, he has an artificial heart, he was assimiliated by the Borg. All&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="reference-50-years-of-star-trek">Reference 50 years of Star Trek&lt;a class="anchor ms-1" href="#reference-50-years-of-star-trek">&lt;i class="fas fa-link">&lt;/i>&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Discovery and Enterprise are TV shows which have a problem. There is Trek going on after them which imposes a few rules on what can and can’t be done.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is a TV Show that will take place after every other Trek TV and Film and can do whatever the creators want. This gives freedom, but it also gives the responsibility to reference what has gone before.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img class="img-fluid" alt="Picard" src="https://storageaccountblog9f5d.blob.core.windows.net/blazor/wp-content/uploads/2018/08/download.jpg?w=662&amp;amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy"
/>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The 2009 Star Trek film features the destruction of Romulus and Spock travelling back in time. How about Picard dealing with surviving Romulans helping rebuild their society, continuing the work that Spock started in the TNG episode Unification.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I look forward to finding out what the Star Trek production team has in store for us. If they have Patrick Stewart convinced I am sure it is going to be good.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Looking back at 2017</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2017/looking-back-at-2017/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Dec 2017 20:00:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2017/looking-back-at-2017/</guid><description>&lt;p>As 2017 starts to draw to a close let’s look at some of the highlights from the past year.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img class="img-fluid" alt="Edward" src="https://storageaccountblog9f5d.blob.core.windows.net/blazor/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/DSC_0376-e1510563039193-225x300.jpg?resize=225%2C300&amp;amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy"
/>
&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Edward&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>In November I became a father again and celebrated the arrival of Edward into the world. Before the birth I was worried how well my first son James would adapt to the new arrival but I am happy to say I didn’t need to, he mostly ignores the new arrival.&lt;/p>
&lt;ol start="2">
&lt;li>Star Trek&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>In September the latest Star Trek TV series Discovery arrived on Netflix. I have been very positive so far about the show, I am still positive however there are things that annoy me about the new show, however I am keen to see the next episode each week so they are definitely doing something right.&lt;/p>
&lt;ol start="3">
&lt;li>Office move&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>In May I helped my employer move to brand new &lt;a href="https://funkysi1701.com/office-move" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">offices&lt;/a>
. This was a lot of hard work, but everything went as planned and our new home is great.&lt;/p>
&lt;ol start="4">
&lt;li>Side projects &lt;img class="img-fluid" alt="Google Play" src="https://storageaccountblog9f5d.blob.core.windows.net/blazor/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/googleplay.jpg?resize=300%2C300&amp;amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy"
/>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>I blogged in February about having a side project but it wasn’t until later in the year that this solidified into what I am working on now. It started as a way to understand &lt;a href="https://funkysi1701.com/interfaces" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">interfaces&lt;/a>
this then led to learning Xamarin and creating an android app to help promote this blog. Troy Hunt expanded his HIBP API to include passwords that have been in data breaches, I then started working on &lt;a href="https://funkysi1701.com/pwned-pass--available-from-the-play-store" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">pwned passwords&lt;/a>
which is a simple android frontend for this.&lt;/p>
&lt;ol start="5">
&lt;li>Learning R&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>In Feb I also experimented with a new programming language &lt;a href="https://funkysi1701.com/learning-r" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">R&lt;/a>
. It started with a problem about converting exchange rates and ended with a SQL stored procedure that executed some R code, I still want to learn lots more but it was a good example of the sorts of thing you can build with R.&lt;/p>
&lt;ol start="6">
&lt;li>DNS programmatically&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>One of my most successful blogs was about how you can create &lt;a href="https://dev.to/funkysi1701/creating-dns-records-programmatically-26lp" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">dns&lt;/a>
records within your application eg sites that have yourname.domain in the url. It was a great chance to look at how dns works and learn more about what azure can do to manage this. I want to expand on this and build something.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So that was 2017, for some ideas about what 2018 might have in store for me look out for my next blog post.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Discovery – My thoughts so far</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2017/discovery-my-thoughts-so-far/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Oct 2017 20:00:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2017/discovery-my-thoughts-so-far/</guid><description>&lt;p>I tried to resist but I am going to have to write about the new Star Trek series Discovery. Warning this post is going to include SPOILERS. If you read on you have been warned.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I watched the first two episodes of the brand new Star Trek TV show. As I am an international viewer I used Netflix, if you are from the US you need to use CBS All Access. &lt;img class="img-fluid" alt="" src="https://storageaccountblog9f5d.blob.core.windows.net/blazor/wp-content/uploads/2017/05/DAD0hTKUAAAUkTP.jpg?resize=662%2C366&amp;amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy"
/>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I have heard a lot of complaining that the show is not free to watch. CBS is making Star Trek Discovery to make money, if they don’t make money they will stop making it. Its as simple as that.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.netflix.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Netflix&lt;/a>
costs £5.99 per month and &lt;a href="https://www.cbs.com/all-access/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">CBS All Access&lt;/a>
costs $5.99 per month. I don’t believe this is a lot of money. The 5.99 above allows you to watch any of the 726 Star Trek episodes at any time of day whenever you want as many times as you want, plus you have access to all the other movies or TV shows available. I don’t think this is too much to ask.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Back to Discovery. I loved it! It felt like Star Trek. I had feared it might only share the name and would be an action filled TV show that had little in common with what he had seen before. I was wrong this is definitely a show that can proudly call itself Star Trek.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>The Klingons&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When it was first announced that the Klingons would feature in the new show I was a bit “meh”. We had done lots with the Klingons before and they had never been my favourite alien race. &lt;img class="img-fluid" alt="" src="https://storageaccountblog9f5d.blob.core.windows.net/blazor/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/star-trek-discovery-klingons-1002567-1280x0.jpg?resize=300%2C165&amp;amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy"
/>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The look of the Klingons was also going to be changed, I have to admit this didn’t bother me. Klingons have had their look updated before. In 1966 Klingons had dark faces and smooth foreheads, in 1979 the forehead ridges were added as the first Star Trek movie was made, and now Discovery has removed all hair from Klingons. I can explain it away as productional changes, I don’t need an on screen explanation like we had on Enterprise (or even DS9).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What I have seen so far is a menacing alien race that fits with what we have seen before with lots of references to honor, Kahless and speaking Klingon. I must admit reading all the subtitles is getting a bit tiresome, but that is a minor issue.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Conflict&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Historically Star Trek has not featured conflict between the main starfleet characters due to the idea that humanity has evolved beyond this. DS9 got round this by having Odo and Kira who are not starfleet characters so can have a little bit of conflict. Discovery has completely abandoned this idea.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In the pilot episode, the Michael Burnham commits mutiny on her captain, even attacking her with a vulcan nerve pinch. In the third episode we finally meet the discovery crew. Gone are the TNG days where the ships crew are like a family, I am not sure I can think of a single character that would call another character “friend”. We are in a time of war so this would be expected, however I do hope we see deepening friendships form between characters.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I am OK with the change to feature more conflict. I must admit the darkness of the third episode, did stop to make me think a bit, however by the fourth episode I was won over.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Cast&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The story is concentrated around Michael Burnham, so I do worry that other characters won’t get a look in. However from what I have seen Michael Burnham is a great character. She is a strong female character, with a intriguing back story relating to Sarek and possibly also Spock.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Saru the alien character on the show, played by the very tall Doug Jones is great. From the trailers he was all about sensing death, but there is far more to him than that. I am looking forward to learn more about him and his threat ganglia.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As the show has gone on we have started to learn about the other characters like Captain Lorca, Tilly and Paul Stamets.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Title Sequence&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I don’t like the opening title sequence, it feels very cheap like a draft version which hasn’t been finished yet. I was looking forward to a title sequence that would show off the USS Discovery, maybe like TNG where it warps around our own solar system. What we see is some of the tech that features in Star Trek which is nice but I want more. The theme tune while great that it features parts from the classic theme doesn’t stand on its own. I can hum all the other TV shows themes, and now after 4 episodes would struggle to do that.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>However I expect that after a while I will grow to like this more.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Overall&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I like Discovery and I will keep watching it. I want to find out what happens to the characters. There are no annoying characters like other shows have had. There is character development, none of the characters are going to finish where they started. I want more friendship between characters, but I expect that will come, I want more exploring and doing Star Trek stuff, but most of all I want more episodes, roll on next weeks show.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Other things I noticed&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Sound effects on the bridge are awesome, it makes me feel at home&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The USS Discovery doesn’t feature in the first two episodes despite being the title of the show.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Others have noted that Captain Georgiou has books on her shelf which feature classic episode titles&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Star Trek is back with Discovery</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2017/star-trek-is-back-with-discovery/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Sep 2017 20:00:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2017/star-trek-is-back-with-discovery/</guid><description>&lt;p>In &lt;a href="https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/star-trek-is-back-in-2017">November 2015&lt;/a>
it was announced that a new Star Trek series was going to be launched. It has been a long wait with multiple delays but Star Trek Discovery is finally here.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Star Trek Discovery launches in the US on 24th September and in the UK on 25th September.&lt;/p>
&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/UoV3kc05Nwc?rel=0" width="560" height="315" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen">&lt;/iframe>
&lt;p>Lets have a look back how we got here.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Star Trek was created by Gene Roddenberry in the 1960s. He imagined a show where we would explore the galaxy while also exploring the human condition. He described it as a wagon train to the stars. However it was cancelled after 79 episodes and three seasons due to budget cuts and low viewers.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After cancellation its popularity boomed in reruns. In the mid 1970s an animated series was created. But demand for Star Trek continued until a new Star Trek show was commissioned called Phase Two.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In 1977 Star Wars came out, and the phase two idea was cancelled and turned into a movie. In 1979 we got Star Trek The Motion Picture. It went massively over budget and failed to really capture the Star Trek spirit.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A much cheaper sequel was created in 1982 Star Trek II: The Wrath of Khan with Roddenberry taking more of a back seat. A film widely considered to be one of the best trek films. Four more feature films starring the original cast were made.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>However in 1987 Gene Roddenberry teamed up with Rick Berman and The Next Generation was created with a brand new cast. The series ran for seven seasons set roughly a century after the adventures of Kirk and Spock.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Popularity of Star Trek soured and this led Rick Berman to help create the spin off series Deep Space 9, Voyager and lastly Enterprise along with four feature films continuing the adventures of the TNG cast. When Enterprise was cancelled in 2005, Star Trek appeared to be dead after 18 years on TV.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>However in 2009 movie creator JJ Abrams recast the classic crew for the big screen. The film was big on action, but took place in an alternative timeline allowing for familiar characters to have new adventures without interfering with events depicted in the TV shows.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Two sequels to this film have been produced and are bringing Star Trek back into popularity. This has given rise to Discovery. Star Trek is returning to the TV screen and it is going to be great.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img class="img-fluid" alt="Discovery" src="https://storageaccountblog9f5d.blob.core.windows.net/blazor/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/gqojtfz1dhmxoiri7g8p.png?resize=662%2C372&amp;amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy"
/>
&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Star Trek Discovery – thoughts on new trailer</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2017/star-trek-discovery/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 May 2017 20:00:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2017/star-trek-discovery/</guid><description>&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/UoV3kc05Nwc" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen>&lt;/iframe>
&lt;p>I am really excited a new Star Trek Discovery trailer has just been released, if you haven’t seen it yet, watch it now.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The rumour mill has been going crazy about Star Trek Discovery but now we have a trailer with actual footage to analyse. In my opinion all the concerns about changes in the production team have gone out the window, this looks to be a polished Star Trek show that can sit alongside our favourites.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="the-ship">The Ship&lt;a class="anchor ms-1" href="#the-ship">&lt;i class="fas fa-link">&lt;/i>&lt;/a>&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>When images first surfaced of the ship I wasn’t keen, however all the shots of the ship look great. I assume this must be the USS Discovery, although it is hard to tell anything from a two minute advert.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img class="img-fluid" alt="" src="https://storageaccountblog9f5d.blob.core.windows.net/blazor/wp-content/uploads/2017/05/DAD0hTKUAAAUkTP.jpg?w=1199&amp;amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy"
/>
&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="the-bridge">The Bridge&lt;a class="anchor ms-1" href="#the-bridge">&lt;i class="fas fa-link">&lt;/i>&lt;/a>&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The Bridge looks recognisable as a Star Trek bridge, but also looks fresh and new. I think it feels very JJ Verse. I like it.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="the-uniforms">The Uniforms&lt;a class="anchor ms-1" href="#the-uniforms">&lt;i class="fas fa-link">&lt;/i>&lt;/a>&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The uniforms look like a mid step between what we saw on Enterprise and what we know as the Classic Trek look. I can’t see any Blue, Red, Gold to signify departments, but it looked like Gold and Silver could well signify something. Really hard to tell at this stage, but I like what I can see.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="characters">Characters&lt;a class="anchor ms-1" href="#characters">&lt;i class="fas fa-link">&lt;/i>&lt;/a>&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The show feels like it is going to be gritty and real. With characters you can really get behind. I liked what I saw of the captain and lead character. The alien character intrigued me, hopefully his line about death will be explored. It feels like there is a strong link between Vulcans and Sarek with the shows lead (played by Sonequa Martin-Green) Not sure how I feel about this yet, depends on what they do with it. I don’t want them to just redo what they have done with Spock, but again lets wait and see.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="klingons">Klingons&lt;a class="anchor ms-1" href="#klingons">&lt;i class="fas fa-link">&lt;/i>&lt;/a>&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>OK I am not sure I like the strong emphasis on the Klingons. I think we have spent a lot of time learning about Klingons, so when I heard the casting news about Klingons I was not excited. The Klingons also have a new look, which doesn’t bother me that much as the Klingons have changed their look before. But lets wait and see what happens.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="star-trek-is-back">Star Trek is back&lt;a class="anchor ms-1" href="#star-trek-is-back">&lt;i class="fas fa-link">&lt;/i>&lt;/a>&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>After over a decade with no Star Trek on TV, it is finally coming back. I am beyond excited about this. There are lots of things I want from this new show but this advert has definitely rekindled my excitement and hope that we are going to get something good.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Happy 50th Star Trek</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2016/happy-50th-star-trek/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Sep 2016 20:00:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2016/happy-50th-star-trek/</guid><description>&lt;p>On September 8th 1966 a TV show called Star Trek first aired. Today 50 years later people around the world are still watching Star Trek.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I was going to blog about the Star Trek story, but instead why not watch this video.&lt;/p>
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Bzi6CmUDabQ" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen>&lt;/iframe></description></item><item><title>Brothers, TNG S4 E3 Review, The Battle Bridge</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2016/brothers-tng-s4-e3-review-battle-bridge/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 May 2016 20:00:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2016/brothers-tng-s4-e3-review-battle-bridge/</guid><description>&lt;p>My latest podcast can be found &lt;a href="http://www.trekmate.org.uk/brothers-tng-s4-e3-review-the-battle-bridge/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">http://www.trekmate.org.uk/brothers-tng-s4-e3-review-the-battle-bridge/&lt;/a>
and feedback can be left on the trekmate forums &lt;a href="http://forum.trekmatefamily.com/2016/05/brothers-tng-s4-e3-review-the-battle-bridge/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">http://forum.trekmatefamily.com/2016/05/brothers-tng-s4-e3-review-the-battle-bridge/&lt;/a>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Data jeopardizes an emergency mission to save an ill child when he gets a signal from his creator.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Today James and Lou discuss (Brothers) and what we think of it, with tonight’s guest host Simon Foster, Funky Si.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Credit: Main Title Theme (TV Edit) was arranged by &lt;a href="http://en.memory-alpha.org/wiki/Dennis_McCarthy" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Dennis McCarthy&lt;/a>
and composed by &lt;a href="http://en.memory-alpha.org/wiki/Jerry_Goldsmith" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Jerry Goldsmith&lt;/a>
and &lt;a href="https://memory-alpha.fandom.com/wiki/Alexander_Courage" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Alexander Courage&lt;/a>
&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Star Trek Episode Review The Best of Both Worlds</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2016/star-trek-episode-review-the-best-of-both-worlds/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Feb 2016 20:00:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2016/star-trek-episode-review-the-best-of-both-worlds/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img class="img-fluid" alt="" src="https://storageaccountblog9f5d.blob.core.windows.net/blazor/wp-content/uploads/2016/02/Picard_kidnapped_by_the_Borg.jpg" loading="lazy"
/>
&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Episode Title: &lt;strong>The Best of Both Worlds&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Star Trek Type: TNG&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Original Air Date: 18 June 1990 &amp;amp; 24 September 1990&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Written By: Michael Piller&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Directed By: Cliff Bole&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>The Borg threaten the Federation, when they kidnap Captain Picard and destroy a fleet of 39 Starships. Luckily some original thinking from Commander Riker and Lieutenant Commander Shelby saves the Federation from assimilation.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Thoughts: I love this episode! It is probably my favourite episode in the whole of trek. I can’t think of a single scene which I don’t like.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It is a two parter that actually works best as a two parter. The moment that Riker orders the Enterprise to fire on the Borg is great. At the time some thought that Patrick Stewart might leave the show and be replaced by Riker/Shelby. I am very glad that didn’t happen but it is interesting to ponder what that might be like.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Borg soundtrack in this episode is great. Ron Jones really captures the spooky threat that the Borg are. I was always disappointed that some of that didn’t continue in First Contact and when the Borg return in Voyager.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The episode has a cracking pace. From the moment the Borg first attack the Enterprise to the moment the Borg ship explodes the show doesn’t slow down.&lt;/p>
&lt;pre tabindex="0">&lt;code>I am Locutus… of Borg. Resistance… is futile.
Your life, as it has been… is over. From this time forward… you will service… us.
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;p>Commander Shelby is a great character that enhances the episode and introduces conflict between characters, particularly Riker.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I have heard that Riker’s thoughts about his career was a mirror to writer Michael Piller’s thoughts about leaving the show. Luckily for us he stayed.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In a future episode of DS9 Worf comments that he felt there was nothing that they couldn’t do during this time. I have to agree the tag team of him and Data is a great one. If I want rescuing it would be Data and Worf that I would want.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My good friends at &lt;a href="http://www.trekmate.org.uk/the-best-of-both-worlds-tng-s3-e26-review-the-battle-bridge/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Trekmate&lt;/a>
have just reviewed part one, why not have a listen?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Star Trek Episode Review Arena</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2016/star-trek-episode-review-arena/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Jan 2016 20:00:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2016/star-trek-episode-review-arena/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img class="img-fluid" alt="" src="https://storageaccountblog9f5d.blob.core.windows.net/blazor/wp-content/uploads/2016/01/Gorn.jpg?w=662&amp;amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy"
/>
&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Episode Title: &lt;strong>Arena&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Star Trek Type: TOS&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Original Air Date: 19 January 1967&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Teleplay: Gene L Coon&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Story By: Frederic Brown&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Directed By: Joseph Pevney&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>The episode begins with the Enterprise in orbit of Cestus III. Commodore Travers requests a tactical team join the away team. When the away team beam down Cestus III has been destroyed.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Spock detects non-human life signs, obviously the aliens that destroyed the outpost. They attack the Enterprise, stranding the away team who are under heavy fire. Sulu is instructed to do whatever he can to protect the Enterprise and leaves orbit.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Kirk finds the armoury and a grenade launcher, after firing the enemy withdraws.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After beaming back aboard the Enterprise they pursue the unknown enemy into uncharted space. One of the survivors of Cestus III explains that the enemy attacked without warning.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Kirk is determined to destroy the enemy ship before it reaches home and the Enterprise prepares for battle.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>An unknown solar system scans the Enterprise as they continue their pursuit of the enemy ship. The enemy ship comes to a complete stop. The Enterprise prepares to attack but before they can they also come to a complete stop. The Metrons have stopped both ships because both ships were on a mission of violence. The captains of both ships will be placed on a planet where the winner can destroy the other.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Captain Kirk and the enemy captain appear on a desert planet. The enemy is a reptilian like species called the Gorn. The Gorn has superior strength to humans but Kirk manages to escape his first encounter.&lt;/p>
&lt;pre tabindex="0">&lt;code>&amp;#34;This is Captain James Kirk of the Starship Enterprise.
Whoever finds this, please get it to Starfleet Command.
I’m engaged in personal combat with a creature apparently
called a Gorn. He’s immensely strong. Already,
he has withstood attacks from me that would have
killed a Human being. Fortunately, though strong,
he is not agile. The agility and I hope the cleverness, is mine.&amp;#34;
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;p>The Metrons said that the planet contained materials to allow the building of a weapon, however at first glance Kirk sees nothing that could help him defeat the much strong Gorn captain. He does find some diamonds, too small to be used as a weapon.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Kirk pushes a huge boulder over a cliff onto the Gorn captain, which appears to knock him out, however he survives and Kirk barely escapes. Kirk then finds Sulphur, which triggers a memory.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Metrons allow the Enterprise to watch the last stages of Kirks struggle. They see Kirk discover Potassium Nitrate. The Gorn accuses the Federation of trespassing into their space.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Kirk starts constructing a weapon using the diamonds, sulphur and potassium nitrate to make a gunpowder explosion to fire the diamonds at the Gorn captain. Just in time he applies a spark to his weapon and his opponent lies defeated.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img class="img-fluid" alt="" src="https://storageaccountblog9f5d.blob.core.windows.net/blazor/wp-content/uploads/2016/01/Gorn_Kirk_cannon.jpg?resize=300%2C225&amp;amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy"
/>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Kirk refused to kill the Gorn captain as they may have been just defending themselves. The Metron announces that Kirk has displayed the advanced trait of mercy and there may be hope for humanity after all.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Thoughts: I like this episode very much. It has some classic Star Trek ideas in it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We have a super powerful alien race (the Metrons) that think there is hope for humanity.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We have Kirk using raw materials to construct a weapon using simple chemistry.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We have an enemy race that appears destructive but may have just been defending themselves.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We have the classic location of Vasquez Rocks, somewhere that if I ever visit the US I have to visit.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We have the very cheesy Gorn mask, yes its not realistic but the story is strong enough that it doesn’t really matter. Enterprise brought back the Gorn but as a CGI character and I think I may prefer the rubber mask.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Interestingly the weapon Kirk builds would likely not work. The US show MythBusters proved that the bamboo wasn’t strong enough to hold the explosion and the weapon would likely wound Kirk as much as it would wound the Gorn.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Score: 10/10
Redshirt Count: Cestus III Outpost, 1 Red Shirt and 1 yellow shirt from away team.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Top 50 Star Trek episodes</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2016/top-50-star-trek-episodes/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Jan 2016 20:00:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2016/top-50-star-trek-episodes/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img class="img-fluid" alt="" src="https://storageaccountblog9f5d.blob.core.windows.net/blazor/wp-content/uploads/2016/01/07df3N8m.jpg?w=512&amp;amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy"
/>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In 1966 a TV show called &lt;a href="http://www.startrek.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Star Trek&lt;/a>
first aired in the USA. Since then 726 episodes have been made and 12 films have been released. 2016 marks the 50th anniversary and Star Trek is as alive as ever with a new film due out this summer and a brand new TV series in the works for broadcast in 2017.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But what can I do to celebrate? With that many episodes I don’t have enough time to re-watch every episode so how about a re-watch of the top 50 episodes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Star Trek has five live action TV series so all I need to do is pick my top 10 from each.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="star-trek">Star Trek&lt;a class="anchor ms-1" href="#star-trek">&lt;i class="fas fa-link">&lt;/i>&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;img class="img-fluid" alt="" src="https://storageaccountblog9f5d.blob.core.windows.net/blazor/wp-content/uploads/2016/01/Landing_party_beams_up_from_Guardian_planet.jpg?resize=300%2C225&amp;amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy"
/>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The original Star Trek series first aired on September 8th 1966. It lasted only three years and 79 episodes. This series featured the iconic characters Kirk, Spock and Bones on a five-year mission to explore space.&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>The City on the Edge of Forever&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The Devil in the Dark&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Balance of Terror&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The Trouble with Tribbles&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="http://www.funkysi1701.com/2016/01/21/star-trek-episode-review-arena/">Arena&lt;/a>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>This Side of Paradise&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Amok Time&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Space Seed&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Mirror Mirror&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The Deadly Years&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h2 id="star-trek-the-next-generation">Star Trek: The Next Generation&lt;a class="anchor ms-1" href="#star-trek-the-next-generation">&lt;i class="fas fa-link">&lt;/i>&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;img class="img-fluid" alt="" src="https://storageaccountblog9f5d.blob.core.windows.net/blazor/wp-content/uploads/2016/01/Senior_staff_poker_game.jpg?resize=300%2C226&amp;amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy"
/>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The first spin-off series set 100 years after Kirk featured a new Enterprise continuing to explore space. This series aired between 1987 and 1994 for 178 episodes.&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="http://www.funkysi1701.com/2016/02/18/star-trek-episode-review-the-best-of-both-worlds/">Best of Both Worlds&lt;/a>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Yesterdays Enterprise&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The Offspring&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The Measure of a Man&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Disaster&lt;/li>
&lt;li>All Good Things…&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Tapestry&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The Inner Light&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Cause and Effect&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Unification&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h2 id="star-trek-deep-space-nine">Star Trek: Deep Space Nine&lt;a class="anchor ms-1" href="#star-trek-deep-space-nine">&lt;i class="fas fa-link">&lt;/i>&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;img class="img-fluid" alt="" src="https://storageaccountblog9f5d.blob.core.windows.net/blazor/wp-content/uploads/2016/01/Federation_fleet_prepares_to_engage_Dominion_fleet.jpg?resize=300%2C229&amp;amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy"
/>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The second spin-off series which ran at the same time as TNG was set on a space station so instead of exploring adventures arrived via a stable wormhole. This series aired between 1993 and 1999 for 176 episodes.&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Emissary&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Duet&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The Way of the Warrior&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The Visitor&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Sacrifice of Angels&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Waltz&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Trials and Tribble-ations&lt;/li>
&lt;li>In the Pale Moonlight&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Far Beyond the Stars&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Siege of AR 558&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h2 id="star-trek-voyager">Star Trek: Voyager&lt;a class="anchor ms-1" href="#star-trek-voyager">&lt;i class="fas fa-link">&lt;/i>&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;img class="img-fluid" alt="" src="https://storageaccountblog9f5d.blob.core.windows.net/blazor/wp-content/uploads/2016/01/Voyager_away_team.jpg?resize=300%2C246&amp;amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy"
/>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The third spin-off series ran after TNG and featured a female captain and a starship stranded in a remote part of the galaxy journeying home. This series aired between 1995 and 2001 for 172 episodes.&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Scorpions&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Year of Hell&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Caretaker&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Message in a Bottle&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Eye of the Needle&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Heroes and Demons&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Jetrel&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Timeless&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Pathfinder&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Riddles&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h2 id="star-trek-enterprise">Star Trek: Enterprise&lt;a class="anchor ms-1" href="#star-trek-enterprise">&lt;i class="fas fa-link">&lt;/i>&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;img class="img-fluid" alt="" src="https://storageaccountblog9f5d.blob.core.windows.net/blazor/wp-content/uploads/2016/01/Andorians_pjem.jpg?resize=300%2C207&amp;amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy"
/>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The most recent spin-off ran after Voyager and was set 100 years before Kirk. This series aired between 2001 and 2005 for 98 episodes.&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Broken Bow&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The Andorian Incident&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Shuttlepod One&lt;/li>
&lt;li>In a Mirror Darkly&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Twilight&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Damage&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Azati Prime&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Regeneration&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Impulse&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Zero Hour&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>I am not going to review each episode here, I will save that for future blogs. With 50 episodes that is one a week to get them all reviewed during Star Trek’s birthday year. We will see if I manage to keep to that schedule.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Roddenberry comic</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2015/roddenberry-comic/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Dec 2015 20:00:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2015/roddenberry-comic/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img class="img-fluid" alt="" src="https://www.funkysi1701.com/images/1-523x400.webp" loading="lazy"
width="523" height="400"
/>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Oatmeal created a comic which you really should check out. It can be found &lt;a href="http://theoatmeal.com/comics/plane" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">here&lt;/a>
.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The comic tells the story of a plane crash, in which the 25 year old co-pilot goes back into the burning plane to rescue passengers and lead a group of survivors through the desert to find help.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The co-pilot was named Gene Roddenberry, and after these events he stopped being a pilot and became a writer and eventually created Star Trek.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In these uncertain times when you are stranded in the desert, get out and help someone, it may change the world.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Star Trek is back (in 2017)</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2015/star-trek-is-back-in-2017/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Nov 2015 20:00:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2015/star-trek-is-back-in-2017/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img class="img-fluid" alt="3f448330857e4ca7ba40ab5465a3c2cb62cdb98c" src="https://storageaccountblog9f5d.blob.core.windows.net/blazor/wp-content/uploads/2015/11/3f448330857e4ca7ba40ab5465a3c2cb62cdb98c.png?resize=620%2C260" loading="lazy"
/>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As you have probably heard Star Trek is coming back to TV. I recently joined with the Sci Fi Waffle podcast to discuss.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sci Fi Waffle: Episode 12 – STAR TREK IS BACK!!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In this episode we discuss the great news that Star Trek IS BACK!!.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Shawn and I are joined again by James Roberts and TrekMates News feed Editor Simon Foster to speculate about the announcement of a new Star Trek TV series due to debut in January 2017.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>James can be found on our sister podcast &lt;a href="http://www.trekmate.org.uk/category/the-battle-bridge/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">The Battle Bridge&lt;/a>
and Simon can be found on Twitter &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/funkysi1701" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">@funkysi1701&lt;/a>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To listen go &lt;a href="http://www.trekmate.org.uk/sci-fi-waffle-episode-11-star-trek-is-back/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">http://www.trekmate.org.uk/sci-fi-waffle-episode-11-star-trek-is-back/&lt;/a>
, to leave feedback go &lt;a href="http://forum.trekmatefamily.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">http://forum.trekmatefamily.com/&lt;/a>
&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Top 10 Warp 11 Songs</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2015/top-10-warp-11-songs/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Oct 2015 20:00:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2015/top-10-warp-11-songs/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="i-dont-want-to-go-to-work-just-want-to-hang-with-captain-kirk">I don’t want to go to work Just want to hang with Captain Kirk&lt;a class="anchor ms-1" href="#i-dont-want-to-go-to-work-just-want-to-hang-with-captain-kirk">&lt;i class="fas fa-link">&lt;/i>&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>I am a big Warp 11 fan. Warp 11 are a Star Trek rock band from Sacramento, California. Their songs often feature bad language, sex and drinking but always feature references to Star Trek characters and episodes and a good dose of humour.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img class="img-fluid" alt="" src="https://storageaccountblog9f5d.blob.core.windows.net/blazor/wp-content/uploads/2015/10/redAlertCover_02.jpg?w=250&amp;amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy"
/>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I first listened to Warp 11 in about 2004 and have listened to every album they have released since. The second album Red Alert is probably my favourite but all their albums have a few tracks which I love. They have just released their seventh album and to celebrate this I will list my favourite tracks.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>All lyrics are by Warp 11 and no infringement is intended, if you like what you see go to their website (&lt;a href="https://www.warp11.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">www.warp11.com&lt;/a>
), or buy their music. Also Warp 11 if you are reading this, come to the UK, I would love to hear you perform live.&lt;/p>
&lt;ol start="10">
&lt;li>&lt;strong>It’s Dead Jim&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>From the fourth album &lt;strong>It’s Dead Jim&lt;/strong>. This song came out after Enterprise was cancelled and is all about the fact there was no more new trek being made. It was a bleak time to be a trekkie and I shared Warp 11’s sadness in this song.&lt;/p>
&lt;pre tabindex="0">&lt;code>First they took my TOS
Then they took my TNG
Said “bon voyage” to Voyager
Now there’s nothing left for me
Decommissioned DS9
Now there’s no more Enterprise
Erased the animated show
Yeah, she met a quick demise
The final frontier has been finalized
There ain’t no coming back
It’s getting no reprise
It boldly came and went
Got no Trek to represent
I never thought the day
Would come that I had to say
It’s dead Jim
Space is cold and so am I
Just like Kirk my show has died
Everything has gone awry
I guess it’s time to say goodbye
‘Cause Scotty’s gone and so is Bones
They took their final voyage home
And I guess I’ve always known
That some day I’d be alone
Tore down the sets today
Gave the plastic ears away
Sold the props on eBay
Left my life in disarray
It’s dead Jim
Until they bring it back again
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;ol start="9">
&lt;li>&lt;strong>7 of Mine&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>From the second album &lt;strong>Red Alert&lt;/strong>. 7 of 9 is one sexy character so it is no surprise that Warp 11 chose to sing about that in a few songs and I think this is probably the best example.&lt;/p>
&lt;pre tabindex="0">&lt;code>Flesh and bone and silicone
You’re all by yourself, but you’re never alone
You’re pretty smooth, for a chick full of wires
So cold to the touch
But you set me on fire
Assimilate me
Dominate me
Short circuit my mind
Energize me
Your thighs always rise me
Let’s go out and make your gears grind
Seven of mine
One minute you’re cruel
And then you’re kind
You gave me a virus, but baby I don’t mind
‘Cause I self destruct when I see your behind
I’ll show you the difference between seven and nine
Chorus
Well, life and love are so absurd
And assimilation is the final word
Resistance is futile can’t you see
So, come on now baby and assimilate me
I’ll give you an identity
Locutus ain’t got nothing on me, oh yeah
Let’s grab a shuttle and go to your cube
You bring the oil and honey I’ll bring the lube
It’s not monogamy
‘Cause in the end
When I’m f****** you, I’m f****** all of your friends
Chorus
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;ol start="8">
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Old Country Dr.(The Ballad Of Bones)&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>From the second album &lt;strong>Red Alert&lt;/strong>. A song dedicated to Bones so of course it is great. The use of harmonica makes you think of the country doctor which is a nice touch. This song gets a sequel as well on one of the later albums.&lt;/p>
&lt;pre tabindex="0">&lt;code>Well, they call me Bones and I’m third in command
Second in line is a man I just can’t stand
He’s a green blooded, pointy-eared, seven year itch
And when he pon farrs
He’ll try to make me his bitch
Well, I may or may not have divorced my wife
But I damn sure pulled the plug on my daddy’s life
And two months later, well, they found a cure
I’m just an old country doctor on a damned five year tour
The damned teleporter
Yeah, it gives me the creeps
The first time I used it
I couldn’t get it up for weeks
Now my tricorder’s busted
And sick bay just stinks
I guess I’ll just go replicate me a drink
Chorus
Well, Jim is the captain of this here ship
We call her the Enterprise, and the crew’s pretty hip
Yeah, the girls all wear go-go boots and miniskirts
And I spend my days patching all the red shirts
Well, I have been asked to do many a thing
Outside the area of my expertise
Damn it Jim, I know I’ve told you before
Damn it Jim, I know I’ve told you before
Damn it Jim, damn it Jim, I told you before
I’m just an old country doctor on a damned five year tour
Just an old country doctor on a damned five year tour
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;ol start="7">
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Space Happy&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>From the second album &lt;strong>Red Alert&lt;/strong>. This song is just solid good fun, with a catchy chorus that I can’t help singing along to.&lt;/p>
&lt;pre tabindex="0">&lt;code>Gonna take a five year tour
Boldly go where no man’s gone before
Gonna travel to the end
And make new friends
Move ahead warp factor ten
Put a miniskirt on my yeoman
Represent the human race
And we’ll make space
A happy place
To boldly go where no man’s gone before
I think I sang that line once before
(But I’m not too sure)
We’ll be so happy – can’t you see?
A zero-g community
Gonna travel to new worlds
Beam on down and meet some green girls
Gonna see what we can see
A fancy-free galaxy
Chorus
Come and take a tour with me
They’ll be no Kahns or Kobiashi
Gonna travel to the end
And make new friends
With aliens
Chorus
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;ol start="6">
&lt;li>&lt;strong>And Thats Why I’m In A Star Trek Band&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>From the second album &lt;strong>Red Alert&lt;/strong>. Not only does the start of this song make me think of the postman pat theme but it is good fun.&lt;/p>
&lt;pre tabindex="0">&lt;code>I love gettin’ hummers from chicks dressed as Klingons
Bumpy heads bobbin’ up and down
Like their necks have a spring on
And I know their teeth hurt
But I still get my thing on
And that’s why
And that’s why
I’m in a Star Trek band
I wanna tag team a stripper with Mr. William Shatner
He’ll take the front and hell, I’ll take the back-ner
And when we blow
We’re gonna reach warp factor
And that’s why
And that’s why
I’m in a Star Trek band
Well, people ask me
Where do I find my joy?
Do I like hot girls, green aliens or young boys?
Well, I got two words for you my friend – Leonard Nimoy
And that’s why
And that’s why
I’m in a Star Trek band
And that’s why
And that’s why
We’re in a Star Trek band
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;ol start="5">
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Everything I Do (I Do With William Shatner)&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>From the second album &lt;strong>Red Alert&lt;/strong>. This was probably the first Warp 11 song I heard and it made me want to listen to the rest. Warp 11 don’t just mention trek, they are actual fans as you can tell from the references that litter their songs.&lt;/p>
&lt;pre tabindex="0">&lt;code>Everything I do, I do with William Shatner
Loosing all my hair while my belly’s growing fat-ner
And when I drink too much
He holds my hair in his hands
And while I’m blowing chunks
He treats me like the captain
Oh, when we get together we boldly go
Talk about our favorite episodes
I don’t want to go to work
Just want to hang with Captain Kirk
And if I had my way I’d make it so
Everything I do, I do with William Shatner
We drink a couple of brews
Go to the Laundromat-ner
When our clothes are dry
We fold them up together
‘Cause everything I do, I do with William Shatner
Chorus
Hey, spend more time with him than George Takei
Say full speed ahead and we’re on our way
He is so mysterious
His middle name’s Tiberius
And he’ll make me his cabin boy someday
Hey Bill – Let’s go get a tan
Hey Bill – And a green woman
Hey Bill – We’ll kill some Romulans
Hey Bill – I’m your number one fan
‘Cause everything I do, I do with William Shatner
We go to the rodeo and put on our cowboy hat-ners
When we paint the town
We buy each other dinner
We’re fully functional
Just like Brent Spiner
Everything I do, I do with William Shatner
And don’t you wish that you could do it too
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;ol start="4">
&lt;li>&lt;strong>What would William Shatner do?&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>From the fifth album &lt;strong>I Don’t Want to Go to Heaven as Long as They Have Vulcans in Hell&lt;/strong>. Everyone’s been in situations where they would like to keep there fandom a secret. And what would William Shatner do?&lt;/p>
&lt;pre tabindex="0">&lt;code>I’ve got a girl, the coolest girl in the world
But she ain’t fly for the guys in sci-fi
And I’m a guy with a model Enterprise
Imagine her surprise if she ever finds out
I’ve got a queen, but she only wears blue jeans
And I am a guy in Kirk t-shirt
Black boots and a red miniskirt
I’ll be in world of hurt if she ever finds out
I’ve got to think about it
I’ve got to work it through
If she learns my dark secret
What would William Shatner do?
I’ve got a chick, in bed a lunatic
Won’t be my whore if she knows I love Star Wars
And I know only one thing for sure
I’ll never score If she ever finds out
I’ve got to make a choice now
Deceive her or tell her true
I know Vulcans never lie but
What would William Shatner do?
I love War of the Worlds, got a b**** for green girls
Alien nations, deep space stations
I love flying saucers, say “live long and prosper”
“May the force be with you”, Mr. Sulu
I want to be your man, “by your command”
Don’t want us to be undone, “danger Will Robinson!”
And if I decree “beedee beedee bee”
Does that mean we’ll be through?
What would William Shatner do?
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;ol start="3">
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Trekie Girl&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>From the second album &lt;strong>Red Alert&lt;/strong>. When I first listened to this song I was a single young man, so of course I dreamed about finding my own Trekie Girl. My wife now shares my love of Trek and looks extremely hot in a starfleet uniform.&lt;/p>
&lt;pre tabindex="0">&lt;code>She knows every episode
She wears the boots that go-go-go
She’s got a red miniskirt
She makes me play Captain Kirk
Trekkie girl, Trekkie girl
We go to conventions
She gives me erections
Girl – my Trekkie girl
She paints her skin green
And it’s not Halloween
She rocks my brave new world
She always acts so logical
She drives a Volvo Iike it’s our space shuttle (of love)
She looks just like Britney Spears
Just add a few pounds and some pointy ears
Trekkie girl, Trekkie girl
She loves outer space
Has a black and white face
Oh, girl – my Trekkie girl
I’m her Leonard Nimoy
She’s the real McCoy
She’s got a Spock haircut with curls
And on some nights she tells me
Put my symbiote inside her
She separates my saucer
Yeah, she knows just what to say
And on nights when I loose power
Well it doesn’t even phaser
She grabs my captain’s log
Torpedoes away
She knows every episode
She wears the boots that go-go-go
She’s got a red miniskirt
She makes me play Captain Kirk
Trekkie girl, Trekkie girl
We go to conventions
She gives me erections
Girl – my Trekkie girl
She paints her skin green
And it’s not Halloween
Oh, girl – my Trekkie girl
She loves outer space
Has a black and white face
Oh, girl – my Trekkie girl
I’m her Leonard Nimoy
She’s the real McCoy
My girl – Trekkie girl
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;ol start="2">
&lt;li>&lt;strong>A Song for People Who Never Watch Star Trek&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>From the third album &lt;strong>Boldly go down on me&lt;/strong>. This really tells you all you need to know about original series trek, plus I like singing the first line of this song to my son (also called James)&lt;/p>
&lt;pre tabindex="0">&lt;code>There was this guy
His name was Jim
You can call him Kirk
Or the Captain
He had a tan
And lots of women
Every episode
He got to blow his l***
He worked with Spock
He was a rock
No emotion
Nothing could rattle him
His blood was green
And Pon Farr could make him scream
And lose control
Though that’s illogical
Each week they’d all warp through space
Fight an alien race
And the Vulcan would pinch a neck
If you want to learn more
Go to the video store
Or just listen to this
Song for people who never watch Star Trek
Then there was Bones
Dr. McCoy
Worked with Nurse Chapel
And removed the red shirt shrapnel
Chased the miniskirts
Screaming, “Dammit, Kirk!”
Wait that wasn’t him
He was screaming, “Dammit Jim!”
Each week on the Enterprise
All the red shirts would die
But no one noticed or got upset
And the next generation
Will watch in syndication
Or just listen to this
Song for people who never watch Star Trek
And for three seasons
You know what they’d do
They’d boldly go
With the rest of their crew
Like Scotty
He was a Scot
And Chekov
He screamed a lot
And Uhura
And Sulu
But let’s face it
After Kirk, Spock and McCoy
Who gives a f*** about the rest of the crew?
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;ol>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>The Saddest Song Ever Written About Star Trek&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>From the fourth album &lt;strong>It’s Dead Jim&lt;/strong>. This song really encapsulates the sadness of Star Trek’s cancellation and the passing away of some of Star Treks greats.&lt;/p>
&lt;pre tabindex="0">&lt;code>It was a warm summer’s night when I sat down to write
The prettiest song ever written about Star Trek
The sky was clear
Full of stars above
I thought of Kirk and his crew
And their mission of love
And I sang the first verse
Of the prettiest song ever written about Star Trek
When the words came out
Everything was wrong
For those who’d boldly go
Had already gone
‘Cause the show was cancelled
And the dream was dead
And a red alert started wailing in my head
And I realized I had written
The saddest song ever written
About Star Trek
Now the sky was dark
Devoid of love
And Roddenberry’s ashes were floating up above
Raining down on a man
Singing the saddest song ever written about Star Trek
And now Bones is nothing but bones
He finally went and took his final voyage home
And Scotty’s body just couldn’t take much more
And I’m sure this is the saddest
Song ever written about Star Trek
I thought about space
And the final frontier
And I shed a tear as I finished
The saddest song ever written about Star Trek
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre></description></item><item><title>The Hunted, TNG S3 E11, The Battle Bridge</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2015/the-hunted-tng-s3-e11-the-battle-bridge/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Oct 2015 20:00:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2015/the-hunted-tng-s3-e11-the-battle-bridge/</guid><description>&lt;p>My latest podcast can be found &lt;a href="http://www.trekmate.org.uk/the-hunted-tng-s3-e11-the-battle-bridge/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">http://www.trekmate.org.uk/the-hunted-tng-s3-e11-the-battle-bridge/&lt;/a>
and feedback can be left on the trekmate forums &lt;a href="http://forum.trekmatefamily.com/2015/10/the-hunted-tng-s3-e11-review-the-battle-bridge/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">http://forum.trekmatefamily.com/2015/10/the-hunted-tng-s3-e11-review-the-battle-bridge/&lt;/a>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>While the Enterprise-D is reviewing a seemingly idyllic planet’s application for Federation membership, an escaped prisoner leads its crew to discover an ugly secret: the government’s shameful treatment of its war veterans.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Today James and Lou discuss (The Hunted) and what we think of it and much more as well as listener feedback with tonight’s guest host Simon.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Credit: Main Title Theme (TV Edit) was arranged by &lt;a href="http://en.memory-alpha.org/wiki/Dennis_McCarthy" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Dennis McCarthy&lt;/a>
and composed by &lt;a href="http://en.memory-alpha.org/wiki/Jerry_Goldsmith" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Jerry Goldsmith&lt;/a>
and &lt;a href="http://en.memory-alpha.org/wiki/Alexander_Courage/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Alexander Courage&lt;/a>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You can download the MP3 version of this show by &lt;a href="http://media.blubrry.com/trekmate/p/media.blubrry.com/previouslyalpha/p/media.blubrry.com/trekmatesupplemental/p/media.blubrry.com/loutrekshow/p/media.techpodcasts.com/loutrekshow/p/www.trekmate.org.uk/battlebridge/tbb-s3e11-the_hunted.mp3" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">clicking here&lt;/a>
.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Ten Forward Episode #135 – Anti Firbob is Back or Simon’s Desert Island Trek</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2015/ten-forward-episode-135-anti-firbob-is-back-or-simons-desert-island-trek/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2015 20:00:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2015/ten-forward-episode-135-anti-firbob-is-back-or-simons-desert-island-trek/</guid><description>&lt;p>The podcast I recorded the other week has been released, why not have a listen by heading over to &lt;a href="http://www.trekmate.org.uk/ten-forward-episode-135-anti-firbob-is-back-or-simons-desert-island-trek/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">trekmate.org.uk&lt;/a>
and comment on their forums&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This week Sina, Chris and Paul welcome Simon Foster, Trek Mate’s News Editor, to do discuss his Desert Island Trek choices. Paul becomes Firbob, or AntiFirbob, or&amp;hellip;something like that. Boo hiss Firbob. Every one listen and decide – Simon or Firbob?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You can reach Simon here:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/funkysi1701" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">@funkysi1701&lt;/a>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Complaints to @firbob1&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You can reach the rest of the gang here:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/queenkatblue" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">@queenkatblue&lt;/a>
, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/chriscantfly" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">@chriscantfly&lt;/a>
, or &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/TenForwardPod" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">facebook.com/TenForwardPod&lt;/a>
&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Podcasts</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2015/podcasts/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2015 20:00:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2015/podcasts/</guid><description>&lt;p>For a while now I have been listening to podcasts. For those that don’t know a podcast is an audio file that you can download and listen to, usually about a topic you are interested in. The topics that interest me are obviously Star Trek, Science and Technology and IT stuff. I mainly listen to them in the car when I am driving, but sometimes it will be at home when doing jobs around the house.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I think the first podcast I listened to was &lt;a href="http://www.trekmate.org.uk/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Trekmate&lt;/a>
. Trekmate as the name suggests is about Star Trek, it’s a few guys talking about Star Trek. It’s very similar to those conversations you have in the pub with your mates. Trekmate do lots of podcasts, one for almost every flavour of Star Trek out there, I don’t keep up with all of them, but the ones I listen to I really enjoy.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My favourite podcast that is work related is &lt;a href="http://www.runasradio.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">RunAs Radio&lt;/a>
. If you are a SysAdmin or have an interest in servers or IT you should listen to this. The host Richard Campbell interviews IT experts about a particular piece of technology, one week it will be Exchange, the next Security, and then SQL Server. Often I will learn something that I will want to try out, some weeks I won’t learn something specific but will give be an insight into which way IT for businesses is going. I think it was probably only after listening to RunAs Radio that are started having more of a long term plan for my IT infrastructure at work.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As I have blogged about before I am learning Development so obviously I listen to &lt;a href="http://www.dotnetrocks.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">.NET Rocks&lt;/a>
. This is hosted by Carl Franklin and Richard Campbell (yes the same guy that does RunAs Radio) who talk to developers about code, learning and IT from a more Developer point of view. This is released 3 times a week so is a bit hit and miss sometimes, but most weeks there will be something relevant to me or worth listening to.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A few days ago I did something for the first time, I was a guest on one of the Trekmate pods, TenForward. I reviewed 5 Star Trek episodes. This was a bit of a leap for me as an introvert I don’t like to be the center of attention and I certainly don’t like how my voice sounds recorded. Hopefully when released people will like it and I will do lots more of these in the future. Once it has been released I will put a link up here so you can all have a listen.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>To boldly go where no SQL has gone before Part 2</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2014/to-boldly-go-where-no-sql-has-gone-before-part-2/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2014 20:00:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2014/to-boldly-go-where-no-sql-has-gone-before-part-2/</guid><description>&lt;p>Let’s continue looking at a database schema for storing details of every Star Trek Episode. If you are new to databases, a schema is just the design of the structure of the database.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We have three tables, Episode, EpisodeWriter and Writer. See my last post for more details of these. It has been suggested that a slight change to this structure would enable storage of more of the creative staff.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Lets rename Writer and call it Credit, and rename EpisodeWriter and call it EpisodeCredit. Now any creative staff member involved in an episode can be stored in the Credit table. Lets alter EpisodeCredit and add an extra column called CreditType. CreditType is just a text field that stores the role that creative person had on that episode, it can be anything from Director, Writer, Actor, Science Consultant etc.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We now have the ability to store information relating to the episode in the episode table and any creative people in the credit table. What else can we add to the database? How about a table that can be used to record when an episode was last watched. I am probably weird but sometimes I want to watch a Star Trek episode that I like but I haven’t watched in ages.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The last watched table is really simple and just have a datetime field and episodeId. This can be further expanded to have a userId field if you wanted to keep track of what episodes your friends had been watching.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Another idea could be to tag episodes with certain themes or topics like Klingon episodes or meaning of life episodes or Kirk talks a computer to death episodes. Again this is fairly simple table containing TagName and EpisodeId.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>To boldly go where no SQL has gone before</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2014/to-boldly-go-where-no-sql-has-gone-before/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2014 20:00:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2014/to-boldly-go-where-no-sql-has-gone-before/</guid><description>&lt;p>My last post proved quite popular so I am wondering if I can combine a post about IT and Star Trek.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Years ago I used to have lists of Star Trek episodes, which included such information like original air date, production number, episode title and brief description.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>One thing that was hard to keep track of was how many episodes were written by a specific person. This is because episodes are written by multiple people. A column called writer would then need to contain multiple people, another option would be to have columns called writer1, writer2 etc. This wouldn’t help either as you wouldn’t know which column a specific writer had been saved in.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img class="img-fluid" alt="" src="https://storageaccountblog9f5d.blob.core.windows.net/blazor/wp-content/uploads/2014/10/manytomany.jpg?w=559&amp;amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy"
/>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The relationship between writer and episode is known as a many to many relationship. An episode can have many writers and a writer can have written many episodes. To achieve this structure in a SQL database you will need three database tables as it is not possible to create a many to many join between two tables. The first table will contain all the episodes, the second table will contain all the writers, the third table known as a junction table, will contain the relationship between the two.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Let’s do an example so we can see how this would work. Gene Roddenberry creator of Star Trek wrote the pilot episode ‘The Cage’. So Gene would be added to the writers table with an id of 1 and The Cage would be added to the episode table with an id of 1. In the junction table, it has two columns episode and writer, so we would enter 1 and 1 into these columns.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;">&lt;code class="language-sql" data-lang="sql">&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>&lt;span style="color:#66d9ef">Select&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#f92672">*&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#66d9ef">from&lt;/span> Episode e
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>&lt;span style="color:#66d9ef">Join&lt;/span> EpisodeWriter ew &lt;span style="color:#66d9ef">on&lt;/span> e.id &lt;span style="color:#f92672">=&lt;/span> ew.EpisodeId
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>&lt;span style="color:#66d9ef">Join&lt;/span> Writer w &lt;span style="color:#66d9ef">on&lt;/span> w.id &lt;span style="color:#f92672">=&lt;/span> ew.WriterId
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>&lt;p>But if Gene Coon and Gene Roddenberry had writing credits on The Cage we would need to add Gene Coon to the writing table and add an extra entry to the episodewriter table.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I am going to do more posts based on this as I expand the database structure to include other information, I may go on to create stored procedures for bringing back certain information or I may use this as an example to talk about coding a user interface.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Destination Star Trek</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2014/destination-star-trek/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2014 20:00:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2014/destination-star-trek/</guid><description>&lt;p>As a break from my usual topics I am going to talk about what I did over the weekend.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img class="img-fluid" alt="" src="https://storageaccountblog9f5d.blob.core.windows.net/blazor/wp-content/uploads/2014/10/10670061_10152884492389155_77781042960777157_n.jpg" loading="lazy"
/>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I am a huge star trek fan, so me and my wife Laura went to Destination Star Trek, a convention held in London. This is a picture of us in costume, my wife created a tribble costume (A tribble is an alien race that just consists of a ball of fur) and I am wearing an original series captains uniform. We had a great time.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There are several things that made this trip special.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Friends&lt;/strong>: After the last convention I remember thinking how much better the convention would be with a group of friends. Shortly afterwards I started listening to the trekmate podcast, eventually this lead to me helping out with their website and making friends via twitter with many of the hosts. This weekend was the first time I met up with them and it was great to put faces to names (or twitter names)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Writers and Directors&lt;/strong>: Star Trek has a great philosophy. In the future human beings will put their differences aside and work together to explore the galaxy, this is one reason why Star Trek is so popular even after almost 50 years. This philosophy has been created by the writers and other creative staff over the years. My favourite Star Trek film is Wrath of Khan which was directed by Nicholas Meyer, this weekend I got my DVD signed by him and was able to tell him how I still enjoyed that film over 30 years after it was made. He said that he really appreciated me saying that. Listening to his talk later on, it was fascinating to hear his insights into making my favourite film. It is the writers and directors that make our favourite characters who they are, the actors themselves aren’t allowed to ad lib, all they do is flesh them out with a bit of emotion or a mannerism, it is the writer that create our favourite lines or situations that we remember.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Seven of Nine&lt;/strong>: During my teenage years I had lots of posters of Seven on my walls. Seven of Nine was the ex-borg that walked around the ship in a skin tight catsuit, but she was also highly intelligent and continued to explore what it was to be human. It was great to have my photo taken with her, even if it was rushed due to the large number of people that wanted their picture taken.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Trivia&lt;/strong>: On the Friday of the convention, Laura took part in the beginners trivia challenge, she won. On Saturday I took part in the intermediate trivia challenge, I did really badly only got 3 correct, On Sunday I took part in the captain level challenge and I won. I really wasn’t expecting that, after I did so badly the day before. Thanks Marc Stamper and Destination Star Trek for organising that it was great fun, and also fun to meet the other trekkies who I had been competing against via twitter.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Party!&lt;/strong>: On Saturday night we went to a party, we had Romulan Ale to drink, we had some of the actors performing songs (James Darren was particularly good), and some of the actors mingled with fans, it was great to see the actors relaxing and if you were lucky you could chat to them, I asked Vaughn Armstrong how he was enjoying the music, he loved it.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>This is just a taste of what I got up to, there was lots more, like seeing alien costumes, listening to talks, sitting on a mockup of the bridge. Only one way to end this post, &lt;strong>Live Long and Prosper!&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>