<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>PowerBI on Funky Si's Blog</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/tags/powerbi/</link><description>Recent content in PowerBI on Funky Si's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 Jun 2017 20:00:45 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.funkysi1701.com/tags/powerbi/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>How do I add Power BI data to a webpage?</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts-old/how-do-i-add-power-bi-data-to-a-webpage/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jun 2017 20:00:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts-old/how-do-i-add-power-bi-data-to-a-webpage/</guid><description>&lt;p>Last week I talked about &lt;a href="https://www.funkysi1701.com/2017/06/05/businessintelligence/">Power BI&lt;/a>
, what it is and some of the different services you can use with it. This week lets add some of that data to a simple web page.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For this example I am going to add the google analytics data from this website to this page.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>First login to your Power BI &lt;a href="https://app.powerbi.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://app.powerbi.com/&lt;/a>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Click the get data link at the bottom left.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Click My Organisation to bring up the app search box.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img class="img-fluid" alt="Alt Text" src="https://dev-to-uploads.s3.amazonaws.com/uploads/articles/46c1lyxy053xcq66fowf.jpg" loading="lazy"
/>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Click the Apps tab and search for “google” in the search box, you should then see Google Analytics, click into this and then click the get it now button.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Log into your google account. If you have multiple google accounts I found it worked best to sign out of all of them or run this in an incognito window.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Once you are signed in you should see a list of the different google analytics data you have, select the one you want to use and click import.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Power BI will then go away and start loading the data.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Once loaded go to Reports and select the Google Analytics that has been loaded. If you have more than one, it is a good idea to rename each one eg Corporate Site Google Analytics, Blog Google Analytics so you won’t get mixed up.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In the file menu select Publish to web and agree that you are OK for this to be made public.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You will then be given a piece of HTML code that starts with &amp;lt;iframe copy this onto your web page. Reload your webpage and you should see something similar to mine below.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It should be noted that while you can but the webpage containing the iframe behind a login page, the data could still be accessed if you knew the url contained within the iframe, this is why the link can be emailed and continue to work.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>