<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>DZone on Funky Si's Blog</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/tags/dzone/</link><description>Recent content in DZone on Funky Si's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 25 Aug 2016 20:00:45 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.funkysi1701.com/tags/dzone/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>DZone</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2016/dzone/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Aug 2016 20:00:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2016/dzone/</guid><description>&lt;p>For a while now I have been sharing some of my blog posts on the &lt;a href="https://dzone.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Dzone&lt;/a>
website.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img class="img-fluid" alt="" src="https://storageaccountblog9f5d.blob.core.windows.net/blazor/wp-content/uploads/2016/08/dzone_02.png?w=400&amp;amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy"
/>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Dzone website allows users to submit links to content and I have been submitting the content I have created on this website. This is how Dzone describes themselves:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>With over 1 Million members, DZone.com is one of the web’s largest communities and publishers of technical content for software professionals. Developers from all over the world come to DZone for the latest and best content to hone their skills and advance their careers.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Well this week I have been invited to join the &lt;a href="https://dzone.com/pages/mvb" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">MVB&lt;/a>
(Most Valuable Blogger) programme. The hope is that more of my readers will find my content from the DZone website.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The DZone team will soon start sharing my content on the DZone website and I hope this will result in even more people reading what I have to say.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If nothing else this is clearly telling me that my blog is making a difference, people are taking note of me and what I have to say. I need to keep going and keep writing articles and be more consistent.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>