<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>2019 on Funky Si's Blog</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/2019/</link><description>Recent content in 2019 on Funky Si's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 05 Apr 2019 20:00:45 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.funkysi1701.com/2019/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Gated Release</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2019/gated-release/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Apr 2019 20:00:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2019/gated-release/</guid><description>&lt;p>Automated releases of software are great but how can we add an element of feedback so only good releases go live.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I have been using Azure DevOps to release my &lt;a href="https://www.funkysi1701.com/pwned-pass/">PwnedPass&lt;/a>
android app to the Google Play Store for a while now. There are options to deploy to the alpha, Beta or Production tracks and even to set % of users to target. For the full range of options check out the Google Play &lt;a href="https://marketplace.visualstudio.com/items?itemName=ms-vsclient.google-play" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">extension&lt;/a>
for Azure DevOps.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My release starts by publishing to 10% of users on the production track, my next step makes use of the increase rollout option to increase this %, you can have as many of these additional steps as you want until you reach 100% of your users.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img class="img-fluid" alt="Image" src="https://storageaccountblog9f5d.blob.core.windows.net/blazor/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/image.png?fit=662%2C116&amp;amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy"
/>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now if you run this release now it will just run through each of the steps one after the other. Now of course you can add a pre or post approval to your pipeline but this just adds a manual dependency to your release. Whoever does the approving needs to check things are working before approving or worse just approves regardless.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Azure DevOps has the concept of &lt;a href="https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/azure/devops/pipelines/release/deploy-using-approvals?view=azure-devops" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">gated releases&lt;/a>
which allows you to add automated checks before or after a release happens. These automated checks can be any of the following:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>An Azure Function&lt;/li>
&lt;li>A Rest API call&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Azure Monitor Alert&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Query Work Items&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Security and Compliance Assessment&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>We are going to make use of the Azure Monitor Alert, to create an alert from your Application Insights data and only continue the rollout if no failures are detected.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Open up your application insights resource in the Azure portal and look in alerts. Click add new alert rule.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img class="img-fluid" alt="Image" src="https://storageaccountblog9f5d.blob.core.windows.net/blazor/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/image-1.png?fit=662%2C552&amp;amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy"
/>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Select your application insights resource in Resource, In Condition choose a condition to check, I chose Failed Requests, so every time a failure is registered in my API I can stop the deployment. The exact criteria you want to use is entirely up to you.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Create an action group, I just set my alert to send an email to myself but there are other alert actions you may want to try. Give your alert a name and description and click save.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now all we need to do is make Azure DevOps make use of this alert. In your release pipeline select the pre-deployment conditions of your second step and open up the Gates section.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img class="img-fluid" alt="Image" src="https://storageaccountblog9f5d.blob.core.windows.net/blazor/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/image-2.png?fit=662%2C498&amp;amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy"
/>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Choose a suitable time to evaluate, I have been using something long like 12 or 24 hours so if there are problems there is time for it to be noticed. Choose Version 1 of the task (I was not able to get it to work with Version 0)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now select your Azure subscription and Resource Group and leave the rest of the settings as they are. Now your Deployment will stop and analyse application insights for any Failed requests and will halt if it finds any.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img class="img-fluid" alt="Image" src="https://storageaccountblog9f5d.blob.core.windows.net/blazor/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/image-3.png?fit=662%2C88&amp;amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy"
/>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I am still testing this out but it will take a few days to figure out if this what I want due to the large time scales involved. I feel this is going to be an improvement of manually approving release steps.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Pwned Pass Update</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2019/pwned-pass-update/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Jan 2019 20:00:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2019/pwned-pass-update/</guid><description>&lt;p>Its been a while since I first released Pwned Pass so lets have a look at where we are now.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We are very close to 500 Downloads from &lt;a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=pwnedpasswords.pwnedpasswords" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Google Play&lt;/a>
and we have recently smashed past 100 active installs, peaking at 116 and even now we are still over 100. I have had 9 reviews (6 x 5*, 2 x 1 * and a 4 *) which averages out at 4 *
&lt;img class="img-fluid" alt="Alt Text" src="https://storageaccountblog9f5d.blob.core.windows.net/blazor/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/image.png?w=662&amp;amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy"
/>
Over Christmas I released a UWP version that can be found in the &lt;a href="https://www.microsoft.com/store/apps/9NM2WHNZTNLT" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Microsoft Store&lt;/a>
. This has currently had 9 downloads and even had a download to windows mobile (someone out there still likes the platform!)
&lt;img class="img-fluid" alt="Alt Text" src="https://storageaccountblog9f5d.blob.core.windows.net/blazor/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/image-1.png?w=662&amp;amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy"
/>
I have a fairly smooth deployment process using Azure DevOps. After every check in of code a build runs which compiles the UWP and Android versions. The build also increments the version numbers that is required to deploy to either of the app stores.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Every successful build of the master branch will kick off a release to the Beta track of Google Play. If I am happy I then release to 10% of the Production track, which can then be increased to 100% (or halted). The release to Microsoft Store happens after the Beta track of Google Play. Only reason for this order is that there isn’t a beta area for UWP apps so I want to quickly test change on android before rolling out for windows.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>All these steps require confirmation by me before proceeding and often don’t get further than the beta track.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A further development is that I have open sourced the source code to &lt;a href="">github&lt;/a>
do take a look if you are curious or want to contribute. With the purchase by Microsoft there are easy ways to connect github repositories to Azure DevOps. Once I create a Pull Request in github it creates a build in Azure DevOps and all the build and release steps can happen.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I am still not 100% sure if I want to keep my bug and issue tracking in github or Azure DevOps as both have features for doing so.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>One future improvement I want to make is to automate the creation of screenshots. When I create a new feature and it gets checked in. I would like to automatically created screenshots of the key pages and submit them to the different app stores. Currently I am not sure if this is possible or how to go about it. I have some ideas to experiment with so we will see what I can do.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Lets see what 2019 can do!</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2019/lets-see-what-2019-can-do/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 20:00:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2019/lets-see-what-2019-can-do/</guid><description>&lt;p>This is my annual lets make some goals for the new year blog post. So in no particular order.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="improve-house">Improve House&lt;a class="anchor ms-1" href="#improve-house">&lt;i class="fas fa-link">&lt;/i>&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>I can’t outdo last years goal of buying a house but I can continue to make efforts to improve it. I was going to put something about decorating or doing something to our bedrooms, however today I spotted a hole in the roof so this may well absorb most of my home improvement budget.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="connect-with-local-area">Connect with local area&lt;a class="anchor ms-1" href="#connect-with-local-area">&lt;i class="fas fa-link">&lt;/i>&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Since we moved in October we haven’t really connected with our local area yet. My only interaction with my neighbours was when my car blocked his drive!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I am going to make efforts to change this in 2019. I don’t exactly know how yet, but I have some ideas. My son starts nursery and later school this year so could be one way to meet other parents and teachers. I want to connect with a local church, so far this hasn’t happened so need to make more effort with this. There are other local groups that put on child friendly events which would be good to attend.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="lightning-talk">Lightning Talk&lt;a class="anchor ms-1" href="#lightning-talk">&lt;i class="fas fa-link">&lt;/i>&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>I failed last year to do this so it is back on my list. I know I must have stuff of value to share so going to try again on this.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A lightning talk is a very short talk or presentation given at a conference or user group. I am not a natural public speaker so this is a step out of my comfort zone, however I am going to start small and see what happens.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>##Family Holiday
As always we Fosters are going to have a holiday in the summer and have some quality family time. I also want to take the boys to London for a weekend.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="blogging">Blogging&lt;a class="anchor ms-1" href="#blogging">&lt;i class="fas fa-link">&lt;/i>&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>This blog has taken a bit of a backseat in 2018 so I want to try and refocus it for 2019. My commitment is for 12 blog posts in 2019, that is one a month. It doesn’t sound like much but I know how easily life can get in the way.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Having said that my log has had record views this year. 7159 views. However I believe this number to be incorrect and has been inflated by my app development and some of the automated processes taking place.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="routine">Routine&lt;a class="anchor ms-1" href="#routine">&lt;i class="fas fa-link">&lt;/i>&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Last goal is to try a get more of a routine going. With two small boys, one of which is starting school in September a routine is going to be essential and will allow all of us all a chance to get more things done.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>