<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Mobile on Funky Si's Blog</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/tags/mobile/</link><description>Recent content in Mobile on Funky Si's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 14 Aug 2017 20:00:45 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.funkysi1701.com/tags/mobile/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Pwned Pass – Available from the Play Store</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2017/pwned-pass-available-from-the-play-store/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Aug 2017 20:00:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2017/pwned-pass-available-from-the-play-store/</guid><description>&lt;p>Pwned Pass is now available from the &lt;a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=pwnedpasswords.pwnedpasswords" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Google Play Store&lt;/a>
.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img class="img-fluid" alt="Pwned Pass" src="https://storageaccountblog9f5d.blob.core.windows.net/blazor/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/Screenshot_20170813-205152.png?resize=169%2C300&amp;amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy"
/>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Pwned Pass is a simple android app that allows you to type in a password and tells you if it has been used in a data breach.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Troy Hunt of &lt;a href="https://haveibeenpwned.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Have I Been Pwned?&lt;/a>
recently added a new API to his website which allows you to search his extensive database of pwned passwords, 306 million of them. I have simply created a Android frontend to this API.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The API itself takes a SHA1 hash of the password and either returns a HTTP 200 if the password is found or a HTTP 404 if the password does not exist in the HIBP database. For more details of how Troy Hunt created this check out his &lt;a href="https://www.troyhunt.com/introducing-306-million-freely-downloadable-pwned-passwords/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">blog post&lt;/a>
.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My app simply generates a SHA1 hash of anything that is typed in and then passes this to Troy Hunt’s API. I then get the HTTP return code so I know if the password exists or not.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It should be noted that: &lt;strong>Do not send any password you actively use to a third-party service – even this one!&lt;/strong> I don’t log anything that you type into my app and all I am then doing is passing a SHA1 hash over SSL to HIBP. However you shouldn’t trust my word alone.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The app itself is written in Visual Studio with Xamarin Forms in a similar fashion to the app I talked about &lt;a href="https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/android-app-development-and-the-visual-studio-mobile-centre">last week&lt;/a>
.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As I am using Xamarin Forms there is the potential that I may develop iPhone or UWP versions of this code in the future. With that in mind I have made use of interfaces for the android specific parts of the code.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I also make use of the &lt;a href="https://www.nuget.org/packages/modernhttpclient/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">modernhttpclient&lt;/a>
nuget package due to problems I encountered with httpclient and SSL. This is due to limitations of what libraries are available in mono and what has been implemented, I suspect there are better ways to solve this but that is all part of the fun.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Please do have a look at Pwned Pass and let me know what you think. Especially if it doesn’t work or throws errors. I would like to spend time making this app as good as I can make it.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>