<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>2015 on Funky Si's Blog</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/2015/</link><description>Recent content in 2015 on Funky Si's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2015 20:00:45 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.funkysi1701.com/2015/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>A look back at 2015</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2015/look-back-2015/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2015 20:00:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2015/look-back-2015/</guid><description>&lt;p>Wow! What an amazing year 2015 has been and with 2015 about to end I thought it would be good to look back at what happened in this amazing year.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img class="img-fluid" alt="" src="https://storageaccountblog9f5d.blob.core.windows.net/blazor/wp-content/uploads/2015/12/151218181153-2015-year-in-review-biggest-stories-wrap-up-orig-00025316-large-169.jpg?w=460&amp;amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy"
/>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>January&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I started the year with a declaration that 2015 would be my year of code. Well I have had a few breaks from programming but I have learnt loads this year. I have flitted a bit concentrating on different areas of programming but I think that has broadened my knowledge. I consider myself to be a &lt;a href="http://www.funkysi1701.com/2015/06/03/im-a-developer-now/">programmer now&lt;/a>
, which I didn’t at the start of 2015.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>February&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A first for 2015 was appearing on a &lt;a href="http://www.funkysi1701.com/2015/01/27/podcasts/">podcast&lt;/a>
. The Trekmate podcast &lt;a href="http://www.funkysi1701.com/2015/02/13/ten-forward-episode-135-anti-firbob-is-back-or-simons-desert-island-trek/">Ten Forward&lt;/a>
were the lucky ones that got to experience my first attempt at talking to the world. This continued throughout the year with appearances on &lt;a href="http://www.funkysi1701.com/2015/07/30/upper-pylon-2-1-x-09-the-passenger/">Upper Pylon 2&lt;/a>
, &lt;a href="http://www.funkysi1701.com/2015/10/08/the-hunted-tng-s3-e11-the-battle-bridge/">The Battle Bridge&lt;/a>
and even the &lt;a href="http://www.funkysi1701.com/2015/11/12/star-trek-is-back-in-2017/">Sci-Fi Waffle&lt;/a>
podcast.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It was a sad time for Trekkies at the end of February when &lt;a href="http://www.funkysi1701.com/2015/02/28/hes-really-not-dead-as-long-as-we-remember-him/">Leonard Nimoy&lt;/a>
passed away.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>March&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In March I talked about my recent efforts with &lt;a href="http://www.funkysi1701.com/2015/03/12/azure-traffic-manager/">Azure Traffic Manager&lt;/a>
to help prevent downtime. I also spent a lot of time improving &lt;a href="http://www.funkysi1701.com/2015/03/05/database-deployment/">databases&lt;/a>
which led me to consider ways to deploy it better.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Also in March I attended an IT networking event called &lt;a href="http://www.funkysi1701.com/2015/03/22/networking-event/">ITBoss&lt;/a>
. Free food and drinks and a discussion with fellow IT Managers.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>April&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>April was a bit of a mixed bag. I celebrated my second wedding anniversary but I also said goodbye to my car due to financial reasons.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I played about with a &lt;a href="http://www.funkysi1701.com/2015/04/11/the-raspberry-pi-adventure-starts/">Raspberry Pi&lt;/a>
, mostly with the &lt;a href="http://www.funkysi1701.com/2015/04/15/security-camera-with-raspberry-pi-camera/">camera&lt;/a>
. I really must make some time to play with it more.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>May&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In May I went to a C# User Group called Leeds Sharp, was great fun and I really need to make more time and go back in 2016. It did result in one of my &lt;a href="http://www.funkysi1701.com/2015/05/30/user-groups-and-f/">most popular blog posts&lt;/a>
.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Usually developers don’t enjoy finding bugs in their software but I had great fun when I realised I had a &lt;a href="http://www.funkysi1701.com/2015/05/22/overflow/">Stack Overflow&lt;/a>
in one of my databases, it was easy to fix once I worked out what was going on.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In May the UK went to the polls as we had another General Election.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>June&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In June I celebrated my &lt;a href="http://www.funkysi1701.com/2015/06/17/50th-blog-post/">50th Blog Post&lt;/a>
. Amazing to think I had already written 50 Blog posts, even more now!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Leeds Sharp had a coding challenge, to solve &lt;a href="http://www.funkysi1701.com/2015/06/26/sudoku-challenge/">Sodoku&lt;/a>
puzzle programatically. Didn’t get it finished but made a good stab at it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>July&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In July it was SysAdmin Day and I celebrated with my staff the amazing work we do keeping everything working.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Microsoft launched &lt;a href="http://www.funkysi1701.com/2015/07/11/how-to-upgrade-to-windows-10/">Windows 10&lt;/a>
in July, the latest operating system is being offered for free for a year.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>August&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In August everything changed as my son &lt;a href="http://www.funkysi1701.com/2015/09/03/baby-magic-and-becoming-a-father/">James&lt;/a>
was born. I took time out from blogging and work during this time to spend with James.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Before James was born I stepped down from my involvement with the &lt;a href="http://www.funkysi1701.com/2015/08/03/volunteering-for-a-technical-team/">technical team&lt;/a>
at St Michael le Belfrey.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>September&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In september it was back to work, where I started planning how to add &lt;a href="http://www.funkysi1701.com/2015/09/24/adding-internet-connection-resiliency/">internet connections&lt;/a>
to reduce the chance of outages.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>October&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In October I took James to a &lt;a href="http://www.funkysi1701.com/2015/10/22/james-goes-on-an-adventure-with-daddy/">dads group&lt;/a>
. This was the first time Dad spent time with James without Mummy and it was awesome.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I also celebrated my first birthday after becoming a father, was great to have a card from James. James also got the chance to spend time with my family in Nottingham.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>November&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In November the countdown to Christmas began with James appearing in his first Nativity as Jesus and dressed up as an Elf at a Christingle service.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Exciting Star Trek news was announced this month, a new &lt;a href="http://www.funkysi1701.com/2015/11/12/star-trek-is-back-in-2017/">TV series&lt;/a>
is to be aired in January 2017. No other details yet but very exciting.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>December&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>December is all about &lt;a href="http://www.funkysi1701.com/2015/12/24/christmas-2015-fosters/">Christmas&lt;/a>
and we had a great Christmas time as a family.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sadly York was hit by Floods just after Christmas, luckily my family was not affected but many others have been. Hopefully by the time you read this the cleanup will be well underway.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Before Christmas I spent my time counting down the days with the &lt;a href="http://www.funkysi1701.com/2015/12/17/christmas-count-code/">Advent of Code&lt;/a>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>What will 2016 bring?&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I don’t know. There will be lots more time with James as he continues to learn and develop. I will continue to learn and develop my coding skills. Watch this space as I keep blogging about it.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Christmas 2015 with the Fosters</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2015/christmas-2015-fosters/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Dec 2015 20:00:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2015/christmas-2015-fosters/</guid><description>&lt;p>Four months ago James David Martin Foster was born. And he is even more awesome now than when he was born.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img class="img-fluid" alt="" src="https://storageaccountblog9f5d.blob.core.windows.net/blazor/wp-content/uploads/2015/12/20151206_105450.jpg?w=747&amp;amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy"
/>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As I write this James only has a few sleeps (as James sleeps multiple times in a day I can’t put an exact number) until his first Christmas. James is pretty much unaware of what is going on as he is still too young but that doesn’t stop his parents enjoying the season.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>He has lots of Christmas themed clothes which we have been enjoying taking pictures of him wearing. He makes a great looking elf I think.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We took James to his first Christingle service at &lt;a href="http://belfrey.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">St Michael le Belfrey&lt;/a>
at the start of December. A Christingle service is where you stick a candle and cocktail sticks into an orange. James loved it, he already loves looking at lights so loved looking into the light from the candle.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img class="img-fluid" alt="" src="https://storageaccountblog9f5d.blob.core.windows.net/blazor/wp-content/uploads/2015/12/12333053_10153912153609155_79017677_o.jpg?resize=168%2C300&amp;amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy"
/>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Another Christmas activity we did this year as a family was to appear in a nativity. St Michael le Belfrey every Christmas hold a cafe to tell people the good news about Christmas and they have a nativity outside which includes donkeys. Don’t we make a great holy family. (Excuse the coffee cups but it was cold.)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Me and James’s mummy have gone a bit crazy with buying him presents, we have both got him lots of things to open on Christmas morning (or more likely mummy/daddy will do the opening)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>James also has three Christmas days to look forward to, with different sides of the family each no doubt with him as the centre of attention.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Exciting times. Happy Christmas everyone, make yours as special as ours.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img class="img-fluid" alt="" src="https://storageaccountblog9f5d.blob.core.windows.net/blazor/wp-content/uploads/2015/12/12309579_10153809916077792_2703731936729335666_o.jpg?resize=225%2C300&amp;amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy"
/>
&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Christmas count down with code</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2015/christmas-count-code/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Dec 2015 20:00:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2015/christmas-count-code/</guid><description>&lt;p>In December we count down the days to Christmas. People often have advent calendars filled with chocolates or even Lego.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But what about if you are a programmer, how can you count down the days till Christmas? What about if you had a daily Christmas themed coding challenge? Well &lt;a href="https://www.adventofcode.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">www.adventofcode.com&lt;/a>
is the answer.
&lt;img class="img-fluid" alt="" src="https://storageaccountblog9f5d.blob.core.windows.net/blazor/wp-content/uploads/2015/12/adventofcode.jpg?w=691&amp;amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy"
/>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Each day a new challenge is available. So far the challenges are related to Christmas and Santa delivering his presents. The challenge is split into two closely linked parts. You are given a randomly generated input and your need to give an answer using a short string or number.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The challenges are getting harder, with some completely defeating me, (not surprising with my limited programming knowledge). The challenges are language independent so you could try them in javascript or c#. I have been using Visual Studio and C# and my code is viewable on &lt;a href="https://github.com/funkysi/AdventSolution" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">github&lt;/a>
.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So far I have completed Challenges 1 to 6 and also 10. Partly because I found challenge 7 very difficult but I am hoping to have another go at it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>While coding through these challenges I have done a fair amount of refactoring. I started off with a simple console app with most of my code in one method. As the number of challenges increased I started moving the code for each challenge into its own class, with methods and properties that were unique to the challenge. I also added a main menu so you can choose which challenge to run. Some of my code to answer the challenges takes some time to run so this was quite a time saver over running each challenge in order.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>These challenges are very good at teaching me things about coding. I have got to think about data structures, what is the best way to store this information, classes and methods and return types, how to output data to the screen, how to input/import data.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Before I try and work on the next challenge lets have a look at the first challenge:&lt;/p>
&lt;pre tabindex="0">&lt;code>Santa is trying to deliver presents in a large apartment building, but he can’t find the right floor – the directions he got are a little confusing. He starts on the ground floor (floor 0) and then follows the instructions one character at a time.
An opening parenthesis, (, means he should go up one floor, and a closing parenthesis, ), means he should go down one floor.
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;p>This is a simple loop through a long string of ( and ) and keep track of the floor number you are on to calculate what floor Santa finishes on. The second part of the challenge asks at what point in your input string does santa reach the basement (floor -1)&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>SQL Server Management Studio</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2015/sql-server-management-studio/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2015/sql-server-management-studio/</guid><description>&lt;p>I use SQL Server Management Studio all the time for writing queries, getting data and general SQL development.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img class="img-fluid" alt="SQL Server Management Studio" src="https://storageaccountblog9f5d.blob.core.windows.net/blazor/wp-content/uploads/2015/12/sql-server-2012-management-studio-splash-screen.png?resize=529%2C360" loading="lazy"
/>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I have enjoyed seeing the improvements that each new version of SQL Server Management Studio (SSMS) introduced. One great improvement was intellisense.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This feature saves typing and reduces errors by automatically suggesting tables, column names or other database objects.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A common query that I get asked to write is provide a spreadsheet that gives the information that satisfies certain criteria. This is easy to do in SSMS, you can write the query, click execute and the rows that satisfy the criteria are displayed. These rows can then be easily copy/pasted into Excel or other spreadsheets.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A common data item that gets stored in databases is addresses and addresses often contain line breaks to make the data display better. In the earlier versions of SSMS, when you copied and pasted these line breaks were ignored and the data displayed the same in SSMS as it did in Excel. However in the more recent version, theses line breaks got copied across breaking your spreadsheet and making it hard to see what data corresponded with what.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now I don’t know if this should be described as introducing a bug or fixing one. I can easily argue both sides. If your data contains a line break and you copy this data it should include the line break in the destination, but if it does that it displays badly in Excel.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The fix I have been using until recently is to use the following TSQL command in my queries.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;">&lt;code class="language-sql" data-lang="sql">&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>&lt;span style="color:#66d9ef">SELECT&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#66d9ef">REPLACE&lt;/span>(&lt;span style="color:#66d9ef">REPLACE&lt;/span>(&lt;span style="color:#f92672">@&lt;/span>str, CHAR(&lt;span style="color:#ae81ff">13&lt;/span>), &lt;span style="color:#e6db74">&amp;#34;), CHAR(10), &amp;#34;&lt;/span>)
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>&lt;p>This command replaces any line breaks with an empty string. Both Char(10) and Char(13) are needed because you can have different types of line breaks. This is great if you are writing the script from scratch but isn’t great if your are running a stored procedure or your query has a lot of columns.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The answer to this is to use Visual Studio to run your SQL query. In Visual Studio you can write and run queries via Server Explorer and the results produced don’t contain line breaks. I have only just discovered this solution, but so far it has worked and is very easy to do, plus as I do most of my development in Visual Studio anyway it saves me having to open SSMS to test my queries.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Star Trek is back (in 2017)</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2015/star-trek-is-back-in-2017/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Nov 2015 20:00:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2015/star-trek-is-back-in-2017/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img class="img-fluid" alt="3f448330857e4ca7ba40ab5465a3c2cb62cdb98c" src="https://storageaccountblog9f5d.blob.core.windows.net/blazor/wp-content/uploads/2015/11/3f448330857e4ca7ba40ab5465a3c2cb62cdb98c.png?resize=620%2C260" loading="lazy"
/>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As you have probably heard Star Trek is coming back to TV. I recently joined with the Sci Fi Waffle podcast to discuss.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sci Fi Waffle: Episode 12 – STAR TREK IS BACK!!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In this episode we discuss the great news that Star Trek IS BACK!!.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Shawn and I are joined again by James Roberts and TrekMates News feed Editor Simon Foster to speculate about the announcement of a new Star Trek TV series due to debut in January 2017.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>James can be found on our sister podcast &lt;a href="http://www.trekmate.org.uk/category/the-battle-bridge/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">The Battle Bridge&lt;/a>
and Simon can be found on Twitter &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/funkysi1701" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">@funkysi1701&lt;/a>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To listen go &lt;a href="http://www.trekmate.org.uk/sci-fi-waffle-episode-11-star-trek-is-back/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">http://www.trekmate.org.uk/sci-fi-waffle-episode-11-star-trek-is-back/&lt;/a>
, to leave feedback go &lt;a href="http://forum.trekmatefamily.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">http://forum.trekmatefamily.com/&lt;/a>
&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Adding Internet Connection Resiliency</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2015/adding-internet-connection-resiliency/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Sep 2015 20:00:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2015/adding-internet-connection-resiliency/</guid><description>&lt;p>I have been asked to investigate adding a fail over internet connection to one of our offices.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Currently this office is connected via a wireless link with our head office. Unfortunately we have recently experienced some poor performance with this connection, this has now been corrected but like all technology there is the chance of it failing in some way in the future and causing loss of business because of it.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="internet-connection">Internet Connection&lt;a class="anchor ms-1" href="#internet-connection">&lt;i class="fas fa-link">&lt;/i>&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>This is one of my first considerations. I need a reliable internet connection and there are a lot of options to consider, lets look at a few.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img class="img-fluid" alt="" src="https://storageaccountblog9f5d.blob.core.windows.net/blazor/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/14091d1357164106-internet-connection-drops-every-couple-minutes-cable-sxchu-internet1.jpg?resize=660%2C252&amp;amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy"
/>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>ADSL Connection&lt;/strong> This is your standard internet connection that most homes have, you get around 20Mb/s download but only 2Mb/s upload for a fairly low price per month. Speeds are dependent on area and the quality and distance from your exchange, some rural areas have speeds much lower than this. As this connection is for an office I want the best connection I can afford so would rather not go down this option if I can avoid it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>FTTC (Fibre to the Cabinet)&lt;/strong> This is what ISPs typically mean when they say superfast broadband. The cables that have been laid to your exchange cabinet have been upgraded to fibre optic cables which are capable of much faster transfer speeds (eg 40Mb/s download and 10Mb/s upload). This is my ideal choice, however BT Openreach are responsible for upgrading the country to these cables and they are not very quick about it. A few years back when investigating this FTTC had almost reached our office, but when I investigated today nothing seems to have progressed. Both FTTC and ADSL require a phone line into the office to run on.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Leased Line&lt;/strong> This is where your ISP connects a dedicated line to your office which provides you a much faster connection (upload and download speeds are the same) but this is very expensive. We have this for our head office as this is where our servers are located and the faster speed benefits the entire company. We do not want to do this for every branch office as it will be too expensive.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Spur from a Leased Line&lt;/strong> It could be possible to branch or spur off the leased line to our second office. This would be one leased line that terminates in two locations instead of one. However due to the distances involved I do not think this will be possible in my case and may end up costing as much as a second leased line.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>ISP&lt;/strong> As well as the type of connection I need to decide who will provide it. There are hundreds of ISPs out there but I like to use ISPs that have a good reputation or I have used in the past and have been happy with. I do not stick with one ISP for all my connections as I like to have some connections that continue to work should that ISP be experiencing problems. ISPs that I would recommend are YDS, Eclipse and PlusNet&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Money Off&lt;/strong> While I am talking about internet connections the government has been offering a scheme offering businesses money off upgrading their connections to a superfast connection (either FTTC or Leased Line) More information can be found on your councils website, If you have an office in York have a look here for more details. We got £3000 off installation so worth investigating if you qualify.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="vpn-connection">VPN Connection&lt;a class="anchor ms-1" href="#vpn-connection">&lt;i class="fas fa-link">&lt;/i>&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Offices require access to far more resources than just the internet. This particular office requires access to our email and database servers as a bare minimum. One way to access a remote offices network resources is through a VPN (Virtual Private Network) connection. So my next consideration is how to establish a VPN link between our offices.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Software&lt;/strong> Windows Server includes RRAS (Routing and Remote Access Service) which you can use to configure a VPN connection. One important thing to note is that the server needs at least two network connections, one on the internet with a public IP and one on the internal network.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Hardware&lt;/strong> The more expensive routers often have settings that allow the configuration of a VPN connection.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I have used both of these methods in the past. RRAS is a pain to work with but has evolved with the newer versions of windows server, so may not be as bad as I remember. Using a router to do VPN introduces its own set of problems and there is no guarantee of avoiding RRAS, you may still need it to authenticate the VPN provided by your router.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="multiple-connection-handling">Multiple Connection Handling&lt;a class="anchor ms-1" href="#multiple-connection-handling">&lt;i class="fas fa-link">&lt;/i>&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Internet connectivity is being provided in two ways, the primary way is via a Wireless link and the second way is via one of the options above.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There are lots of options to deal with multiple connections, do I want to load balance both connections and use them all the time, do I want to fail over onto the second connection only if the first one fails, or do I want it to be a manual process or switching over to the backup network if problems occur.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As you can see there are lots of different technologies to consider before I can add resiliency to this office and I haven’t even started to think about if an additional server will be required.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Unmanaged Database Deployment</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2015/unmanaged-database-deployment/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Sep 2015 20:00:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2015/unmanaged-database-deployment/</guid><description>&lt;p>For the past few months I have been deploying changes to my companies database every couple of weeks or so. Over a weekend when the database was not being used I would make a backup of the database, load up visual studio, deploy the database changes and copy a couple of front-end files.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My weekends and evenings have recently become a bit more precious to me since the arrival of my son James. At suitable times to run the database upgrade I am either, asleep, about to fall asleep or be spending time with James.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This entire deployment can be set to run at a time of my choosing using SQL Server Jobs, (not sure why I never thought of doing this before). I still need to check everything is working after it has run. The job can send me an email if it encounters any problems so I can still ensure the company has the minimum of problems but has more frequent changes.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="unmanaged-database-deployment">Unmanaged Database Deployment&lt;a class="anchor ms-1" href="#unmanaged-database-deployment">&lt;i class="fas fa-link">&lt;/i>&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>OK so what do I need to do to set this up.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img class="img-fluid" alt="" src="https://storageaccountblog9f5d.blob.core.windows.net/blazor/wp-content/uploads/2015/09/deploy.jpg?resize=263%2C300&amp;amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy"
/>
&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Test all your code changes are working correctly on a backup of the database and everything is committed to source control.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Backup everything that is going to be changed so it can be rolled back in case of a problem. I don’t rely on the daily backup jobs for this, I do my own. Maybe I am a bit paranoid, or maybe I am just being cautious.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;">&lt;code class="language-sql" data-lang="sql">&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>BACKUP &lt;span style="color:#66d9ef">DATABASE&lt;/span> DBName &lt;span style="color:#66d9ef">TO&lt;/span> DISK&lt;span style="color:#f92672">=&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#e6db74">&amp;#39;E:\SQL Backups\Filename.bak&amp;#39;&lt;/span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>&lt;p>I would include in the backup file name the date and time of the deployment for easy reference later on. For the front-end files these are backed up daily and only ever change during a deployment so I am going to rely on the day to day backups, plus they are in source control so in a worse case scenario I can look there.&lt;/p>
&lt;ol start="3">
&lt;li>From Visual Studio create a deployment script using the publish option and save as a file on your database server.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Create a SQL Server Job and give it a descriptive name.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>In steps create a step called backup and enter the T-SQL code above. Set this to stop on failure and continue on success.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Create a second step called upgrade of type operating system with the following code.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;pre tabindex="0">&lt;code>sqlcmd -S (local) -i &amp;#34;E:\SQL Backups\deploy_test.sql&amp;#34;
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;p>The -S parameter is the name of your SQL Server instance and the -i parameter is the path to the sql script you generated from Visual Studio above. Set this job to quit reporting success or failure.&lt;/p>
&lt;ol start="7">
&lt;li>In schedule create a date time you want the job to run, make sure this is a one time job as you don’t want it to try and run again possibly causing problems.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>In notifications I have set to email on completion, you can set it to email on failure only. I would prefer to know the outcome of the job regardless.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Using SQL Server jobs to copy files over the network is possible but is not trivial to setup so I am going to use windows task scheduler for this.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Create a job in task scheduler to copy all the ADPs or ADEs that have been changed. If the SQL job fails you will need to copy the old versions of these back but that is simple enough to do.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>This process can be expanded to check code out of source control and do even more automated deployments but for now this is good enough for my purposes.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Baby Magic and Becoming a Father</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2015/baby-magic-and-becoming-a-father/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Sep 2015 20:00:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2015/baby-magic-and-becoming-a-father/</guid><description>&lt;p>I am pleased to announce the birth of James David Martin Foster weighing 9 lb 12 on 19th August 2015.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Mother and Baby (and Father) are doing well.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img class="img-fluid" alt="" src="https://storageaccountblog9f5d.blob.core.windows.net/blazor/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/james5.jpg?resize=300%2C225&amp;amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy"
/>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I am not a baby person, I hate children and I run a mile from other people’s babies.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But James performed some magic on me and now I will do anything for him. If you have had children you probably know what I am talking about and if you haven’t you are probably like me 24 hours before James arrived.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>During the pregnancy I had been living in denial that I would become a father, despite the wife speaking about nothing else and our home filing with baby equipment. It was only minutes before I first saw my son that I changed.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Due to James’s large size, the birth wasn’t easy. After about an hour of pushing the midwife called in a team of doctors and nurses to help and I think it was at this point that it started to hit me. I am not an emotional man, if anything I tend to repress my feelings but I completely and utterly failed to do that on this occasion. By the time the baby had been placed on my wife’s chest tears of joy were streaming down my face and this continued for some time. Moments after birth James had a tight grip on my finger. His tiny hands were like miniature versions of my own hands.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img class="img-fluid" alt="" src="https://storageaccountblog9f5d.blob.core.windows.net/blazor/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/jameshand.jpg?resize=169%2C300&amp;amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy"
/>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I have been asked what it felt like holding James in my arms for the first time, this happened on the following day. I am not sure if I can put it into words, but a few adjectives come to mind, amazing, great, fantastic, humbling. James depends on me (and his mother) for everything and his existence has put a new spin on everything I do. I want to be there for him, help him learn stuff, provide for him and love him.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I have been working very hard recently, spending my free time writing this blog, learning stuff and doing other work. The reasons for this hard work are now clear, I work so I can provide for James and so I can spend my free time with him.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Before James arrived I had it in my head that his mother would do the majority of the caring for him. This is not going to happen now that I have met James. I want to cuddle him, change his nappies, dress him, hold his hand, take him to school, watch TV with him, stroke his head when he is ill, tell him about my life experiences, introduce him to wine, tell him about girls, help him move home, etc.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I am not saying being a parent is going to be easy. I am pretty clueless about what is in store for us, but already I am worrying if he is OK, trying to calm him down when he is upset and being woken in the early hours.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Anyway only time will tell if I continue being this positive about fatherhood, but so far I am loving it. Normal blog posts will hopefully resume over the next few weeks (or when I have time).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Things to know before working on your database</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2015/things-to-know-before-working-on-your-databasethings-to-know-before-working-on-your-database/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Jul 2015 20:00:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2015/things-to-know-before-working-on-your-databasethings-to-know-before-working-on-your-database/</guid><description>&lt;p>I recently saw this blog &lt;a href="http://www.brentozar.com/archive/2015/07/questions-to-ask-before-you-touch-a-database-server/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">post&lt;/a>
by &lt;a href="http://www.brentozar.com/team/brent-ozar/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Brent Ozar&lt;/a>
that I thought I might discuss.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Brent listed 13 questions to ask about a database before you start working with it. I am going to go through these 13 questions and expand on them based on my experiences.&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Is this database in production now?&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>I think it should go without saying that the first thing you should find out is if your database is in production. If its not in production you can do what you like and no one will notice.
I know what databases are in production and which aren’t where I work so I can answer this one.&lt;/p>
&lt;ol start="2">
&lt;li>&lt;strong>If this goes down, what apps go down with it?&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>What apps are running on what databases is a good second question. I have at least one database which has multiple front end apps. At first glance you would think that that these two apps are not connected but they are, I need to be careful with both of these apps to make sure they don’t break each other.
I know what apps run off what databases.&lt;/p>
&lt;ol start="3">
&lt;li>&lt;strong>When those apps go down, is there potential for loss of life or money?&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>This is a difficult question so I will split it into two. Loss of life, my databases don’t control life support machines or nuclear weapons so my first instinct would be to say no. However it is not that straightforward, what if your app allowed contractors to know the location of dangers inside a property they were working in. Once your app goes down, they could have an accident due to lack of information.
Loss of money, this one is more straightforward. Time is money in the business world so any time that your app is down and your employees are not able to work is a loss of money. If your database is linked to an eCommerce site, the loss of money could be extremely high.
I know what affect downtime will have on my users and business.&lt;/p>
&lt;ol start="4">
&lt;li>&lt;strong>How sensitive are these apps to temporary slowdowns?&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>Similar to the previous question, a slowdown can be as serious as downtime for some applications.
Luckily most of my apps are internal only so are not seriously affected by slowness.&lt;/p>
&lt;ol start="5">
&lt;li>&lt;strong>When was the last successful backup?&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>I manage the backup schedule for all my databases so I know exactly when each one was last backed up. When ever I do anything to a production database I will run a backup so I can roll back in case of problems. As part of developing changes I run my changes on a backup of the data. I can script all my changes and repeatedly run them against a backup until I am sure no problems will occur.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img class="img-fluid" alt="" src="https://storageaccountblog9f5d.blob.core.windows.net/blazor/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/uf010206.jpg" loading="lazy"
/>
&lt;/p>
&lt;ol start="6">
&lt;li>&lt;strong>When was the last successful restore test?&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>More important than a backup is testing restoring your databases. If you can’t restore data then your backup is useless. I try to test restoring my backups at least weekly so I know that I can rely on my backups.&lt;/p>
&lt;ol start="7">
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Is everyone okay losing data back to the last successful backup?&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>If disaster strikes you could loose all data between now and the time of your last backup. But all is not lost transactional backups can be scheduled throughout the day, in my case the most data we could loose is 15 minutes. This could be configured to be more or less frequent depending on your data. But remember the previous question and make sure you test a restore of your transactional backups, if you can’t restore from them you will be forced to restore from the last successful backup.&lt;/p>
&lt;ol start="8">
&lt;li>&lt;strong>When was the last successful clean corruption test?&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>Corruption can be a killer if it is not found quickly. If you need to restore to the last backup before corruption occurred this could result in a significant amount of data loss. To check for corruption you need to run DBCC regularly.&lt;/p>
&lt;ol start="9">
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Do we have a development or staging environment where I can test my changes first?&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>If the answer to this is no, then your next job is to setup a development or staging area. Having a development environment makes development a lot easier and I don’t think I could manage to do all the changes I have done recently without one.&lt;/p>
&lt;ol start="10">
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Is there any documentation for why the server was configured this way?&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>I really wish we had more documentation about configurations as it would make finding out why thing were setup the way they are. So unfortunately the answer to this question is No.&lt;/p>
&lt;ol start="11">
&lt;li>&lt;strong>What changes am I not allowed to make?&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>Depending on what your app does, where it is hosted, how quick the changes are needed and many other factors will all restrict what changes you can make. Historical decisions on the database can also affect what changes can be made, if the database has been structured in a certain way, it may be very difficult to restructure it in a more efficient way.&lt;/p>
&lt;ol start="12">
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Who can test that my changes fixed the problem?&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>This is an interesting question, from experience the best people to speak to about problems with the database are the users. If they can show you how to reproduce a problem, you should be able to fix this problem, after that you can probably get them to verify that it has been fixed.&lt;/p>
&lt;ol start="13">
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Who can test that the apps still work as designed, and that my changes didn’t have unintended side effects?&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>This is an extension of the previous question. The main users of your app should be your first port of call to find out if the app works as expected. However exploring side affects and undesired features is something that I would test as part of the development process. It has taken a while but I have constructed a detailed check list that can be used for testing so I know that most bugs can be found before release.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Sudoku Challenge</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2015/sudoku-challenge/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Jun 2015 20:00:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2015/sudoku-challenge/</guid><description>&lt;p>Last night I went to a Code Dojo at Leeds Sharp (the coding user group I have started going to). A Code Dojo is a programming challenge that people work on usually in pairs.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The challenge that we worked on was to code a solution to the puzzle game Sudoku. The code we worked with can be found on github.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img class="img-fluid" alt="" src="https://storageaccountblog9f5d.blob.core.windows.net/blazor/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/2000px-Sudoku-by-L2G-20050714.svg_.png?resize=660%2C660&amp;amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy"
/>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I don’t know much about Sudoku but the game goes like this. You start with a 9×9 grid, and the idea is to fill in all the missing numbers.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Each Row can only use each digit 1 to 9 once, each column can only use each digit 1 to 9 once and each subgrid (3×3) can only use each digit once.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I worked with Richard one of the Leeds Sharp organisers, we started by trying to loop through each empty cell and insert values in a brute force attack, but this approach didn’t get us very far (literally as the application crashed!)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The approach that we needed to use was to loop through calculating possible values.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It was only when I sat down at this dojo did I realise how much I still have to learn, but while talking with Richard about different approaches and different coding structures I started to learn.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Fathers Day</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2015/fathers-day/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Jun 2015 20:00:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2015/fathers-day/</guid><description>&lt;p>In the UK today is Fathers Day. Happy Fathers Day Dad!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I thought I might talk about how he encouraged my interest in technology, especially as in about 8 weeks I will become a parent and will have someone to encourage and inspire.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I am going to sound really old but when I was born there was no internet, no mobile phones and computers more often appeared in sci-fi than in your home.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The first computer I remember us owning was a Lynx. A quick google reveals there were a number of different models, I have no idea what we had but here is what I found.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img class="img-fluid" alt="" src="https://storageaccountblog9f5d.blob.core.windows.net/blazor/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/PRODPIC-2926.jpg?resize=300%2C185&amp;amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy"
/>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In March 1983 the Lynx 48K was released, in September this was upgraded to 96K. In December 1983 a new Lynx was released with 128K. To put these numbers in perspective on my desktop is an image file that is 123K! The CPU in this computer was rated at between 4 and 6Mhz. (Modern PCs have CPUs around the 1.5Ghz or 1500Mhz)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Lynx we had, didn’t have a disk drive or a mouse. Programs were loaded from audio tapes (Audio tape was a form of data storage that came before CDs where data was stored on magnetic tape, most often used for music) The tapes we had would often get stuck and data wouldn’t load. The answer to this was to fast-forward/rewind the tape or hit the tape on your leg. For some reason this is a memory I still have of my dad hitting a tape on his leg to get a game or something else to load on the lynx. We also had a joystick for playing some of the games. I believe we also had an early thermal printer.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My memory of the Lynx is in black and white. The reason for this is that the Lynx was connected to an old black and white TV, it was a special treat when we connected the main colour TV to the Lynx.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We had a wide range of games for the Lynx, I can remember Jet Set Willy, and Diggerman. But there were also programs which my father had created. The Lynx had a form of BASIC where you can write you own programs and my father spent many hours writing programs for me and my sister. (We actually never realized this at the time)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>With that as my introduction to computers is it any wonder that I do what I do now? Now what should I do for my child to encourage them in a similar way?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As a family we never owned a games console. Not sure if this was a financial or moral choice but it is something I will have to think about. I want my child to be knowledgeable about computers and able to compete in the competitive job market, but I also want them to know about science and nature and to enjoy their childhood. Lots of technology choices to make over the next few years.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Runaway SQL Log growth</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2015/runaway-sql-log-growth/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Jun 2015 20:00:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2015/runaway-sql-log-growth/</guid><description>&lt;p>Today is my day off, but I wake up and have a quick look at &lt;a href="https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/i-love-nagios/">nagios&lt;/a>
to see if there is anything I need to worry about. Yes there is, SQL Server has run out of disk space on its data disk.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I race downstairs and VPN onto the server to find out what has happened. One of my monitoring databases has had runaway log growth and is over 80Gb is size.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;">&lt;code class="language-sql" data-lang="sql">&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>BACKUP LOG [DBName] &lt;span style="color:#66d9ef">WITH&lt;/span> TRUNCATE_ONLY
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>DBCC SHRINKFILE(&lt;span style="color:#e6db74">&amp;#39;DBName_Log&amp;#39;&lt;/span>)
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>&lt;p>Free disk space is back to normal, all users will be unaware of the problem and everything is fine again. I create a daily job that runs the above code, that way it should stay a manageable size.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Next I need to find out why it happened and to prevent it happening again in the future (Next time I have a day off I want to lie in!)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I check the SQL logs and notice&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKUP LOG WITH TRUNCATE_ONLY or WITH NO_LOG is deprecated. The simple recovery model should be used to automatically truncate the transaction log.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Then I remember what I have done to cause this issue. I have a separate disk for my backup files and earlier in the week I noticed this disk was filling up, a large amount of space was taken up by transactional backup files. I thought I don’t need to backup the transactions for this non critical database, I will just do a full backup at the start of everyday.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>However what I forgot is that a transactional backup keeps the log file under control, once this backup was stopped the log file grew uncontrollably. The answer, change the database from FULL mode to SIMPLE.&lt;a href="https://storageaccountblog9f5d.blob.core.windows.net/blazor/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/image002.png" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">&lt;img class="img-fluid" alt="image002" src="https://storageaccountblog9f5d.blob.core.windows.net/blazor/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/image002-300x270.png?resize=300%2C270" loading="lazy"
/>
&lt;/a>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is my understanding of how backups work in FULL mode. A full backup is done at the start of the day which resets the log file, then changes in the database are stored in the log file, this is backed up into a transactional backup and the log file gets reset. If you have regular transactional backups throughout the day the log file doesn’t grow too much, however with no transactional backups your log file contains an entire days worth of changes and so for a monitoring database this could be quite large.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In SIMPLE mode you can’t do transactional backups and the log doesn’t grow uncontrollably. This shouldn’t be used for production databases as if there is a problem you could loose data.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Source Control Fail</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2015/source-control-fail/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2015/source-control-fail/</guid><description>&lt;p>Every developer uses source control, it is a great tool for keeping track of changes to your code, seeing who has done what.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>However I keep messing up, my use of it. I am fairly disciplined when creating new features, all my changes will get committed to source control and when I am happy I will deploy these changes to the live system. But as soon as there is a bug, especially one where the client is chasing for a fix, I will deploy a fix as soon as humanly possible on to the live system.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>At first glance there is nothing wrong with what I have described but what happens the next time I deploy a new feature. Yes the bug the client was complaining about gets deployed with the new feature as the fix was never committed into source control. The client gets angry as the bug he was screaming about is back again.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Every change you make to the system &lt;strong>MUST&lt;/strong> be committed to source control. If it isn’t that change will look like it never existed. I have worked with source control for over 5 years why do I keep making this rookie mistake over and over.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Troy Hunt has a &lt;a href="http://www.troyhunt.com/2011/05/10-commandments-of-good-source-control.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">blog post&lt;/a>
about the 10 commandments of using source control. His number two commandment is “If it’s not in source control, it doesn’t exist” He talks more about code you have written being not saved into source control, but the principal is the same for my example as his.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There are ways to automatically deploy from source control, however most of the time you don’t want your live database being rebuilt because you fixed a typo. Additional steps will need to be implemented and there is still the chance that you might want to bypass these steps to fix the urgent problem. The only way past this problem is for you and everyone on your team to be disciplined and only ever commit to source control first, and only after that deploy live (either automatically or manually)&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Azure Traffic Manager</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2015/azure-traffic-manager/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Mar 2015 20:00:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2015/azure-traffic-manager/</guid><description>&lt;p>I have spent most of the day tweaking my Azure websites. Lots of fun!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Last week unfortunately Azure had some problems and many websites that were running in the North Europe data centre were unavailable for several hours. And you guessed it my websites were hosted here.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>All hosting providers are going to have downtime from time to time and this is just something you have to take on the chin. The important thing to do in times like these is communicate with your customers about what is going on and that you are doing everything you can to restore service.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>However Azure has some amazing features that you can configure to help manage when downtime occurs.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Azure is Microsoft’s global cloud platform. And it really is global, there are data centres in North Europe, West Europe, Brazil, Japan, two more in Asia and five in the US. In the event of problems it is highly unlikely that more than one of these would go down at once. If all of these are unavailable, I expect the planet earth is facing some kind of cataclysmic event and the fact that my website is down is not a priority.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://storageaccountblog9f5d.blob.core.windows.net/blazor/wp-content/uploads/2015/03/IC750592.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">&lt;img class="img-fluid" alt="IC750592" src="https://storageaccountblog9f5d.blob.core.windows.net/blazor/wp-content/uploads/2015/03/IC750592.jpg?resize=662%2C347" loading="lazy"
/>
&lt;/a>
To take advantage of these multiple data centres, Azure has something called a Traffic Manager.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Traffic Manager has various settings but I am using it in failover mode. This means that if one website goes down, the next one is used.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>All you need to do is create a traffic manager, add two or more websites to it (called endpoints) and choose a page that needs to be monitored so Azure knows which websites are up and which are down.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you are using SSL or custom domain names, there are a few extra steps you need to do. Your custom domain name needs pointing at the traffic manager, not the individual websites. The websites themselves have three domain names, the traffic manager address, the azure address and the custom domain name. The SSL certificate can then be assigned to each website that you have added to the traffic manager.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That was easy wasn’t it, and now if a website goes down traffic manager will use the next one. While testing this, the transition to the next website was almost immediate. I did notice that if you had a browser showing the website open during a problem you sometimes got an error page, I think this was probably due to browser caching, reopening a tab or browser fixed this issue.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Tidying my desktop</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2015/tidying-my-desktop/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Mar 2015 20:00:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2015/tidying-my-desktop/</guid><description>&lt;p>My desktop is always a mess. I constantly download files there and forget all about them.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Every now and then I copy files into sub directories, so my desktop looks sane for a day or two before it gets out of control again.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Why don’t I write a script that I can schedule to do this for me. Then my desktop will always be tidy.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I have written a few simple batch scripts, but of course the best scripting language out there at the moment is PowerShell. Lets use that.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Windows provides a nice little utility for writing scripts called the Windows PowerShell ISE, so let&amp;rsquo;s start by loading that up.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>PS has lots of help included to help you, just run &lt;strong>Get-Help [name of ps command]&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To move files you can use &lt;strong>Move-Item&lt;/strong> which works very similar to copy, specify source and destination. In my case I moved files based on their file extension.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Move-Item *.pdf folder&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now all I need to do is schedule this script to run either every day or so, or maybe every time I login or switch my computer on.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>PowerShell can do lots more interesting things which hopefully I will blog about soon.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Source Code for Game of Life</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2015/source-code-for-game-of-life/</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2015 09:00:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2015/source-code-for-game-of-life/</guid><description>&lt;p>Last week I blogged about the Game of Life.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Well it took some searching through dead hard drives and old USB storage but I found the program I wrote, and better than that I have figured out how to turn it back into source code.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The file date is November 2004 and the source code has no comments so I don’t know what was going through my head when I wrote it, or even what some of it does.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To view the source code download &lt;a href="https://storageaccountblog9f5d.blob.core.windows.net/blazor/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/Life.src_.zip" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Life.src&lt;/a>
, to download the finished program download &lt;a href="https://storageaccountblog9f5d.blob.core.windows.net/blazor/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/Life.zip" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Life&lt;/a>
.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img class="img-fluid" alt="Life" src="https://storageaccountblog9f5d.blob.core.windows.net/blazor/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/Life.jpg" loading="lazy"
/>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I am actually surprised I was expected the code to be much worse than it was, I am not saying it is good, but I can see more than one method and I can’t see any code that obviously is repeated. I can see some terrible variable names. Note to future self don’t use tmp676_674!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Assuming that I wrote this in 2004 what would I have been doing then? It was before I started working in IT. (Hard to imagine I know!) It may even have been before I started living with Keith, before he recruited me for my first IT role. I think I was probably working as an administrator for Defra at this point.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If we put 2004 in technical terms, it was before I joined facebook, Office 2003 and XP would have been installed on my PC, and probably felt brand new.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Choosing a Blog Theme</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2015/blog-theme/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2015 20:00:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2015/blog-theme/</guid><description>&lt;p>You may have noticed that my blog has a new home. It can now be found on its own domain &lt;a href="http://www.funkysi1701.com">http://www.funkysi1701.com&lt;/a>
. This change not only gives me more flexibility to make any change I like, it also feels good to have a website again. If you had followed my blog, do keep following it at the new location.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I have also been playing about with giving the site a new look, hope you all like it. I have gone for a more image focussed front page. No doubt in a few weeks I will be bored and change the look again.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I have recently been reading about blogging and one suggestion is to have a clear theme, or idea of what the blog is about. I am not sure my blog has a clear theme.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When I started blogging I was more interested in blogging than thinking about what I was blogging about. The vague theme I worked off was to talk about what I do, to answer the question, &amp;ldquo;What do you do?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I think this is a fairly good theme, but it could probably do with some refinement. The best themed blogs are specialist or about something specific. As I am generally learning about development, rather than doing development I think this should be part of what I concentrate my blogs about. A minority of my blogs can continue to be about the other things I spend my time doing, as it’s always good to have a break from the main “meat” of the blog every now and then.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The people who read my blogs are split between technical people and non-technical people, so I would like to continue to explain what I do in non-technical terms. This is an essential skill for a developer (or SysAdmin) as you will always need to explain what you are doing, or discuss requirements. It is not an easy skill and like development itself, the more I do it the better at it I will become.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So watch this space for the blogs to come. I know I will be working with Azure over the next few weeks so maybe some blogs about that, maybe some more SQL blogs or maybe about what I learn next.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Ten Forward Episode #135 – Anti Firbob is Back or Simon’s Desert Island Trek</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2015/ten-forward-episode-135-anti-firbob-is-back-or-simons-desert-island-trek/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2015 20:00:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2015/ten-forward-episode-135-anti-firbob-is-back-or-simons-desert-island-trek/</guid><description>&lt;p>The podcast I recorded the other week has been released, why not have a listen by heading over to &lt;a href="http://www.trekmate.org.uk/ten-forward-episode-135-anti-firbob-is-back-or-simons-desert-island-trek/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">trekmate.org.uk&lt;/a>
and comment on their forums&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This week Sina, Chris and Paul welcome Simon Foster, Trek Mate’s News Editor, to do discuss his Desert Island Trek choices. Paul becomes Firbob, or AntiFirbob, or&amp;hellip;something like that. Boo hiss Firbob. Every one listen and decide – Simon or Firbob?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You can reach Simon here:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/funkysi1701" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">@funkysi1701&lt;/a>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Complaints to @firbob1&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You can reach the rest of the gang here:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/queenkatblue" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">@queenkatblue&lt;/a>
, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/chriscantfly" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">@chriscantfly&lt;/a>
, or &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/TenForwardPod" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">facebook.com/TenForwardPod&lt;/a>
&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Game of Life</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2015/game-of-life/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2015 09:00:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2015/game-of-life/</guid><description>&lt;p>Many, many years ago I tried to learn Java. I didn’t get very far but one of the things I built was The Game of Life.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Unfortunately I can not find the code I wrote, probably a good things as it is probably amusingly bad.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now you are probably asking what is the &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Conway%27s_Game_of_Life" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Game of Life&lt;/a>
? The game of life, sometimes called cellular automation, is a simulation of cells being born and dying. It is sometimes called Conway’s Game of Life after the British mathematician who devised it in 1970.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img class="img-fluid" alt="" src="https://www.funkysi1701.com/images/Gospers_glider_gun.gif" loading="lazy"
width="250" height="180"
/>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The game has several rules:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Any cell with less than three neighbours will die on the next turn&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Any cell with three neighbours lives on to the next turn&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Any cell with more than three neighbours will die on the next turn&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Any dead cell with three live neighbours will be born on the next turn&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>Now I had not thought about this game until the other day when I came across a &lt;a href="https://chaosnil.wordpress.com/2015/02/09/new-project-conways-game-of-life-in-every-language/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">blog&lt;/a>
and a &lt;a href="https://github.com/chaomodus/gameoflife" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">github page&lt;/a>
which sparked my interest again. This version is written in javascript, but the blog mentions a desire to build this program in many different languages. I want to build this with visual studio in C# as it should provide a good training exercise.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There are several problems I need to overcome to achieve this, I am currently trying to work out how to &amp;ldquo;draw&amp;rdquo; the cells. My current thinking is that maybe I can code it using characters to display the cells and then replace with pixels once I have the logic correct. Well lots for me to learn!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Great British Code Off</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2015/great-british-code-off/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2015 20:00:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2015/great-british-code-off/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img class="img-fluid" alt="Great British Code Off" src="https://storageaccountblog9f5d.blob.core.windows.net/blazor/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/logo.jpg" loading="lazy"
/>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Great British Bake Off and The Great British Sewing Bee are very popular TV shows. Each week the contestants take part in a baking or sewing challenge and the judges choose the best and the worst, with the worst having to leave. This is very entertaining as you watch the drama between the contestants and the reactions as the judges tell them they are rubbish.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Could this simple format be applied to computer programming? I think it could.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The only developers I know argue about the best way of tackling different problems, despite being friends. I am going to assume that this is typical behaviour and not unique to them. So for this TV show, we will split the contestants into pairs, that way we would get the added drama of how well they work together.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I am still undecided if the pairs stick together each week with one pair leaving or if we randomize the pairs with one person leaves. The second option would cause there to be a group of three every other week, not sure if this would be a benefit or a curse for that group.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My friends who are experienced programmers have agreed to be the judges, they both have experience of hiring and firing people, know what to look for in good code, and never agree so should be entertaining enough.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On the bake off the contestants don’t really know how well they have done until the judges cut into their cake and take a bite. For the code off we could not compile the code until the judges run it, would make coding extra difficult as if the contestants are anything like me, I run my code every five minutes to see what affect that change has made.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So what challenges can we come up with?&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Web Design week&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Stored Procedure week&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Mobile App week&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Loops&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Logic problems&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Bugs weeks&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Performance issues&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>I think we are onto a winner here. What does everyone else think?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Laziness</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2015/laziness/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2015 20:00:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2015/laziness/</guid><description>&lt;p>I am lazy, I won’t try and deny that. When my alarm goes off in the morning, I will snooze it for twenty minutes or so before getting out of bed.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img class="img-fluid" alt="" src="https://storageaccountblog9f5d.blob.core.windows.net/blazor/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/bill-gates-quote.jpg" loading="lazy"
/>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In my work my laziness continues. Remote Desktop (or RDP) is probably my number one laziness tool. For those that don’t know RDP allows you to connect to another computer and access it like you were sat in front of it. So I can be sat at my desk and RDP into any other computer in the office including any server. However this laziness tool does sometimes require a bit of effort sometimes, powering on the target computer, logging on locally, making sure the user account you are using is allowed to use RDP.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Writing a script is another example of a laziness tool. I often get asked to do tedious and long-winded task, because I am lazy I will go out of my way to learn how to write a script to do this, so that I can run this script and do this long-winded task in a matter of seconds. There are loads of different types of scripts from database SQL scripts, to PowerShell scripts that can do almost anything on your server.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>PowerShell is something Microsoft are really pushing at the moment, you can even write scripts to create new user accounts, so no longer will you have to remember to tick that tickbox for every new user account. And because PowerShell is part of almost all MS technologies you can link Exchange to Active Directory and you don’t even have to remember the right syntax as PowerShell has a built-in help command to tell you how to run that useful command.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As I am now moving into a more developer role can I continue to be lazy? I sure can. Code should be written once and reused as often as possible and this is one of the features of OOP (Object Oriented Programming).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It can be as simple as creating a master page so you don’t need to recreate the same code on every one of your webpages. Or every time you find yourself rewriting the same code again, you plug it into a method so it can be called again and again.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But of course the ultimate way to be lazy is of course get yourself some staff and spend all day getting them to do everything. If you are lucky they may even try and adopt some of these lazy ideas.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Podcasts</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2015/podcasts/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2015 20:00:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2015/podcasts/</guid><description>&lt;p>For a while now I have been listening to podcasts. For those that don’t know a podcast is an audio file that you can download and listen to, usually about a topic you are interested in. The topics that interest me are obviously Star Trek, Science and Technology and IT stuff. I mainly listen to them in the car when I am driving, but sometimes it will be at home when doing jobs around the house.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I think the first podcast I listened to was &lt;a href="http://www.trekmate.org.uk/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Trekmate&lt;/a>
. Trekmate as the name suggests is about Star Trek, it’s a few guys talking about Star Trek. It’s very similar to those conversations you have in the pub with your mates. Trekmate do lots of podcasts, one for almost every flavour of Star Trek out there, I don’t keep up with all of them, but the ones I listen to I really enjoy.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My favourite podcast that is work related is &lt;a href="http://www.runasradio.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">RunAs Radio&lt;/a>
. If you are a SysAdmin or have an interest in servers or IT you should listen to this. The host Richard Campbell interviews IT experts about a particular piece of technology, one week it will be Exchange, the next Security, and then SQL Server. Often I will learn something that I will want to try out, some weeks I won’t learn something specific but will give be an insight into which way IT for businesses is going. I think it was probably only after listening to RunAs Radio that are started having more of a long term plan for my IT infrastructure at work.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As I have blogged about before I am learning Development so obviously I listen to &lt;a href="http://www.dotnetrocks.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">.NET Rocks&lt;/a>
. This is hosted by Carl Franklin and Richard Campbell (yes the same guy that does RunAs Radio) who talk to developers about code, learning and IT from a more Developer point of view. This is released 3 times a week so is a bit hit and miss sometimes, but most weeks there will be something relevant to me or worth listening to.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A few days ago I did something for the first time, I was a guest on one of the Trekmate pods, TenForward. I reviewed 5 Star Trek episodes. This was a bit of a leap for me as an introvert I don’t like to be the center of attention and I certainly don’t like how my voice sounds recorded. Hopefully when released people will like it and I will do lots more of these in the future. Once it has been released I will put a link up here so you can all have a listen.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Pair Programming</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2015/pair-programming/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2015 20:00:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2015/pair-programming/</guid><description>&lt;p>So I have been working through the challenges on the &lt;a href="http://www.freecodecamp.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">freecodecamp&lt;/a>
website and one of the unique things that this site does is give you the chance to program with another person.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I am an introvert and if you were to ask me to pick up the phone and ring someone I will procrastinate a lot before doing it (if I do it at all), I also am not good at speaking with strangers but I have been enjoying the pair programming I have done so far.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I have only pair programmed a couple of times so far, so I am no expert. The first time was with someone from North America, it was weird to begin with talking to your computer and hearing an american voice respond, but you soon forget that as you concentrate on the problems you are working on.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The second time was with someone from the Netherlands. This time we tackled some trickier problems. Both times I took more of a back seat but I think contributed useful stuff and I certainly learnt a lot from the other person.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I think that is the key thing about pair programming, you learn so much about how to look at a problem from another angle, or learn about a function you haven’t heard of before. If you are reading this and it was you that I pair programmed with a big thank you for spending the time with me, I learnt a lot.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I was trying to pair program again tonight but technical problems prevented me. One problem I have found is finding a partner, was hoping to do some yesterday but no one else was around to partner with.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I would be interested to learn what companies use pair programming. I imagine a pointy haired boss would say why pay two people to do one job, when you could get them working on different things. However if you want to build up your team and give them loads more skills then pair programming would be great. I also think there are probably some problems that are crying out for pair programming.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Javascript progress</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2015/javascript-progress/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2015 20:00:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2015/javascript-progress/</guid><description>&lt;p>I got excited earlier this week as I started playing around with the javascript I have been learning.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I thought I would try and create useful javascript that could be applied to an online filestore. Somewhere that you could upload, delete, edit files and folders and various options to do with your files would popup via javascript or jquery code.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So far I have created a static HTML page which lists a few dummy files. I have added a button which adds a new row into my table and I have used jquery to highlight any selected files and also when the mouse passes over.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you want to follow my progress I have put my files on &lt;a href="https://github.com/funkysi1701/CodeSamples/tree/master/clouds-js" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">github&lt;/a>
. It’s very basic stuff and I have already got a few lines I would like to refactor but not bad for an evenings work. I have lots of feature ideas to add to this page which should help me learn the basics.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The trouble with learning all this javascript is that I am starting to get all my programming languages confused. Earlier this week I started writing a for loop in javascript, only problem was I was working on an MS Access ADP (Don’t ask!) which requires the code in VBA. That is never going to work. Oh well.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If anyone knows good ways to stop myself getting my programming languages all confused do let me know.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hello World!</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2015/hello-world-2/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2015 20:00:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2015/hello-world-2/</guid><description>&lt;p>The first program anyone writes in a new language is often really simple and just displays the text “Hello World!”, below are a few examples from languages I have knowledge of.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;">&lt;code class="language-C#" data-lang="C#">&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>Console.WriteLine(&lt;span style="color:#e6db74">&amp;#34;Hello, world!&amp;#34;&lt;/span>);
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;">&lt;code class="language-HTML" data-lang="HTML">&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>&amp;lt;&lt;span style="color:#f92672">html&lt;/span>&amp;gt;
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>&amp;lt;&lt;span style="color:#f92672">head&lt;/span>&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/&lt;span style="color:#f92672">head&lt;/span>&amp;gt;
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>&amp;lt;&lt;span style="color:#f92672">body&lt;/span>&amp;gt;
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>&amp;lt;&lt;span style="color:#f92672">p&lt;/span>&amp;gt;Hello, world!&amp;lt;/&lt;span style="color:#f92672">p&lt;/span>&amp;gt;
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>&amp;lt;/&lt;span style="color:#f92672">body&lt;/span>&amp;gt;
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>&amp;lt;/&lt;span style="color:#f92672">html&lt;/span>&amp;gt;
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;">&lt;code class="language-PHP" data-lang="PHP">&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>&lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">php&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#66d9ef">echo&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#e6db74">&amp;#39;Hello, world!&amp;#39;&lt;/span>; &lt;span style="color:#75715e">?&amp;gt;&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#960050;background-color:#1e0010">
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>&lt;pre tabindex="0">&lt;code>MsgBox(&amp;#34;Hello, World!&amp;#34;)
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;">&lt;code class="language-SQL" data-lang="SQL">&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>&lt;span style="color:#66d9ef">SELECT&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#e6db74">&amp;#39;Hello, world!&amp;#39;&lt;/span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>&lt;p>Or maybe&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;">&lt;code class="language-SQL" data-lang="SQL">&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>&lt;span style="color:#66d9ef">SELECT&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#f92672">*&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#66d9ef">FROM&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#66d9ef">table&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#66d9ef">WHERE&lt;/span> name &lt;span style="color:#f92672">=&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#e6db74">&amp;#39;Hello World!&amp;#39;&lt;/span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;">&lt;code class="language-PowerShell" data-lang="PowerShell">&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>&lt;span style="color:#e6db74">&amp;#39;Hello, world!&amp;#39;&lt;/span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;">&lt;code class="language-JavaScript" data-lang="JavaScript">&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>&lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">console&lt;/span>.&lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">log&lt;/span>(&lt;span style="color:#e6db74">&amp;#39;Hello, world!&amp;#39;&lt;/span>);
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;">&lt;code class="language-BASIC" data-lang="BASIC">&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>&lt;span style="color:#66d9ef">PRINT&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#e6db74">&amp;#34;Hello, world!&amp;#34;&lt;/span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>&lt;p>Turns out I know quite a few programming languages. And yes there have been times where I need to stop and think about which language I am writing in.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>My Year of Code</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2015/my-year-of-code/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2015 20:00:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2015/my-year-of-code/</guid><description>&lt;p>There is no escaping the fact that we are in 2015 now. My new years resolution is to do more coding.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Over Christmas I thought I would have a go at &lt;a href="http://www.codecademy.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">http://www.codecademy.com&lt;/a>
I completed the javascript course and I was just wondering what I should try next when I saw a tweet about &lt;a href="http://www.freecodecamp.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">http://www.freecodecamp.com&lt;/a>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Since then I have been addicted to doing the exercises that they have, almost everyday I have made a bit of progress.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But this site is not just about teaching you how to code, it has an active forum where you can ask questions and understand more about what it takes to become a developer.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Before I started these exercises I didn’t know much javascript or jquery but I am starting to learn quite a few commands that hopefully I can put into use at some point. Whatever development I end up doing I am sure I am going to need javascript at some point.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>One of the tips I have learnt is that you need to practise daily. Did you ever use flash cards to help pass exams? Well there is an electronic version of them now called Anki. Just add a question/answer pair to your deck of cards and review them each day, the ones you find difficult you review more often than the ones you have learnt.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Hopefully I can keep this up and later in the year I will be well on way to writing lots of useful code.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>