<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>2015 on Funky Si's Blog</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/2015/</link><description>Recent content in 2015 on Funky Si's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2015 09:00:45 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.funkysi1701.com/2015/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Source Code for Game of Life</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/source-code-for-game-of-life/</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2015 09:00:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/source-code-for-game-of-life/</guid><description>&lt;p>Last week I blogged about the Game of Life.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Well it took some searching through dead hard drives and old USB storage but I found the program I wrote, and better than that I have figured out how to turn it back into source code.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The file date is November 2004 and the source code has no comments so I don’t know what was going through my head when I wrote it, or even what some of it does.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To view the source code download &lt;a href="https://storageaccountblog9f5d.blob.core.windows.net/blazor/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/Life.src_.zip" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Life.src&lt;/a>
, to download the finished program download &lt;a href="https://storageaccountblog9f5d.blob.core.windows.net/blazor/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/Life.zip" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Life&lt;/a>
.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img class="img-fluid" alt="Life" src="https://storageaccountblog9f5d.blob.core.windows.net/blazor/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/Life.jpg" loading="lazy"
/>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I am actually surprised I was expected the code to be much worse than it was, I am not saying it is good, but I can see more than one method and I can’t see any code that obviously is repeated. I can see some terrible variable names. Note to future self don’t use tmp676_674!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Assuming that I wrote this in 2004 what would I have been doing then? It was before I started working in IT. (Hard to imagine I know!) It may even have been before I started living with Keith, before he recruited me for my first IT role. I think I was probably working as an administrator for Defra at this point.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If we put 2004 in technical terms, it was before I joined facebook, Office 2003 and XP would have been installed on my PC, and probably felt brand new.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>