<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>2015 on Funky Si's Blog</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/2015/</link><description>Recent content in 2015 on Funky Si's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 03 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.funkysi1701.com/2015/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>SQL Server Management Studio</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/sql-server-management-studio/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/sql-server-management-studio/</guid><description>&lt;p>I use SQL Server Management Studio all the time for writing queries, getting data and general SQL development.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img class="img-fluid" alt="SQL Server Management Studio" src="https://storageaccountblog9f5d.blob.core.windows.net/blazor/wp-content/uploads/2015/12/sql-server-2012-management-studio-splash-screen.png?resize=529%2C360" loading="lazy"
/>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I have enjoyed seeing the improvements that each new version of SQL Server Management Studio (SSMS) introduced. One great improvement was intellisense.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This feature saves typing and reduces errors by automatically suggesting tables, column names or other database objects.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A common query that I get asked to write is provide a spreadsheet that gives the information that satisfies certain criteria. This is easy to do in SSMS, you can write the query, click execute and the rows that satisfy the criteria are displayed. These rows can then be easily copy/pasted into Excel or other spreadsheets.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A common data item that gets stored in databases is addresses and addresses often contain line breaks to make the data display better. In the earlier versions of SSMS, when you copied and pasted these line breaks were ignored and the data displayed the same in SSMS as it did in Excel. However in the more recent version, theses line breaks got copied across breaking your spreadsheet and making it hard to see what data corresponded with what.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now I don’t know if this should be described as introducing a bug or fixing one. I can easily argue both sides. If your data contains a line break and you copy this data it should include the line break in the destination, but if it does that it displays badly in Excel.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The fix I have been using until recently is to use the following TSQL command in my queries.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;">&lt;code class="language-sql" data-lang="sql">&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>&lt;span style="color:#66d9ef">SELECT&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#66d9ef">REPLACE&lt;/span>(&lt;span style="color:#66d9ef">REPLACE&lt;/span>(&lt;span style="color:#f92672">@&lt;/span>str, CHAR(&lt;span style="color:#ae81ff">13&lt;/span>), &lt;span style="color:#e6db74">&amp;#34;), CHAR(10), &amp;#34;&lt;/span>)
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>&lt;p>This command replaces any line breaks with an empty string. Both Char(10) and Char(13) are needed because you can have different types of line breaks. This is great if you are writing the script from scratch but isn’t great if your are running a stored procedure or your query has a lot of columns.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The answer to this is to use Visual Studio to run your SQL query. In Visual Studio you can write and run queries via Server Explorer and the results produced don’t contain line breaks. I have only just discovered this solution, but so far it has worked and is very easy to do, plus as I do most of my development in Visual Studio anyway it saves me having to open SSMS to test my queries.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Star Trek is back (in 2017)</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/star-trek-is-back-in-2017/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Nov 2015 20:00:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/star-trek-is-back-in-2017/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img class="img-fluid" alt="3f448330857e4ca7ba40ab5465a3c2cb62cdb98c" src="https://storageaccountblog9f5d.blob.core.windows.net/blazor/wp-content/uploads/2015/11/3f448330857e4ca7ba40ab5465a3c2cb62cdb98c.png?resize=620%2C260" loading="lazy"
/>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As you have probably heard Star Trek is coming back to TV. I recently joined with the Sci Fi Waffle podcast to discuss.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sci Fi Waffle: Episode 12 – STAR TREK IS BACK!!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In this episode we discuss the great news that Star Trek IS BACK!!.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Shawn and I are joined again by James Roberts and TrekMates News feed Editor Simon Foster to speculate about the announcement of a new Star Trek TV series due to debut in January 2017.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>James can be found on our sister podcast &lt;a href="http://www.trekmate.org.uk/category/the-battle-bridge/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">The Battle Bridge&lt;/a>
and Simon can be found on Twitter &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/funkysi1701" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">@funkysi1701&lt;/a>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To listen go &lt;a href="http://www.trekmate.org.uk/sci-fi-waffle-episode-11-star-trek-is-back/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">http://www.trekmate.org.uk/sci-fi-waffle-episode-11-star-trek-is-back/&lt;/a>
, to leave feedback go &lt;a href="http://forum.trekmatefamily.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">http://forum.trekmatefamily.com/&lt;/a>
&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Runaway SQL Log growth</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/runaway-sql-log-growth/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Jun 2015 20:00:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/runaway-sql-log-growth/</guid><description>&lt;p>Today is my day off, but I wake up and have a quick look at &lt;a href="https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/i-love-nagios/">nagios&lt;/a>
to see if there is anything I need to worry about. Yes there is, SQL Server has run out of disk space on its data disk.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I race downstairs and VPN onto the server to find out what has happened. One of my monitoring databases has had runaway log growth and is over 80Gb is size.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;">&lt;code class="language-sql" data-lang="sql">&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>BACKUP LOG [DBName] &lt;span style="color:#66d9ef">WITH&lt;/span> TRUNCATE_ONLY
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>DBCC SHRINKFILE(&lt;span style="color:#e6db74">&amp;#39;DBName_Log&amp;#39;&lt;/span>)
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>&lt;p>Free disk space is back to normal, all users will be unaware of the problem and everything is fine again. I create a daily job that runs the above code, that way it should stay a manageable size.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Next I need to find out why it happened and to prevent it happening again in the future (Next time I have a day off I want to lie in!)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I check the SQL logs and notice&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKUP LOG WITH TRUNCATE_ONLY or WITH NO_LOG is deprecated. The simple recovery model should be used to automatically truncate the transaction log.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Then I remember what I have done to cause this issue. I have a separate disk for my backup files and earlier in the week I noticed this disk was filling up, a large amount of space was taken up by transactional backup files. I thought I don’t need to backup the transactions for this non critical database, I will just do a full backup at the start of everyday.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>However what I forgot is that a transactional backup keeps the log file under control, once this backup was stopped the log file grew uncontrollably. The answer, change the database from FULL mode to SIMPLE.&lt;a href="https://storageaccountblog9f5d.blob.core.windows.net/blazor/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/image002.png" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">&lt;img class="img-fluid" alt="image002" src="https://storageaccountblog9f5d.blob.core.windows.net/blazor/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/image002-300x270.png?resize=300%2C270" loading="lazy"
/>
&lt;/a>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is my understanding of how backups work in FULL mode. A full backup is done at the start of the day which resets the log file, then changes in the database are stored in the log file, this is backed up into a transactional backup and the log file gets reset. If you have regular transactional backups throughout the day the log file doesn’t grow too much, however with no transactional backups your log file contains an entire days worth of changes and so for a monitoring database this could be quite large.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In SIMPLE mode you can’t do transactional backups and the log doesn’t grow uncontrollably. This shouldn’t be used for production databases as if there is a problem you could loose data.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Azure Traffic Manager</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/azure-traffic-manager/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Mar 2015 20:00:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/azure-traffic-manager/</guid><description>&lt;p>I have spent most of the day tweaking my Azure websites. Lots of fun!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Last week unfortunately Azure had some problems and many websites that were running in the North Europe data centre were unavailable for several hours. And you guessed it my websites were hosted here.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>All hosting providers are going to have downtime from time to time and this is just something you have to take on the chin. The important thing to do in times like these is communicate with your customers about what is going on and that you are doing everything you can to restore service.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>However Azure has some amazing features that you can configure to help manage when downtime occurs.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Azure is Microsoft’s global cloud platform. And it really is global, there are data centres in North Europe, West Europe, Brazil, Japan, two more in Asia and five in the US. In the event of problems it is highly unlikely that more than one of these would go down at once. If all of these are unavailable, I expect the planet earth is facing some kind of cataclysmic event and the fact that my website is down is not a priority.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://storageaccountblog9f5d.blob.core.windows.net/blazor/wp-content/uploads/2015/03/IC750592.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">&lt;img class="img-fluid" alt="IC750592" src="https://storageaccountblog9f5d.blob.core.windows.net/blazor/wp-content/uploads/2015/03/IC750592.jpg?resize=662%2C347" loading="lazy"
/>
&lt;/a>
To take advantage of these multiple data centres, Azure has something called a Traffic Manager.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Traffic Manager has various settings but I am using it in failover mode. This means that if one website goes down, the next one is used.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>All you need to do is create a traffic manager, add two or more websites to it (called endpoints) and choose a page that needs to be monitored so Azure knows which websites are up and which are down.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you are using SSL or custom domain names, there are a few extra steps you need to do. Your custom domain name needs pointing at the traffic manager, not the individual websites. The websites themselves have three domain names, the traffic manager address, the azure address and the custom domain name. The SSL certificate can then be assigned to each website that you have added to the traffic manager.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That was easy wasn’t it, and now if a website goes down traffic manager will use the next one. While testing this, the transition to the next website was almost immediate. I did notice that if you had a browser showing the website open during a problem you sometimes got an error page, I think this was probably due to browser caching, reopening a tab or browser fixed this issue.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Tidying my desktop</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/tidying-my-desktop/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Mar 2015 20:00:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/tidying-my-desktop/</guid><description>&lt;p>My desktop is always a mess. I constantly download files there and forget all about them.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Every now and then I copy files into sub directories, so my desktop looks sane for a day or two before it gets out of control again.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Why don’t I write a script that I can schedule to do this for me. Then my desktop will always be tidy.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I have written a few simple batch scripts, but of course the best scripting language out there at the moment is PowerShell. Lets use that.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Windows provides a nice little utility for writing scripts called the Windows PowerShell ISE, so let&amp;rsquo;s start by loading that up.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>PS has lots of help included to help you, just run &lt;strong>Get-Help [name of ps command]&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To move files you can use &lt;strong>Move-Item&lt;/strong> which works very similar to copy, specify source and destination. In my case I moved files based on their file extension.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Move-Item *.pdf folder&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now all I need to do is schedule this script to run either every day or so, or maybe every time I login or switch my computer on.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>PowerShell can do lots more interesting things which hopefully I will blog about soon.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Source Code for Game of Life</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/source-code-for-game-of-life/</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2015 09:00:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/source-code-for-game-of-life/</guid><description>&lt;p>Last week I blogged about the Game of Life.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Well it took some searching through dead hard drives and old USB storage but I found the program I wrote, and better than that I have figured out how to turn it back into source code.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The file date is November 2004 and the source code has no comments so I don’t know what was going through my head when I wrote it, or even what some of it does.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To view the source code download &lt;a href="https://storageaccountblog9f5d.blob.core.windows.net/blazor/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/Life.src_.zip" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Life.src&lt;/a>
, to download the finished program download &lt;a href="https://storageaccountblog9f5d.blob.core.windows.net/blazor/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/Life.zip" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Life&lt;/a>
.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img class="img-fluid" alt="Life" src="https://storageaccountblog9f5d.blob.core.windows.net/blazor/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/Life.jpg" loading="lazy"
/>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I am actually surprised I was expected the code to be much worse than it was, I am not saying it is good, but I can see more than one method and I can’t see any code that obviously is repeated. I can see some terrible variable names. Note to future self don’t use tmp676_674!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Assuming that I wrote this in 2004 what would I have been doing then? It was before I started working in IT. (Hard to imagine I know!) It may even have been before I started living with Keith, before he recruited me for my first IT role. I think I was probably working as an administrator for Defra at this point.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If we put 2004 in technical terms, it was before I joined facebook, Office 2003 and XP would have been installed on my PC, and probably felt brand new.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>