<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Connect4 on Funky Si's Blog</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/tags/connect4/</link><description>Recent content in Connect4 on Funky Si's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 Feb 2017 20:00:45 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.funkysi1701.com/tags/connect4/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Side Project – Connect 4</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2017/side-project-connect-4/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Feb 2017 20:00:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2017/side-project-connect-4/</guid><description>&lt;p>Hello?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You have probably like me almost forgotten about this blog. Life has got in the way over the last few months, but lets see if I can restart my blogging habit.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img class="img-fluid" alt="" src="https://storageaccountblog9f5d.blob.core.windows.net/blazor/wp-content/uploads/2017/02/Connect4.png?w=639&amp;amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy"
/>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In 2017 I want to start a side project for a few reasons. I want to improve my coding skills and look at things I wouldn’t normally during my day job.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I have been trying to decide what to build. The actual project doesn’t matter too much, it is the techniques I use during build that matters the most. I would like something that I can start off as a windows app and then extend onto the web or mobile apps.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I started off thinking about a Rubik’s cube app, however my initial coding has lead me to believe it is probably too complex for my first app.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Last year I spent an evening looking at Connect 4 during a &lt;a href="https://yorkcodedojo.github.io/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">York Code Dojo&lt;/a>
session. I think this should be complex enough that I can code some logic to efficiently solve the game, however not too complex I get defeated before building too much.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So far I have built a console app that displays via Console.Write() commands, a grid to represent the game, with 0 meaning empty, 1 red and 2 yellow etc. I am currently working on the logic to solve the game, once I have that in a good state I can extend into a winforms app, into a web (MVC most likely) app and finally a mobile app (I have no knowledge about how to do this yet, but something I would like to try one day).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Over the last few days I listened to .NetRocks where they discussed &lt;a href="https://www.dotnetrocks.com/?show=1396" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Progressive Web Apps&lt;/a>
. This sounds like a great challenge for me to aim for. A progressive Web App is a website that automatically detects various properties to give you an app that runs well whatever the state of your internet connection and whatever browser you are in.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I have lots to learn but I can split it down into small sections and I can build something that demonstrates some of my skills.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>