<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>2015-07 on Funky Si's Blog</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/2015/07/</link><description>Recent content in 2015-07 on Funky Si's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 30 Jul 2015 20:00:45 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.funkysi1701.com/2015/07/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Upper Pylon 2 – 1 x 09: The Passenger</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2015/upper-pylon-2-1-x-09-the-passenger/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Jul 2015 20:00:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2015/upper-pylon-2-1-x-09-the-passenger/</guid><description>&lt;p>I recorded another podcast the other week it can be found &lt;a href="http://www.trekmate.org.uk/upper-pylon-2-1-x-09-the-passenger/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">http://www.trekmate.org.uk/upper-pylon-2-1-x-09-the-passenger/&lt;/a>
and feedback about it can be left on the trekmate forums &lt;a href="http://forum.trekmatefamily.com/2015/07/thoughts-on-up2s-the-passenger-or-vantika-x-33/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">http://forum.trekmatefamily.com/2015/07/thoughts-on-up2s-the-passenger-or-vantika-x-33/&lt;/a>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img class="img-fluid" alt="" src="https://storageaccountblog9f5d.blob.core.windows.net/blazor/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/Bashir-Choked.jpg" loading="lazy"
/>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This week on Upper Pylon 2, we are joined by our first UK guest, Simon (aka &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/funkysi1701" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">funkysi1701&lt;/a>
) as we take a look at the Bashir-centric “mystery” episode, “The Passenger.”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When a former prisioner, Rao Vantika (a name you’ll hear COUNTLESS times throughout the episode) is killed, his pursuer believes that the late murderer is not really dead, and continues her investigation at DS9 while an important shipment is scheduled to arrive. Will Vantika reappear, and if so, who will he appear as? Well, if you’ve seen the opening of the episode, it really isn’t all that hard to deduce. But join the UP2 crew as we dissect this little caper.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As always, be sure to leave us your feedback about the episode!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>10 facts about Windows 10</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2015/10-facts-about-windows-10/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Jul 2015 20:00:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2015/10-facts-about-windows-10/</guid><description>&lt;p>Today Microsoft release Windows 10 so what else can I talk about? I like many technology people are very excited today. This version of window is the first that Microsoft have release for free.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img class="img-fluid" alt="" src="https://storageaccountblog9f5d.blob.core.windows.net/blazor/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/Windows-10_Product-Family.jpg?resize=1024%2C576&amp;amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy"
/>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>10 You heard that correct Windows 10 is &lt;strong>free&lt;/strong>. If you upgrade your device to windows 10 before 29th July 2016 it is free and will continue working on that device forever.&lt;/p>
&lt;pre tabindex="0">&lt;code>Upgrade to Windows 10 within the first year and it is yours free, forever.
No subscriptions, no additional costs.
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;p>9 As with any upgrade always backup your computer and any important files before you do anything. Microsoft and any IT expert will tell you this. For a great guide to upgrading see Scott Hansleman’s &lt;a href="http://www.hanselman.com/blog/GettingStartedWithWindows10.aspx" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">blog&lt;/a>
. I have upgraded my laptop without any problems but there will always be exceptions so take extra care.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>8 Windows 10 is the &lt;strong>LAST&lt;/strong> version of windows. I don’t know what this means but I can take a guess.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Typically Microsoft has created a new version of windows every few years. With every new version there has come headaches and problems as people try to make software and hardware work with the next version. Microsoft is instead going to try and release updates and patches to the operating system to keep things up to date.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>However I can see that only working for so long. Eventually Microsoft will make something new but it is unlikely to be called Windows. Maybe it will be something hosted in the Cloud, as they have a really strong presence with Azure which is only going to grow as time goes on.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>7 Windows 10 is available in 7 different flavours.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Windows 10 Home – equivalent to the Home editions we have had since XP. This version is designed for your typical consumer.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Windows 10 Mobile – this version is designed to run on phones and tablets. Unlike previous Phone versions, everything you can find on the desktop OS should be available on the phone (but optimised for the smaller screens)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Windows 10 Pro – this is the version I will be testing with my work PCs. It is designed for small businesses and allows domain joining.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Windows 10 Enterprise – this version is only available via Volume Licensing so not easily available to the typical user but is aimed at larger businesses.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Windows 10 Education – another version that is only available via Volume Licensing but targeted at schools and universities.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Windows 10 Mobile Enterprise – this version is for mobile and tablets in the business world. Standard policies can be applied to all your employees mobile devices.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Windows 10 IoT Core – this is an interesting version designed to run on hardware and Internet of Things (IoT) devices. I would quite like to play with this version on my Raspberry Pi&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>6 Windows 10 introduces a brand new web browser called Edge. For years web developers have hated Internet Explorer, for its lack of support for the latest web standards. Internet Explorer 6 caused many users to migrate away to browsers like firefox and later Chrome and despite Microsoft’s best effort with the later versions people have not moved back. Edge is an attempt at a fresh start.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>5 In 2011 Apple introduced the personal assistant Siri, well now Microsoft are bringing us &lt;strong>Cortana&lt;/strong> the windows equivalent. With Cortana you can ask your computer to do anything, set reminders, search the internet, answer questions, anything. With advanced voice recognition you can speak as well as type your questions. Cortana is now part of Windows 10.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img class="img-fluid" alt="" src="https://storageaccountblog9f5d.blob.core.windows.net/blazor/wp-content/uploads/2015/05/win10.jpg?resize=300%2C181&amp;amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy"
/>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>4 Windows 10 brings back the start menu. The start menu you have always used to access programs works the same but features of the windows 8 start screen have been incorporated into it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>3 Windows 10 is more &lt;strong>secure&lt;/strong>. Security patches are frequently released for all operating systems, but windows 10 has been designed with security in mind. For businesses there are options to completely lock down your users environment only allowing ‘white listed’ programs to run.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2 &lt;strong>Continuum&lt;/strong> is one of the most revolutionary things about Windows 10. Continuum is the notion that one computing experience is continued regardless of the device used or the location. Continuum will automatically adjust your screen to make the best use of its size. Tablets and phones have the tiled view and start screen, if you connect a keyboard and monitor it will behave like a full blown PC. This is mind bending, that a phone running windows 10 can do as much as your laptop.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 Today I am off to a Windows 10 launch event where I expect many of these features will be discussed and most likely many more.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Writing better Git commit messages</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2015/writing-better-git-commit-messages/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Jul 2015 20:00:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2015/writing-better-git-commit-messages/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img class="img-fluid" alt="" src="https://storageaccountblog9f5d.blob.core.windows.net/blazor/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/git_commit.png?w=439&amp;amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy"
/>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I always use source control for my coding changes, however some of my commit messages leave something to be desired.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I always try to write a commit message but I often think that the change themselves should be enough to indicate what I did. I also don’t need to include who made the change or the time and date and that gets included automatically.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Here are some tips I have found that may help me in the future.&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Ask yourself why you are making this change. The Who, When and What are already being covered so it is only the why that needs including in the commit message.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>If your commit breaks something or causes side affects or a new dependency this should be included in the commit message. If your commit breaks functionality, consider if you really need to commit it yet, maybe only commit once fixed?&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>If your commit includes a long list of changes consider if the commit needs splitting into several commits. It is easy to only commit one or two files write a specific commit message and then commit the rest of the changes separately.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Consider including a subject for larger commits. The following comes from the git manual.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;pre tabindex="0">&lt;code>Though not required, it’s a good idea to begin the commit message with a single short
(less than 50 character) line summarizing the change, followed by a blank line and then
a more thorough description. The text up to the first blank line in a commit message
is treated as the commit title, and that title is used throughout Git.
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;ol start="5">
&lt;li>If you use a subject follow the following conventions:&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Limit of 50 characters&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Start with a capital letter&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Do not end with a full stop&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Use the imperative mood i.e. write as if issuing a command&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>My Love/Hate Relationship with Microsoft Access</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2015/microsoft-access/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Jul 2015 20:00:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2015/microsoft-access/</guid><description>&lt;p>For historical reasons I use Microsoft Access as the front-end for all my line of business databases.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Access allows you to create an ADP file that can connect to your SQL Server database. However Office has dropped support for this, so the last version of office that I can use is Office 2010.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Before I start hating on Access there are some good things about the platform. Users with very little knowledge can create a database fairly quickly. Development time is also fairly low as it doesn’t take long to create a new form, and add a few buttons which open different reports.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For the last 5 years or so I have built a range of different forms in Access, (and even if I do say so myself), I have got quite good at creating forms that users can be more productive with. Access has the concept of a subform which is a form embedded in a form, each form can be connected to a different query and can be connected to each other so it is relatively easy to create something quite powerful.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Access report are an easy way to create professional looking reports that can be sent out to clients, or used by management and they also have the concept of subreports, (same as subforms but embedded in a report), this means you don’t have to write one query to pull back every piece of data that shows up in a report.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>VBA or Visual Basic for Access allows you easily do things programmatically, like run something if something is selected or a button is clicked. This is not the easiest programming language to work with, however once you have used it for a while you get used to its quirks. My favourite function is IIF, the syntax is fairly simple IIF(expr, truepart, falsepart), if expr evaluates to true the truepart is executed (executed can be as simple as displaying certain text in certain conditions), if it is false the falsepart is executed, and you can also chain them together which I have done to produce something very complex looking.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now for the negative side of things. Access creates a binary ADP file, binary files can not be version controlled in git or subversion. This is a big problem as I want to keep track of every change I make. It also means that branching or working with others on big projects is also difficult.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>One work around I have found to this problem is &lt;a href="https://accesssvn.codeplex.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">AccessSVN&lt;/a>
. This program takes an ADP and creates text files of every form and report. It also can create an ADP from these files as well, however I have had varying success with this feature so I prefer to just create the text files if possible. What I do after I have made a change to the ADP is to run AccessSVN, create text files and commit these to source control. You can then see what controls have been changed or added. It also helps with bugs as I have found that sometimes while testing access will apply a filter to a form, which will break things if deployed, which is very annoying.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Access can only do what access was designed to do. There are some advanced features that we would like to add to our databases. Things like sending emails or uploading reports to a website. This is not Access fault as it was never designed to be able to do such things but I am often asked about what is possible.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>End of support for Office 2010 is approaching and I have plans to stop using Access but until then I need to keep supporting our existing front ends.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Things to know before working on your database</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2015/things-to-know-before-working-on-your-databasethings-to-know-before-working-on-your-database/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Jul 2015 20:00:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2015/things-to-know-before-working-on-your-databasethings-to-know-before-working-on-your-database/</guid><description>&lt;p>I recently saw this blog &lt;a href="http://www.brentozar.com/archive/2015/07/questions-to-ask-before-you-touch-a-database-server/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">post&lt;/a>
by &lt;a href="http://www.brentozar.com/team/brent-ozar/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Brent Ozar&lt;/a>
that I thought I might discuss.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Brent listed 13 questions to ask about a database before you start working with it. I am going to go through these 13 questions and expand on them based on my experiences.&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Is this database in production now?&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>I think it should go without saying that the first thing you should find out is if your database is in production. If its not in production you can do what you like and no one will notice.
I know what databases are in production and which aren’t where I work so I can answer this one.&lt;/p>
&lt;ol start="2">
&lt;li>&lt;strong>If this goes down, what apps go down with it?&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>What apps are running on what databases is a good second question. I have at least one database which has multiple front end apps. At first glance you would think that that these two apps are not connected but they are, I need to be careful with both of these apps to make sure they don’t break each other.
I know what apps run off what databases.&lt;/p>
&lt;ol start="3">
&lt;li>&lt;strong>When those apps go down, is there potential for loss of life or money?&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>This is a difficult question so I will split it into two. Loss of life, my databases don’t control life support machines or nuclear weapons so my first instinct would be to say no. However it is not that straightforward, what if your app allowed contractors to know the location of dangers inside a property they were working in. Once your app goes down, they could have an accident due to lack of information.
Loss of money, this one is more straightforward. Time is money in the business world so any time that your app is down and your employees are not able to work is a loss of money. If your database is linked to an eCommerce site, the loss of money could be extremely high.
I know what affect downtime will have on my users and business.&lt;/p>
&lt;ol start="4">
&lt;li>&lt;strong>How sensitive are these apps to temporary slowdowns?&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>Similar to the previous question, a slowdown can be as serious as downtime for some applications.
Luckily most of my apps are internal only so are not seriously affected by slowness.&lt;/p>
&lt;ol start="5">
&lt;li>&lt;strong>When was the last successful backup?&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>I manage the backup schedule for all my databases so I know exactly when each one was last backed up. When ever I do anything to a production database I will run a backup so I can roll back in case of problems. As part of developing changes I run my changes on a backup of the data. I can script all my changes and repeatedly run them against a backup until I am sure no problems will occur.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img class="img-fluid" alt="" src="https://storageaccountblog9f5d.blob.core.windows.net/blazor/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/uf010206.jpg" loading="lazy"
/>
&lt;/p>
&lt;ol start="6">
&lt;li>&lt;strong>When was the last successful restore test?&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>More important than a backup is testing restoring your databases. If you can’t restore data then your backup is useless. I try to test restoring my backups at least weekly so I know that I can rely on my backups.&lt;/p>
&lt;ol start="7">
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Is everyone okay losing data back to the last successful backup?&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>If disaster strikes you could loose all data between now and the time of your last backup. But all is not lost transactional backups can be scheduled throughout the day, in my case the most data we could loose is 15 minutes. This could be configured to be more or less frequent depending on your data. But remember the previous question and make sure you test a restore of your transactional backups, if you can’t restore from them you will be forced to restore from the last successful backup.&lt;/p>
&lt;ol start="8">
&lt;li>&lt;strong>When was the last successful clean corruption test?&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>Corruption can be a killer if it is not found quickly. If you need to restore to the last backup before corruption occurred this could result in a significant amount of data loss. To check for corruption you need to run DBCC regularly.&lt;/p>
&lt;ol start="9">
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Do we have a development or staging environment where I can test my changes first?&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>If the answer to this is no, then your next job is to setup a development or staging area. Having a development environment makes development a lot easier and I don’t think I could manage to do all the changes I have done recently without one.&lt;/p>
&lt;ol start="10">
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Is there any documentation for why the server was configured this way?&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>I really wish we had more documentation about configurations as it would make finding out why thing were setup the way they are. So unfortunately the answer to this question is No.&lt;/p>
&lt;ol start="11">
&lt;li>&lt;strong>What changes am I not allowed to make?&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>Depending on what your app does, where it is hosted, how quick the changes are needed and many other factors will all restrict what changes you can make. Historical decisions on the database can also affect what changes can be made, if the database has been structured in a certain way, it may be very difficult to restructure it in a more efficient way.&lt;/p>
&lt;ol start="12">
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Who can test that my changes fixed the problem?&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>This is an interesting question, from experience the best people to speak to about problems with the database are the users. If they can show you how to reproduce a problem, you should be able to fix this problem, after that you can probably get them to verify that it has been fixed.&lt;/p>
&lt;ol start="13">
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Who can test that the apps still work as designed, and that my changes didn’t have unintended side effects?&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>This is an extension of the previous question. The main users of your app should be your first port of call to find out if the app works as expected. However exploring side affects and undesired features is something that I would test as part of the development process. It has taken a while but I have constructed a detailed check list that can be used for testing so I know that most bugs can be found before release.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>