<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>SQLServer on Funky Si's Blog</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/tags/sqlserver/</link><description>Recent content in SQLServer on Funky Si's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 23 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.funkysi1701.com/tags/sqlserver/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Updating SQL Server with Docker</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/updating-sqlserver-with-docker/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/updating-sqlserver-with-docker/</guid><description>&lt;p>This morning I was listening to a podcast where the new features coming out for SQL Server 2022 were being discussed. This starting me thinking about what would be involved in upgrading.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Upgrading production environments is complex and there are licensing considerations to take into account. However for non production workloads like development this isn&amp;rsquo;t a problem so lets look at that first.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In the past I have installed SQL Server Devloper Edition onto my laptop, this is fine but I have found that unless you are very careful you may end up with multiple different versions of SQL Server sitting around, and it is difficult to cleanly remove them without a fresh install of the OS.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>However in this day and age, Docker and Containers are king. My current development environment makes use of Docker and has a docker compose file which sets up SQL Server for this particular application, lets take a look.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;">&lt;code class="language-yml" data-lang="yml">&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> &lt;span style="color:#f92672">sqlserver&lt;/span>:
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> &lt;span style="color:#f92672">image&lt;/span>: &lt;span style="color:#ae81ff">mcr.microsoft.com/mssql/server:2019-latest&lt;/span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> &lt;span style="color:#f92672">container_name&lt;/span>: &lt;span style="color:#ae81ff">Sql&lt;/span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> &lt;span style="color:#f92672">ports&lt;/span>:
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> - &lt;span style="color:#e6db74">&amp;#34;5432:1433&amp;#34;&lt;/span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> &lt;span style="color:#f92672">networks&lt;/span>:
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> - &lt;span style="color:#ae81ff">my-network&lt;/span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> &lt;span style="color:#f92672">volumes&lt;/span>:
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> - &lt;span style="color:#ae81ff">sqlvolume:/var/opt/mssql&lt;/span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>&lt;p>This defines which docker image to use, in this case 2019-latest, sets up ports and the name and saves the data on a docker volume.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If we then run SELECT @@VERSION on this instance of SQL Server we get told:&lt;/p>
&lt;pre tabindex="0">&lt;code>Microsoft SQL Server 2019 (RTM-CU13) (KB5005679) - 15.0.4178.1 (X64) Sep 23 2021 16:47:49 Copyright (C) 2019 Microsoft Corporation Developer Edition (64-bit) on Linux (Ubuntu 20.04.3 LTS) &amp;lt;X64&amp;gt;
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;p>What if we change the docker-compose file to use 2022-latest?&lt;/p>
&lt;pre tabindex="0">&lt;code>manifest for mcr.microsoft.com/mssql/server:2022-latest not found: manifest unknown: manifest tagged by &amp;#34;2022-latest&amp;#34; is not found
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;p>SQL Server 2022 hasn&amp;rsquo;t been released yet so there is no docker image for it yet. Try this command again in a few months when it is available.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>OK so what else can we try? What about a downgrade to 2017-latest? Will that work?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>SQL Server 2017 starts but the following error gets logged.&lt;/p>
&lt;pre tabindex="0">&lt;code>2022-02-23 21:41:15.30 Server Software Usage Metrics is disabled.
2022-02-23 21:41:15.30 spid6s Starting up database &amp;#39;master&amp;#39;.
2022-02-23 21:41:15.34 spid6s Error: 948, Severity: 20, State: 1.
2022-02-23 21:41:15.34 spid6s The database &amp;#39;master&amp;#39; cannot be opened because it is version 904. This server supports version 869 and earlier. A downgrade path is not supported.
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;p>Doh we can&amp;rsquo;t downgrade the existing database we have. Probably a good thing really.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Microsoft release regular updates for SQL Server called CU&amp;rsquo;s (Cumulative Updates), you can see above we are on CU13. Is there a CU14 or CU15 we could try?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Update the docker compose to: mcr.microsoft.com/mssql/server:2019-CU14-ubuntu-20.04&lt;/p>
&lt;p>At this point I actually got an error&lt;/p>
&lt;pre tabindex="0">&lt;code>2022-02-23 21:50:20.71 Server Error: 17058, Severity: 16, State: 1.
2022-02-23 21:50:20.71 Server initerrlog: Could not open error log file &amp;#39;/var/opt/mssql/log/errorlog&amp;#39;. Operating system error = 5(Access is denied.).
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;p>This is caused by trying to use SQL Server 2017 but it is easy to fix.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In docker desktop there is a volumes section, find the volume you are using with SQL Server and delete the errorlog mentioned above.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img class="img-fluid" alt="Docker Desktop" src="https://storageaccountblog9f5d.blob.core.windows.net/blazor/wp-content/uploads/2022/docker-desktop1.png" loading="lazy"
/>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now if you retry SQL will start OK.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Repeating the SELECT @@VERSION gives us a new CU&lt;/p>
&lt;pre tabindex="0">&lt;code>Microsoft SQL Server 2019 (RTM-CU14) (KB5007182) - 15.0.4188.2 (X64) Nov 3 2021 19:19:51 Copyright (C) 2019 Microsoft Corporation Developer Edition (64-bit) on Linux (Ubuntu 20.04.3 LTS) &amp;lt;X64&amp;gt;
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;pre tabindex="0">&lt;code>Microsoft SQL Server 2019 (RTM-CU15) (KB5008996) - 15.0.4198.2 (X64) Jan 12 2022 22:30:08 Copyright (C) 2019 Microsoft Corporation Developer Edition (64-bit) on Linux (Ubuntu 20.04.3 LTS) &amp;lt;X64&amp;gt;
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;p>How much easier is this than manually installing updates and rebooting or attempting to uninstall and reinstall SQL Server. As SQL Server 2022 isn&amp;rsquo;t out yet I can&amp;rsquo;t say for certain what issues I may encounter but hopefully it will be as easier as this. And I don&amp;rsquo;t need to backup or restore and databases they are all available as before!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>SQL Server Management Studio</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/sql-server-management-studio/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/sql-server-management-studio/</guid><description>&lt;p>I use SQL Server Management Studio all the time for writing queries, getting data and general SQL development.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img class="img-fluid" alt="SQL Server Management Studio" src="https://storageaccountblog9f5d.blob.core.windows.net/blazor/wp-content/uploads/2015/12/sql-server-2012-management-studio-splash-screen.png?resize=529%2C360" loading="lazy"
/>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I have enjoyed seeing the improvements that each new version of SQL Server Management Studio (SSMS) introduced. One great improvement was intellisense.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This feature saves typing and reduces errors by automatically suggesting tables, column names or other database objects.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A common query that I get asked to write is provide a spreadsheet that gives the information that satisfies certain criteria. This is easy to do in SSMS, you can write the query, click execute and the rows that satisfy the criteria are displayed. These rows can then be easily copy/pasted into Excel or other spreadsheets.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A common data item that gets stored in databases is addresses and addresses often contain line breaks to make the data display better. In the earlier versions of SSMS, when you copied and pasted these line breaks were ignored and the data displayed the same in SSMS as it did in Excel. However in the more recent version, theses line breaks got copied across breaking your spreadsheet and making it hard to see what data corresponded with what.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now I don’t know if this should be described as introducing a bug or fixing one. I can easily argue both sides. If your data contains a line break and you copy this data it should include the line break in the destination, but if it does that it displays badly in Excel.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The fix I have been using until recently is to use the following TSQL command in my queries.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;">&lt;code class="language-sql" data-lang="sql">&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>&lt;span style="color:#66d9ef">SELECT&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#66d9ef">REPLACE&lt;/span>(&lt;span style="color:#66d9ef">REPLACE&lt;/span>(&lt;span style="color:#f92672">@&lt;/span>str, CHAR(&lt;span style="color:#ae81ff">13&lt;/span>), &lt;span style="color:#e6db74">&amp;#34;), CHAR(10), &amp;#34;&lt;/span>)
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>&lt;p>This command replaces any line breaks with an empty string. Both Char(10) and Char(13) are needed because you can have different types of line breaks. This is great if you are writing the script from scratch but isn’t great if your are running a stored procedure or your query has a lot of columns.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The answer to this is to use Visual Studio to run your SQL query. In Visual Studio you can write and run queries via Server Explorer and the results produced don’t contain line breaks. I have only just discovered this solution, but so far it has worked and is very easy to do, plus as I do most of my development in Visual Studio anyway it saves me having to open SSMS to test my queries.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Runaway SQL Log growth</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/runaway-sql-log-growth/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Jun 2015 20:00:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/runaway-sql-log-growth/</guid><description>&lt;p>Today is my day off, but I wake up and have a quick look at &lt;a href="https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/i-love-nagios/">nagios&lt;/a>
to see if there is anything I need to worry about. Yes there is, SQL Server has run out of disk space on its data disk.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I race downstairs and VPN onto the server to find out what has happened. One of my monitoring databases has had runaway log growth and is over 80Gb is size.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;">&lt;code class="language-sql" data-lang="sql">&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>BACKUP LOG [DBName] &lt;span style="color:#66d9ef">WITH&lt;/span> TRUNCATE_ONLY
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>DBCC SHRINKFILE(&lt;span style="color:#e6db74">&amp;#39;DBName_Log&amp;#39;&lt;/span>)
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>&lt;p>Free disk space is back to normal, all users will be unaware of the problem and everything is fine again. I create a daily job that runs the above code, that way it should stay a manageable size.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Next I need to find out why it happened and to prevent it happening again in the future (Next time I have a day off I want to lie in!)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I check the SQL logs and notice&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKUP LOG WITH TRUNCATE_ONLY or WITH NO_LOG is deprecated. The simple recovery model should be used to automatically truncate the transaction log.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Then I remember what I have done to cause this issue. I have a separate disk for my backup files and earlier in the week I noticed this disk was filling up, a large amount of space was taken up by transactional backup files. I thought I don’t need to backup the transactions for this non critical database, I will just do a full backup at the start of everyday.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>However what I forgot is that a transactional backup keeps the log file under control, once this backup was stopped the log file grew uncontrollably. The answer, change the database from FULL mode to SIMPLE.&lt;a href="https://storageaccountblog9f5d.blob.core.windows.net/blazor/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/image002.png" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">&lt;img class="img-fluid" alt="image002" src="https://storageaccountblog9f5d.blob.core.windows.net/blazor/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/image002-300x270.png?resize=300%2C270" loading="lazy"
/>
&lt;/a>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is my understanding of how backups work in FULL mode. A full backup is done at the start of the day which resets the log file, then changes in the database are stored in the log file, this is backed up into a transactional backup and the log file gets reset. If you have regular transactional backups throughout the day the log file doesn’t grow too much, however with no transactional backups your log file contains an entire days worth of changes and so for a monitoring database this could be quite large.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In SIMPLE mode you can’t do transactional backups and the log doesn’t grow uncontrollably. This shouldn’t be used for production databases as if there is a problem you could loose data.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>