<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Elf on Funky Si's Blog</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/tags/elf/</link><description>Recent content in Elf on Funky Si's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 24 Dec 2015 20:00:45 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.funkysi1701.com/tags/elf/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Christmas 2015 with the Fosters</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2015/christmas-2015-fosters/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Dec 2015 20:00:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2015/christmas-2015-fosters/</guid><description>&lt;p>Four months ago James David Martin Foster was born. And he is even more awesome now than when he was born.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img class="img-fluid" alt="" src="https://storageaccountblog9f5d.blob.core.windows.net/blazor/wp-content/uploads/2015/12/20151206_105450.jpg?w=747&amp;amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy"
/>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As I write this James only has a few sleeps (as James sleeps multiple times in a day I can’t put an exact number) until his first Christmas. James is pretty much unaware of what is going on as he is still too young but that doesn’t stop his parents enjoying the season.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>He has lots of Christmas themed clothes which we have been enjoying taking pictures of him wearing. He makes a great looking elf I think.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We took James to his first Christingle service at St Michael le Belfrey at the start of December. A Christingle service is where you stick a candle and cocktail sticks into an orange. James loved it, he already loves looking at lights so loved looking into the light from the candle.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img class="img-fluid" alt="" src="https://storageaccountblog9f5d.blob.core.windows.net/blazor/wp-content/uploads/2015/12/12333053_10153912153609155_79017677_o.jpg?resize=168%2C300&amp;amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy"
/>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Another Christmas activity we did this year as a family was to appear in a nativity. St Michael le Belfrey every Christmas hold a cafe to tell people the good news about Christmas and they have a nativity outside which includes donkeys. Don’t we make a great holy family. (Excuse the coffee cups but it was cold.)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Me and James’s mummy have gone a bit crazy with buying him presents, we have both got him lots of things to open on Christmas morning (or more likely mummy/daddy will do the opening)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>James also has three Christmas days to look forward to, with different sides of the family each no doubt with him as the centre of attention.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Exciting times. Happy Christmas everyone, make yours as special as ours.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img class="img-fluid" alt="" src="https://storageaccountblog9f5d.blob.core.windows.net/blazor/wp-content/uploads/2015/12/12309579_10153809916077792_2703731936729335666_o.jpg?resize=225%2C300&amp;amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy"
/>
&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>