<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Conference on Funky Si's Blog</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/tags/conference/</link><description>Recent content in Conference on Funky Si's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2019 20:00:45 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.funkysi1701.com/tags/conference/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Microsoft Ignite | The Tour – London</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2019/microsoft-ignite-the-tour-london/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2019 20:00:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2019/microsoft-ignite-the-tour-london/</guid><description>&lt;p>I have just spent the first day at the conference Microsoft Ignite | The Tour.
&lt;img class="img-fluid" alt="Alt Text" src="https://www.funkysi1701.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/D0UTj08XgAEo1YJ.jpg?fit=662%2C440&amp;amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy"
/>
The conference was free I just needed to arrange travel and accommodation. Microsoft have really looked after me and all the other guests, breakfast and lunch has been provided, I got a free t-shirt, coffee (or tea) all day plus a beer or glass of wine to end the day. And that’s before you collect any free stuff the vendors are giving away.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The first session was Designing resilient cloud applications with &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/CodeMillMatt" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Matt Soucoup&lt;/a>
and talked about some cloud technologies like Azure key vault and serving static files from blob storage. Unfortunately this had a few technical issues with the demos. I think it was just connectivity with the MongoDB backend but this slightly spoiled the session. As this was the only technical problem I noticed all day I can let it pass.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Next was a session on Azure DevOps mainly build and release pipelines called Deploying your application faster and safer with &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/bbenz" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Brian Benz&lt;/a>
. A lot of this I knew but good to reinforce I am doing things correctly.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Next was a session on Application Insights called Detecting application anomalies with Telemetry with Matt Soucoup.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Probably the most useful session was on Docker and Kubernetes called Integrate containers and Kubernetes into your Azure DevOps build and release model with &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/crad77" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Marco De Sanctis&lt;/a>
. Going to spend some time looking through the examples from this session.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A session on Serverless covered Azure Functions, Azure Logic apps and the other Azure Serverless offerings. Investing in Serverless: less servers, more code with &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/simona_cotin" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Simona Cotin&lt;/a>
.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Lastly was a panel discussion on the changes facing IT Pros and SysAdmins. What is the future of the IT Pro in a DevOps &amp;amp; Cloudy world? with &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/jenstirrup" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Jennifer Stirrup&lt;/a>
, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/bakionur" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Baki Onur Okutucu&lt;/a>
, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/AmyKateNicho" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Amy Boyd&lt;/a>
and &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/TheOpsMgr" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Stephen Thair&lt;/a>
. Should they learn to code, how should they make sure they keep up.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Tomorrow I have a loads more sessions, including ones about mental health, Azure pipelines, more Kubernetes stuff and dealing with failure.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>