<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Authentication on Funky Si's Blog</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/tags/authentication/</link><description>Recent content in Authentication on Funky Si's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 03 Mar 2016 20:00:45 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.funkysi1701.com/tags/authentication/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Trying Out Azure Active Directory</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2016/trying-out-azure-active-directory/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Mar 2016 20:00:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2016/trying-out-azure-active-directory/</guid><description>&lt;p>One of my plans is to create new MVC Webapps for my companies databases. Once I publish these I will need to secure them so only staff have access.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The traditional way to do this would be insert membership tables into my database. The user then has to remember another username and password and I have to secure the storage of these credentials. Lots of work for everyone.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img class="img-fluid" alt="" src="https://storageaccountblog9f5d.blob.core.windows.net/blazor/wp-content/uploads/2016/03/arch.png?w=600&amp;amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy"
/>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There is a better way by using Azure Active Directory. You have probably heard of Active Directory, if you are a SysAdmin you probably use it all the time to manage your corporate users and computers. Azure Active Directory is an extension of this into the Cloud.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I have blogged in the past about using Azure but this is the first time I have tried connecting my internal domain to Azure. There is a &lt;a href="https://vlabs.holsystems.com/vlabs/technet?eng=VLabs&amp;amp;auth=external&amp;amp;src=vlabs&amp;amp;altadd=true&amp;amp;labid=13535" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Virtual Lab&lt;/a>
which helped me try out some of these ideas.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The first thing I did was to create a new Directory in Azure. I did this via the old portal (&lt;a href="https://manage.windowsazure.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">manage.windowsazure.com&lt;/a>
) it might be possible via the new portal but I don’t know how yet.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Click New, select App Services &amp;gt; Active Directory &amp;gt; Directory and select Custom Create. Select Create new directory, give it a name and a domain name and select a region from the drop down. Then add a Global Admin for this directory.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There is a tool called &lt;a href="https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/download/details.aspx?id=47594" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Azure Active Directory Connect&lt;/a>
. Download and Install this with express settings on one of your domain controllers. You need to specify a domain admin account to access your domain and the Azure Global Admin account you just created.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>At this point I went to bed so I am not sure how long it tool to sync all the domain information but by morning it was all showing in the users list on Azure.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>All my user accounts are showing with a @contoso.onmicrosoft.com, it is possible to use custom domains but I haven’t figured out that step yet. I made a change in my Active Directory and a while later that change was showing in Azure AD.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So now what? Open up Visual Studio and see if I can use Azure to Authenticate.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I selected to create a new MVC web project and clicked the change authenticate option. One of the options was Work and School Accounts, I then selected Cloud Single Organization and entered contoso.onmicrosoft.com. I then ran this app and it authenticated using Azure using my domain password. Really impressed at how easy that was.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The app then shows up on Azure in the old portal. In Applications you can see a list of which users have access to your app and configure few other app related settings.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is a long way off being useful in my actual app, but it shows that the basics of what I am trying to do does work. Anyone done anything similar with Azure AD? How did you get on?&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>