<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>LeedsSharp on Funky Si's Blog</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/tags/leedssharp/</link><description>Recent content in LeedsSharp on Funky Si's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 Jun 2015 20:00:45 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.funkysi1701.com/tags/leedssharp/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Sudoku Challenge</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2015/sudoku-challenge/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Jun 2015 20:00:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2015/sudoku-challenge/</guid><description>&lt;p>Last night I went to a Code Dojo at Leeds Sharp (the coding user group I have started going to). A Code Dojo is a programming challenge that people work on usually in pairs.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The challenge that we worked on was to code a solution to the puzzle game Sudoku. The code we worked with can be found on github.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img class="img-fluid" alt="" src="https://storageaccountblog9f5d.blob.core.windows.net/blazor/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/2000px-Sudoku-by-L2G-20050714.svg_.png?resize=660%2C660&amp;amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy"
/>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I don’t know much about Sudoku but the game goes like this. You start with a 9×9 grid, and the idea is to fill in all the missing numbers.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Each Row can only use each digit 1 to 9 once, each column can only use each digit 1 to 9 once and each subgrid (3×3) can only use each digit once.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I worked with Richard one of the Leeds Sharp organisers, we started by trying to loop through each empty cell and insert values in a brute force attack, but this approach didn’t get us very far (literally as the application crashed!)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The approach that we needed to use was to loop through calculating possible values.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It was only when I sat down at this dojo did I realise how much I still have to learn, but while talking with Richard about different approaches and different coding structures I started to learn.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>