<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Servers on Funky Si's Blog</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/tags/servers/</link><description>Recent content in Servers on Funky Si's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 May 2017 20:00:45 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.funkysi1701.com/tags/servers/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Office Move</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2017/office-move/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2017 20:00:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2017/office-move/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img class="img-fluid" alt="New Rack" src="https://storageaccountblog9f5d.blob.core.windows.net/blazor/wp-content/uploads/2017/04/20170422_191127-e1493403982560-169x300.jpg?resize=169%2C300&amp;amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy"
/>
For the past few weeks my software developing has been taking a back seat as I planned and coordinated the IT requirements of an office move.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The company I work for has been working out of a converted barn, but as the company has grown we have outgrown the building and for quite a while it has been a real squeeze to get everyone in. We now have a shiny new offices with plenty of room for growth.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It was at the start of the year when I first started getting involved with the new office. At that time building work was about to begin. The office had concrete floors so in order to get network and power points in the floor, channels would have to be cut into the concrete for the floor boxes and cable runs.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>At the old office our servers were in a cabinet in the corner of the room which meant they could be quite loud especially when the fans were going full pelt. Our American owners were supplying brand new IT equipment and we would have a dedicated server room.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Soon a weekly conference call was setup so we could coordinate with the IT people in America and the various different contractors that would help deliver our new office.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>One thing I was particularly proud of was YDS. York Data Services (YDS) is an ISP I have worked with in the past at a previous job and I was able to continue my relationship with them and they were contacted and became our primary internet supplier.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Unfortunately most ISPs have to deal with BTOpenreach who have a bit of a monopoly on getting phone lines or leased lines installed. The initial estimate we were given was two weeks after we were due to move in. It was looking like we would move in and two weeks later we would get an internet connection. We were in the process of getting quotes for a temporary internet connection when BT contacted us and could get us connected up. &lt;img class="img-fluid" alt="New Office" src="https://storageaccountblog9f5d.blob.core.windows.net/blazor/wp-content/uploads/2017/05/18121045_1302238519862436_8711390769620542649_o.jpg?resize=300%2C225&amp;amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy"
/>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Soon afterwards a huge cabinet and two pallets full of equipment was delivered. Two days later a team was dispatched to rack everything up. On the rack we had the following equipment: 4 x UPS, 4 x Network Switches, 2 x Routers (for 2 x Leased Lines from different providers, the secondary connection has not been installed yet), 2 x Palo Alto Firewall devices, 2 x New Servers.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Just prior to our move we had a rack full of equipment but no patch cables, nothing connected up and I was beginning to get concerned that we would not be ready in time.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Thankfully a team was dispatched to help out over the weekend of the move, with the patch cables being delivered only hours beforehand. I worked closely with them and we worked late into the night. By the end of the Friday night our domain controller had been moved and its IP address updated. DHCP scopes had been setup for the new network. Once that was done we could get the WiFi points connected up (These had already been fitted to the ceiling).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The following day we moved our existing servers and updated their IP addresses and got everything patched up. Furniture started arriving so desks could start being setup and phones connected up. Everything was slotting into place, and for the first time our new office was starting to look like an office.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>By the time it got to Monday the only problem was the phone number had not transferred as requested (something else to blame on BT) All staff could either connect via an Ethernet cable or connect to our brand new WiFi network and had access to all the IT services they had at the old office. Another minor issue was the NAS we used for backups had to be reset as it couldn’t communicate with the domain so no one could login, luckily this didn’t affect the data on it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>From my perspective the move was a massive success considering how complex and how many different people had been involved.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Looking back Ten years</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2016/looking-back-ten-years/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Sep 2016 20:00:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2016/looking-back-ten-years/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img class="img-fluid" alt="" src="https://storageaccountblog9f5d.blob.core.windows.net/blazor/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/10-year-term-life-insurance.gif?resize=471%2C314" loading="lazy"
/>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Next month I will celebrate ten years working at my current job, two weeks after that I will start a new chapter of my life at a new company. Lets take this opportunity to look back ten years at some of the great stuff I have achieved.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="2006">2006&lt;a class="anchor ms-1" href="#2006">&lt;i class="fas fa-link">&lt;/i>&lt;/a>&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>In 2006 I had no IT experience. If you were to ask me where Event Logs could be found I wouldn’t know, and the letters DNS meant nothing to me. I was quiet and shy but hard working. The idea of making IT my career hadn’t occurred to me, this was just a job.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I started off life doing first line support and compiling health and safety files onto CD-ROMs (known by the company as Eurofiles) with HTML. At the time the company had a mix of Windows 2000 and Windows XP, using MS Office 2003. Server wise I can’t remember exactly but I think two domain controllers, a database server and a backup server using a tape drive. At this point in time I don’t believe I did a lot with the servers but I think the servers were running Windows Server 2005.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As time went on I learnt more and more about what the company did and how stuff worked.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="nagios">Nagios&lt;a class="anchor ms-1" href="#nagios">&lt;i class="fas fa-link">&lt;/i>&lt;/a>&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>One of my early achievements was setting up a nagios server. I have blogged about &lt;a href="https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2014/i-love-nagios/">Nagios&lt;/a>
before, but it is a server monitoring system that runs on linux. I am extremely proud of what I have achieved here, no one else in the company had my knowledge of how nagios worked. Initially I even experimented with using a cheap mobile phone connected to the serial port (remember when PCs had these?) to send SMS messages to alert of down time. However this was abandoned when I burned through all the credit on this phone.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Nagios is still used today, and my current team have been shown how to extend the system as the business changes. My philosophy has always been if we have a problem that Nagios didn’t warn us about we need an extra nagios test. These days the nagios web interface is publicly available on the internet so can be checked from anywhere (assuming the office internet is up!) and a mobile app replaces the SMS idea we originally had.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="2011">2011&lt;a class="anchor ms-1" href="#2011">&lt;i class="fas fa-link">&lt;/i>&lt;/a>&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>At the end of 2010 the IT Manager resigned, then the Developer resigned and finally the Lead Developer resigned. I was alone. I was IT Manager. I negotiated my first pay rise since joining the company. I was IT.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Wow things were stressful back then. I had so much to learn but somehow I managed. I learnt how to Interview, yes I have employed some clangers along the way, but also some great staff. As well as internal staff I learnt to deal with contractors. We had contractors to help with our internal systems and also contractors to do development work. One thing I have learnt about contractors is that you will always have to chase them at some point to deliver what you are paying them for.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="server-migration">Server Migration&lt;a class="anchor ms-1" href="#server-migration">&lt;i class="fas fa-link">&lt;/i>&lt;/a>&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Around the start of 2011 our email server started to show its age. Exchange 2003 had a hard limit on the size of its information store and we were rapidly approaching this. Along with an IT contractor I worked to migrate to Exchange 2010, this was a huge project and caused all sorts of issues which we just worked through. Since then I have done other migrations so Windows Server 2012 and also virtualized many servers in 2013.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="bandwidth">Bandwidth&lt;a class="anchor ms-1" href="#bandwidth">&lt;i class="fas fa-link">&lt;/i>&lt;/a>&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>A major limit with our infrastructure has always been the internet connection coming in. For a while we tried to load balance three ADSL connections, but the upload speed was always a limiting factor. It was a major victory for the simplification of our network when we got a leased line installed into our head office, helped by a government grant we gave us free installation. Not content with this I did the same again for our second York office, including the free installation.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="learning-development">Learning Development&lt;a class="anchor ms-1" href="#learning-development">&lt;i class="fas fa-link">&lt;/i>&lt;/a>&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Since I started I have always been learning development stuff. But in the past few years I have learnt a massive amount helped largely by two main things. My boss passing lots of my responsibility onto others and dedicating lots of my time to development tasks, and also the opportunity to learn with our outsourced development team.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="finishing-off">Finishing off&lt;a class="anchor ms-1" href="#finishing-off">&lt;i class="fas fa-link">&lt;/i>&lt;/a>&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>There are a few things that have been ongoing that we have wanted to change since I started which I can’t really take the credit for as they are not complete yet, but I am proud as they may be finished in the next few months.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The company stores calendar information in one giant excel spreadsheet, this is being replaced by outlook calendars.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Our last Windows Server 2003 server and tape drive is being decommissioned. This is the only server that has been running for the entire time I have been here.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The way the company keeps track of work coming in and who does what is being reviewed. Over the years many people have tried to adapt the old database that one of the directors created in Access many years ago. I did a major overhaul recently to delete unused columns and added extra invoicing functionality. What is needed is a fresh system, maybe a CRM can do everything they want. I wish them lots of luck in doing this as I know it won’t be easy but it has to be done.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="2016">2016&lt;a class="anchor ms-1" href="#2016">&lt;i class="fas fa-link">&lt;/i>&lt;/a>&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>There are many other projects and pieces of work that I have done that I am proud of. In 2016 I will leave a stable IT department. All clients are on Windows 10 and using Office 2010. We have virtual servers running Server 2012 and are using some great services from Azure to run our SaaS websites. There are of course things I would have liked to achieve, and things I wish I had done differently but on the whole it feels like the right time to move on, especially now long running projects are starting to conclude.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>If you had £5000 to spend on technology what would you get?</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2014/if-you-had-5000-to-spend-on-technology-what-would-you-get/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2014 20:00:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2014/if-you-had-5000-to-spend-on-technology-what-would-you-get/</guid><description>&lt;p>I listen to the dot net rocks podcast and they ask this question every show. (If you don’t listen then you should!)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I don’t know what my answer would be as there are so many gadgets and cool things that I like the sound of.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I might get a surface pro 3, it’s a tablet with attachable keyboard that’s more powerful than my current laptop. But at £600 it’s expensive so maybe not. Maybe instead I would install a SSD into my existing laptop to increase disk performance.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I’d like a new car with lots of gadgets built-in. A friend gave me a ride in his new BMW and it’s nice. Bluetooth so I don’t have to have an audio cable to listen to podcasts. Parking sensors so no chance the wife will prang it. Built in satnav etc&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img class="img-fluid" alt="" src="https://storageaccountblog9f5d.blob.core.windows.net/blazor/wp-content/uploads/2014/10/google-car.png?w=599&amp;amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy"
/>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>While we are on the subject of cars eventually I’d like a google self driving car as I think Google is a better driver than me. Think about it I drive to a friends I have a drink I sleep in the back seat as my car drives me home. Once all cars are automated I believe the roads will be much safer.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The last thing I would spend on is an intensive training course on development, I would really like to get further in dev and more training would really help. Specifically something that would help solve my current dev problems. I am sure it is possible for me to learn dev with self-study but that requires a discipline I don’t think I have, I easily eat my time up with my current job, wife and other interests.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I recently had £6500 to spend on improving my employers IT infrastructure. That was really hard. It sounds like a lot of money, but it really isn’t.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Once I started looking at the problems that I wanted to solve and what hardware I wanted I quickly used it all up and that was before I factored in license and software costs. In the end I just had to order what I wanted and hope that on a future date I could spend on other areas. I got a super powerful server that I could virtualize almost all our existing physical servers with it I needed licences, which left me just enough to get a NAS for file storage.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>I love Nagios</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2014/i-love-nagios/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2014 20:00:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2014/i-love-nagios/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://storageaccountblog9f5d.blob.core.windows.net/blazor/wp-content/uploads/2014/09/nagios.png" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">&lt;img class="img-fluid" alt="Nagios" src="https://storageaccountblog9f5d.blob.core.windows.net/blazor/wp-content/uploads/2014/09/nagios.png?resize=212%2C50" loading="lazy"
/>
&lt;/a>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You may not have heard of Nagios but it has saved my bacon quite a few times.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Nagios is an open source server monitoring application that runs on many linux flavours.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I can’t remember exactly when I first installed nagios but I am guessing it was sometime in 2007/8. My boss gave me a book about it (which I never read) and told me to create a system to monitor the companies servers.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Nagios is not simple to set up. It relies on setting up various Hosts and services. Hosts are usually physical servers that you want to monitor and services are all the services you want to monitor. As this is a linux program all these can be configured by editing the right config file&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Nagios is very flexible and can be expanded easily with the use of plugins, if you want to monitor something there is usually a plugin available. If you have a dell server running openmanage software there is even a plugin that allows the temperature of your server to be monitored.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you want to monitor windows servers the use of nsclient++ is a real advantage. This is a simple client that runs as a service on your windows server. This allows nagios to track memory, cpu, disk space, performance and services, in fact almost everything that you would want to monitor.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Over the years I have kept a close eye on Nagios and added extra checks as new services were added or problems encountered. A few years ago I dabbled with sending alerts out via SMS message and once I got a smart phone found an app to keep track of Nagios 24/7.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But recently I have started wondering if Nagios is the best way to monitor modern servers like 2012 or remote services like Azure. I want something that is easy to expand as your IT infrastructure expands. Something that relies on running on a linux OS requires your IT staff have a knowledge of linux and you keep that server maintained and updated.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My question is: Is Nagios still the best way to monitor my servers?&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>