<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>2016-08 on Funky Si's Blog</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/2016/08/</link><description>Recent content in 2016-08 on Funky Si's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 25 Aug 2016 20:00:45 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.funkysi1701.com/2016/08/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>DZone</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2016/dzone/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Aug 2016 20:00:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2016/dzone/</guid><description>&lt;p>For a while now I have been sharing some of my blog posts on the &lt;a href="https://dzone.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Dzone&lt;/a>
website.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img class="img-fluid" alt="" src="https://storageaccountblog9f5d.blob.core.windows.net/blazor/wp-content/uploads/2016/08/dzone_02.png?w=400&amp;amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy"
/>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Dzone website allows users to submit links to content and I have been submitting the content I have created on this website. This is how Dzone describes themselves:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>With over 1 Million members, DZone.com is one of the web’s largest communities and publishers of technical content for software professionals. Developers from all over the world come to DZone for the latest and best content to hone their skills and advance their careers.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Well this week I have been invited to join the &lt;a href="https://dzone.com/pages/mvb" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">MVB&lt;/a>
(Most Valuable Blogger) programme. The hope is that more of my readers will find my content from the DZone website.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The DZone team will soon start sharing my content on the DZone website and I hope this will result in even more people reading what I have to say.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If nothing else this is clearly telling me that my blog is making a difference, people are taking note of me and what I have to say. I need to keep going and keep writing articles and be more consistent.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Amazon Web Services Pt 2</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2016/amazon-web-services-pt-2/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Aug 2016 20:00:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2016/amazon-web-services-pt-2/</guid><description>&lt;p>Last time I started looking at Amazon Web Services and how it differed from Azure. I am going to continue looking at what it can do.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="virtual-machines">Virtual Machines&lt;a class="anchor ms-1" href="#virtual-machines">&lt;i class="fas fa-link">&lt;/i>&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Lets look at what you can do with Virtual Machines. I selected to create a new Virtual Machine (or as AWS calls them an EC2 Instance)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>First you choose a name for your VM and then the OS that runs on it. There are 5 main OSes to choose from Windows Server, Amazon Linux and a selection of the most common Linux flavours.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You can then download a certificate to secure your VM.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Like Azure, AWS takes a few moments to create your VM. While I wait I can see that AWS has configured a firewall so only my current IP can connect to it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Once the VM is ready you can download an RDP file. However to get the login details you need to decrypt the password using the certificate you downloaded when you created the VM.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It is interesting to compare the difference in security between Azure and AWS. Azure allows the resetting of passwords of VMs directly from its console, however I suspect that in AWS if you loose your certificate (AWS states they don’t keep a copy of this) you would have to recreate your VM.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Like with the Websites the default name of the VM is much less user-friendly than what you get from Azure. However I suspect there are other options I haven’t spotted that may customise these.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="azure-portal-vs-aws-console">Azure Portal vs AWS Console&lt;a class="anchor ms-1" href="#azure-portal-vs-aws-console">&lt;i class="fas fa-link">&lt;/i>&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>I really like the Azure Portal. It feels like something that has been designed so you can easily access all the options for a specific Azure feature.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The AWS Console probably has all the same options as with Azure however I don’t think it looks half as good, and will take me a while looking through menus to find the equivalent options. Part of this is due to my unfamiliarity with AWS, so will get easier with time.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>