<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Blog on Funky Si's Blog</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/tags/blog/</link><description>Recent content in Blog on Funky Si's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 19 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.funkysi1701.com/tags/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Tips for Developing Yourself</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2018/tips-for-developing-yourself/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2018/tips-for-developing-yourself/</guid><description>&lt;p>For a while I have been mentoring a friend and I thought I might share some top tips I have implemented in my career so far.&lt;/p>
&lt;h5 id="hard-work">Hard Work&lt;a class="anchor ms-1" href="#hard-work">&lt;i class="fas fa-link">&lt;/i>&lt;/a>&lt;/h5>
&lt;p>At school I was told: “&lt;em>Only in the dictionary does Success come before Work&lt;/em>“. Yes it is a bit of a corny saying however it has stuck in my head and it’s true. If you want to get anywhere you need to work at it. For many years I just drifted along, but as soon as I knuckled down and worked hard my career started going somewhere.&lt;/p>
&lt;h5 id="write-a-blog">Write a Blog&lt;a class="anchor ms-1" href="#write-a-blog">&lt;i class="fas fa-link">&lt;/i>&lt;/a>&lt;/h5>
&lt;p>Writing is an important skill that you need to work at to improve. If you commit to writing one blog post a week this will help to improve this skill. Even after 150+ blog posts I still feel I need to improve. Not only that it will also help others learn something from you and shows a willingness to contribute to the community. If a Hiring Manager reads your blog he can see some of the stuff you know or care about and may help give you the edge over more experienced candidates.&lt;/p>
&lt;h5 id="soft-skills">Soft Skills&lt;a class="anchor ms-1" href="#soft-skills">&lt;i class="fas fa-link">&lt;/i>&lt;/a>&lt;/h5>
&lt;p>This is one I need to work on but you should concentrate on the so called “&lt;em>Soft Skills&lt;/em>“. Soft Skills are the skills you have for dealing with others. Are you good at talking to people? Or good at getting requirements out of business owners? If so you have some soft skills, don’t underestimate the value that these bring to a team and keep developing them.&lt;/p>
&lt;h5 id="build-a-side-project">Build a Side Project&lt;a class="anchor ms-1" href="#build-a-side-project">&lt;i class="fas fa-link">&lt;/i>&lt;/a>&lt;/h5>
&lt;p>Start building a side project, it doesn’t matter what it is but start building something. I started building a Xamarin app but I have learnt loads of other connected things while doing this, ViewModels, APIs, Build and Deployment processes, Azure Functions. It also gives you ammunition for things to blog about. If you are short of ideas try solving a problem or rebuild something you use.&lt;/p>
&lt;h5 id="use-your-spare-time">Use your spare time&lt;a class="anchor ms-1" href="#use-your-spare-time">&lt;i class="fas fa-link">&lt;/i>&lt;/a>&lt;/h5>
&lt;p>During the day there are moments you can reclaim for learning stuff. There are lots of &lt;a href="https://www.funkysi1701.com/podcasts">podcast&lt;/a>
which discuss useful development topics, listen to these while driving to work. Subscribe to &lt;a href="https://www.funkysi1701.com/pluralsight">pluralsight&lt;/a>
and listen to this while washing up. Don’t get too concerned with learning everything, however think how much more you are learning than not listening at all.&lt;/p>
&lt;h5 id="im-not-ready">I’m not ready!&lt;a class="anchor ms-1" href="#im-not-ready">&lt;i class="fas fa-link">&lt;/i>&lt;/a>&lt;/h5>
&lt;p>We are never ready to take that next step, it is so easy to make excuses like I need to learn x, or know y. The only way to know if you are ready is to try and to keep trying. Iterate as you go so you keep improving yourself. If you wait before you start trying you will end up waiting forever. If you start trying now you will make some small progress and have a better idea of what you need to do to achieve your goals.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Automation of the Promotion of my Blog</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2017/automation-promotion/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2017 20:00:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2017/automation-promotion/</guid><description>&lt;p>I would like to automate the promotion of this blog. Currently to promote this blog on social media I use a few different services.
&lt;img class="img-fluid" alt="" src="https://storageaccountblog9f5d.blob.core.windows.net/blazor/wp-content/uploads/2017/04/img-buffer-illustration-hub-960@2x.png?w=1780&amp;amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy"
/>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Buffer (&lt;a href="https://buffer.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">buffer.com&lt;/a>
) is a service that allows you to schedule updates to the main social media channels (Facebook, Twitter, LinkedIn and Google+)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>IFTTT or If This Then That (&lt;a href="https://ifttt.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">ifttt.com&lt;/a>
) is a service that allows you to connect different online services. You can send an email when a specific event occurs in your calendar for example.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I have been using a combination of these services to share to social media some of my past blog posts. I then add to my calendar details of my blog posts. Then I use IFTTT to add the event to Buffer, and then buffer tweets on a schedule.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This works great however it is a manual process to add my posts to my calendar. I have been using a spreadsheet to help me generate an ics calendar file which I import into my google calendar. There must be a better way of doing this.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I have written some code that reads the RSS feed of my blog and then shares that to Buffer using the Buffer API. The code I am creating is far from finished however I am trying to use the concepts of clean code to make it as flexible as possible.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I have an interface called ISocial which my buffer code implements, but it would be easy to add a class that implements the same interface but uses the twitter or facebook APIs. My code reads from a specific WordPress RSS feed, but it should be easy enough to adapt to read from a SQL database or any other data source.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I am currently unsure what kind of interface to use for this application. I could create a web page that controls the functionality, or maybe just a windows application, or maybe both of these are complicating things and all I need is just a console application that could be added as a scheduled task.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>