<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Family on Funky Si's Blog</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/tags/family/</link><description>Recent content in Family on Funky Si's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.funkysi1701.com/tags/family/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Looking back at 2018</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2018/looking-back-at-2018/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2018/looking-back-at-2018/</guid><description>&lt;p>As 2018 starts to draw to a close let’s look at some of the highlights from the past year.&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>New Home - I started 2018 with the goal of buying my own home and I managed it. At the end of October I actually moved in but it was months of looking at houses, speaking to estate agents, saving, packing and unpacking. There is more I want to do to my home in 2019 so this is only really the beginning.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>New Job - Another goal was to kick my career up a notch and this happened in June. It has been great working as part of a large team and I have learnt loads, there is much more I want to learn and contribute to so 2019 should be great on that front.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>New Car - Not a goal that I achieved as unfortunately in October I was involved in a car accident, no one was seriously hurt but this was a horrible experience to go through. My car was written off which gave me an excuse to buy a new car.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>See more of family was a goal, I am not sure if I really achieved this. However family have been around loads for us during our move and we do live closer so hopefully I can work on this some more.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Celebrate 5 years of marriage. It hasn&amp;rsquo;t been an easy year for me and the wife due to moving house and all the stress that involved plus with two children she was diagnosed with Postnatal Depression which as a family we are still dealing with. All that said we had a fab weekend away and we so need to do something similar again soon.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Family. 2018 has included many great times with my two boys. It&amp;rsquo;s been amazing seeing them grow, in September we had a thanksgiving service for them and in July we had our annual holiday.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Lightning Talk. This is the only thing I mentioned as a goal that didn&amp;rsquo;t happen, it&amp;rsquo;s on my 2019 list so hopefully I can kick myself into action but with everything else I achieved something had to slip.   &lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>2018 The Story So far</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2018/2018-the-story-so-far/</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2018/2018-the-story-so-far/</guid><description>&lt;p>Remember me? I used to write blog posts but somehow life got in the way. So much has happened this year, lets have a look at my &lt;a href="https://www.funkysi1701.com/2018/lets-see-what-2018-can-do">goals&lt;/a>
for 2018 and see how far we have got with them.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="buy-a-house">Buy a house&lt;a class="anchor ms-1" href="#buy-a-house">&lt;i class="fas fa-link">&lt;/i>&lt;/a>&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>My first goal for 2018 was to buy a house. Well so much progress has been made with this goal.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We looked at a few houses, and have made an offer, had it accepted and are waiting for the last few things to get arranged before we start arranging to move in.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The location we decided upon was &lt;a href="https://www.google.co.uk/maps/place/Thorne,&amp;#43;Doncaster/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Thorne&lt;/a>
. This is about an hour from York where most of our friends are and my wife has lived all her life, and also an hour from where my family live. I have tried my best to balance location and size of property and we think our new home is going to be a good balance but only time will tell.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I have a bit of a mammoth time ahead of me getting everything we own packed up and moved to our new home so wish me luck, but we will get there it is just going to be hard work.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="new-job">New Job&lt;a class="anchor ms-1" href="#new-job">&lt;i class="fas fa-link">&lt;/i>&lt;/a>&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>In June 2018 I started a new job. This was slightly later than I had hoped but I believe it has been worth the wait.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My new job has lots of perks. Finish early on a Friday (1pm), On site canteen, Cool air-conditioned office, Flexible working hours, Part of a big development team.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The main benefit is that I am part of a big development team. I have a huge list of things to learn both in terms of technology and how large development teams function. The team is about to finish the first sprint that I have contributed to. My contributions have been very small. A bug fix here, a tweak of an API there. But the important thing is that I am making a contribution and learning along the way.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I have also started asking questions about deployment and how this could be automated. Something that interests me, especially with the sysadmin and devops background. I have been tasked with learning &lt;a href="https://docs.docker.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">docker&lt;/a>
, so expect some blog posts on this topic in the near future.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="see-more-of-family">See more of family&lt;a class="anchor ms-1" href="#see-more-of-family">&lt;i class="fas fa-link">&lt;/i>&lt;/a>&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>This one I am going to count as a miss. I have seen family a few times this year, but my efforts have been more on the first two items in this list. Hopefully this will change as things settle down.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="celebrate-5-years-of-marriage">Celebrate 5 years of Marriage&lt;a class="anchor ms-1" href="#celebrate-5-years-of-marriage">&lt;i class="fas fa-link">&lt;/i>&lt;/a>&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Me and the wife had a great weekend away to celebrate our wedding anniversary.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="celebrate-my-two-children">Celebrate my two children&lt;a class="anchor ms-1" href="#celebrate-my-two-children">&lt;i class="fas fa-link">&lt;/i>&lt;/a>&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Not happened yet but it is booked and we just need to arrange a few more details.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="lightning-talk">Lightning Talk&lt;a class="anchor ms-1" href="#lightning-talk">&lt;i class="fas fa-link">&lt;/i>&lt;/a>&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>I have made no effort to do a talk and this is going to be a goal for 2019 I think. Most of the reason is concentrating on the other areas above, but also because I am not a natural speaker and I don’t like stepping out of my comfort zone. But I will do it, I just need to wait for other things to calm down a bit first.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="family-holiday">Family Holiday&lt;a class="anchor ms-1" href="#family-holiday">&lt;i class="fas fa-link">&lt;/i>&lt;/a>&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>We had a great week away at the start of July. The weather was really great (and still is) and we had lots of time doing things as a family.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>