<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Family on Funky Si's Blog</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/tags/family/</link><description>Recent content in Family on Funky Si's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.funkysi1701.com/tags/family/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Looking back at 2018</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2018/looking-back-at-2018/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2018/looking-back-at-2018/</guid><description>&lt;p>As 2018 starts to draw to a close let’s look at some of the highlights from the past year.&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>New Home - I started 2018 with the goal of buying my own home and I managed it. At the end of October I actually moved in but it was months of looking at houses, speaking to estate agents, saving, packing and unpacking. There is more I want to do to my home in 2019 so this is only really the beginning.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>New Job - Another goal was to kick my career up a notch and this happened in June. It has been great working as part of a large team and I have learnt loads, there is much more I want to learn and contribute to so 2019 should be great on that front.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>New Car - Not a goal that I achieved as unfortunately in October I was involved in a car accident, no one was seriously hurt but this was a horrible experience to go through. My car was written off which gave me an excuse to buy a new car.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>See more of family was a goal, I am not sure if I really achieved this. However family have been around loads for us during our move and we do live closer so hopefully I can work on this some more.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Celebrate 5 years of marriage. It hasn&amp;rsquo;t been an easy year for me and the wife due to moving house and all the stress that involved plus with two children she was diagnosed with Postnatal Depression which as a family we are still dealing with. All that said we had a fab weekend away and we so need to do something similar again soon.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Family. 2018 has included many great times with my two boys. It&amp;rsquo;s been amazing seeing them grow, in September we had a thanksgiving service for them and in July we had our annual holiday.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Lightning Talk. This is the only thing I mentioned as a goal that didn&amp;rsquo;t happen, it&amp;rsquo;s on my 2019 list so hopefully I can kick myself into action but with everything else I achieved something had to slip.   &lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>2018 The Story So far</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2018/2018-the-story-so-far/</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2018/2018-the-story-so-far/</guid><description>&lt;p>Remember me? I used to write blog posts but somehow life got in the way. So much has happened this year, lets have a look at my &lt;a href="https://www.funkysi1701.com/2018/lets-see-what-2018-can-do">goals&lt;/a>
for 2018 and see how far we have got with them.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="buy-a-house">Buy a house&lt;a class="anchor ms-1" href="#buy-a-house">&lt;i class="fas fa-link">&lt;/i>&lt;/a>&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>My first goal for 2018 was to buy a house. Well so much progress has been made with this goal.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We looked at a few houses, and have made an offer, had it accepted and are waiting for the last few things to get arranged before we start arranging to move in.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The location we decided upon was &lt;a href="https://www.google.co.uk/maps/place/Thorne,&amp;#43;Doncaster/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Thorne&lt;/a>
. This is about an hour from York where most of our friends are and my wife has lived all her life, and also an hour from where my family live. I have tried my best to balance location and size of property and we think our new home is going to be a good balance but only time will tell.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I have a bit of a mammoth time ahead of me getting everything we own packed up and moved to our new home so wish me luck, but we will get there it is just going to be hard work.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="new-job">New Job&lt;a class="anchor ms-1" href="#new-job">&lt;i class="fas fa-link">&lt;/i>&lt;/a>&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>In June 2018 I started a new job. This was slightly later than I had hoped but I believe it has been worth the wait.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My new job has lots of perks. Finish early on a Friday (1pm), On site canteen, Cool air-conditioned office, Flexible working hours, Part of a big development team.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The main benefit is that I am part of a big development team. I have a huge list of things to learn both in terms of technology and how large development teams function. The team is about to finish the first sprint that I have contributed to. My contributions have been very small. A bug fix here, a tweak of an API there. But the important thing is that I am making a contribution and learning along the way.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I have also started asking questions about deployment and how this could be automated. Something that interests me, especially with the sysadmin and devops background. I have been tasked with learning &lt;a href="https://docs.docker.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">docker&lt;/a>
, so expect some blog posts on this topic in the near future.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="see-more-of-family">See more of family&lt;a class="anchor ms-1" href="#see-more-of-family">&lt;i class="fas fa-link">&lt;/i>&lt;/a>&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>This one I am going to count as a miss. I have seen family a few times this year, but my efforts have been more on the first two items in this list. Hopefully this will change as things settle down.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="celebrate-5-years-of-marriage">Celebrate 5 years of Marriage&lt;a class="anchor ms-1" href="#celebrate-5-years-of-marriage">&lt;i class="fas fa-link">&lt;/i>&lt;/a>&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Me and the wife had a great weekend away to celebrate our wedding anniversary.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="celebrate-my-two-children">Celebrate my two children&lt;a class="anchor ms-1" href="#celebrate-my-two-children">&lt;i class="fas fa-link">&lt;/i>&lt;/a>&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Not happened yet but it is booked and we just need to arrange a few more details.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="lightning-talk">Lightning Talk&lt;a class="anchor ms-1" href="#lightning-talk">&lt;i class="fas fa-link">&lt;/i>&lt;/a>&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>I have made no effort to do a talk and this is going to be a goal for 2019 I think. Most of the reason is concentrating on the other areas above, but also because I am not a natural speaker and I don’t like stepping out of my comfort zone. But I will do it, I just need to wait for other things to calm down a bit first.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="family-holiday">Family Holiday&lt;a class="anchor ms-1" href="#family-holiday">&lt;i class="fas fa-link">&lt;/i>&lt;/a>&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>We had a great week away at the start of July. The weather was really great (and still is) and we had lots of time doing things as a family.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Lets see what 2018 can do!</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2018/lets-see-2018-can/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2018/lets-see-2018-can/</guid><description>&lt;p>It is 2018 so it must be time to think about what my plans and goals are for the new year.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="househttpsstorageaccountblog9f5dblobcorewindowsnetblazorwp-contentuploads201712lego-classic-10703-creative-building-box-yellow-housejpgresize3002c300ssl1buy-a-house">HouseBuy a house&lt;a class="anchor ms-1" href="#househttpsstorageaccountblog9f5dblobcorewindowsnetblazorwp-contentuploads201712lego-classic-10703-creative-building-box-yellow-housejpgresize3002c300ssl1buy-a-house">&lt;i class="fas fa-link">&lt;/i>&lt;/a>&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>This a huge goal for me. For many years I was content with renting and thought owning my own home wasn’t for me, but then I went and started a family and my career started going in the right direction and my thoughts about this have changed.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It is going to take a lot of work to make this goal happen in 2018. First I need to save enough money for the deposit, which is far from easy with a wife and two children. Second I need to get our current place sorted ready to physically move which again won’t be easy. Third I need to make a decision which will affect where I live for the next 25 years. At the moment I am torn between the size of property and its physical location, I need to balance both of these and meet the requirements from the rest of the family.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I do think this is an achievable goal so wish me luck.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="progress-in-my-career">Progress in my career&lt;a class="anchor ms-1" href="#progress-in-my-career">&lt;i class="fas fa-link">&lt;/i>&lt;/a>&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>I need to be careful how I phrase this in case past, current or future employers are reading. I have been working hard at my current role for over a year and I am starting to wonder what is next for me. I am not entirely sure what form this is going to take yet, I have a few ideas on the go and hopefully I can reveal more soon.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Another one that is very achievable, as long as I have it in the back of my mind as the year goes on progress should be made.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="see-more-of-family">See more of family&lt;a class="anchor ms-1" href="#see-more-of-family">&lt;i class="fas fa-link">&lt;/i>&lt;/a>&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>I recently missed a family celebration due to the expansion of my own family and it reminded me that there are aunts, uncles and cousins that I haven’t seen in years and it would be nice to reconnect. Also as my own boys get older and are learning to interact it would be great if they could get to know my own family better.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I don’t have a clear idea how to achieve this one as it takes two but I am going to make more of an effort.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="celebrate-5-years-of-marriage">Celebrate 5 years of marriage&lt;a class="anchor ms-1" href="#celebrate-5-years-of-marriage">&lt;i class="fas fa-link">&lt;/i>&lt;/a>&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Wow how has it been five years since we got married? At some point in 2018 I will take time out from the usual and spend it with the wife away from the boys. I won’t give away more details as I want that to be a surprise.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="celebrate-james-and-edwardhttpsstorageaccountblog9f5dblobcorewindowsnetblazorwp-contentuploads201507james5jpgresize3002c225ssl1celebrate-the-birth-of-my-two-sons">![Celebrate James and Edward]https://storageaccountblog9f5d.blob.core.windows.net/blazor/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/james5.jpg?resize=300%2C225&amp;ssl=1)Celebrate the birth of my two sons&lt;a class="anchor ms-1" href="#celebrate-james-and-edwardhttpsstorageaccountblog9f5dblobcorewindowsnetblazorwp-contentuploads201507james5jpgresize3002c225ssl1celebrate-the-birth-of-my-two-sons">&lt;i class="fas fa-link">&lt;/i>&lt;/a>&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>I don’t want to get my boys christened as I would like them to make up their own minds when they are old enough, however I do want to celebrate all that they are with a thanksgiving service. Not sure when we are going to sort this, however it is my hope that it will be soon.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="family-holiday">Family holiday&lt;a class="anchor ms-1" href="#family-holiday">&lt;i class="fas fa-link">&lt;/i>&lt;/a>&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Not much of a goal but in the summer I will take time out to spend a week away with the family. In previous years we have done scotland, wales and northumberland. This year I am thinking of somewhere not too far away as Edward is still small, but maybe near where I grew up.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="lightning-talk">Lightning Talk&lt;a class="anchor ms-1" href="#lightning-talk">&lt;i class="fas fa-link">&lt;/i>&lt;/a>&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>A lightning talk is a very short talk or presentation given at a conference or user group. Friends of mine are having lots of success talking about what they know about and I think it might be time for me to have a go. I am not a natural public speaker so this is a step out of my comfort zone, however I am going to start small and see what happens. At the moment I don’t know what my subject or topic is going to be, my suspicion is that it will be devops related as that interest me more but watch this space.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Baby Magic and Becoming a Father</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2015/baby-magic-and-becoming-a-father/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Sep 2015 20:00:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2015/baby-magic-and-becoming-a-father/</guid><description>&lt;p>I am pleased to announce the birth of James David Martin Foster weighing 9 lb 12 on 19th August 2015.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Mother and Baby (and Father) are doing well.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img class="img-fluid" alt="" src="https://storageaccountblog9f5d.blob.core.windows.net/blazor/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/james5.jpg?resize=300%2C225&amp;amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy"
/>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I am not a baby person, I hate children and I run a mile from other people’s babies.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But James performed some magic on me and now I will do anything for him. If you have had children you probably know what I am talking about and if you haven’t you are probably like me 24 hours before James arrived.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>During the pregnancy I had been living in denial that I would become a father, despite the wife speaking about nothing else and our home filing with baby equipment. It was only minutes before I first saw my son that I changed.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Due to James’s large size, the birth wasn’t easy. After about an hour of pushing the midwife called in a team of doctors and nurses to help and I think it was at this point that it started to hit me. I am not an emotional man, if anything I tend to repress my feelings but I completely and utterly failed to do that on this occasion. By the time the baby had been placed on my wife’s chest tears of joy were streaming down my face and this continued for some time. Moments after birth James had a tight grip on my finger. His tiny hands were like miniature versions of my own hands.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img class="img-fluid" alt="" src="https://storageaccountblog9f5d.blob.core.windows.net/blazor/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/jameshand.jpg?resize=169%2C300&amp;amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy"
/>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I have been asked what it felt like holding James in my arms for the first time, this happened on the following day. I am not sure if I can put it into words, but a few adjectives come to mind, amazing, great, fantastic, humbling. James depends on me (and his mother) for everything and his existence has put a new spin on everything I do. I want to be there for him, help him learn stuff, provide for him and love him.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I have been working very hard recently, spending my free time writing this blog, learning stuff and doing other work. The reasons for this hard work are now clear, I work so I can provide for James and so I can spend my free time with him.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Before James arrived I had it in my head that his mother would do the majority of the caring for him. This is not going to happen now that I have met James. I want to cuddle him, change his nappies, dress him, hold his hand, take him to school, watch TV with him, stroke his head when he is ill, tell him about my life experiences, introduce him to wine, tell him about girls, help him move home, etc.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I am not saying being a parent is going to be easy. I am pretty clueless about what is in store for us, but already I am worrying if he is OK, trying to calm him down when he is upset and being woken in the early hours.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Anyway only time will tell if I continue being this positive about fatherhood, but so far I am loving it. Normal blog posts will hopefully resume over the next few weeks (or when I have time).&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>