<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Troy Hunt on Funky Si's Blog</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/tags/troy-hunt/</link><description>Recent content in Troy Hunt on Funky Si's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 29 May 2017 20:00:45 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.funkysi1701.com/tags/troy-hunt/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Have I Been Pwned?</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2017/have-i-been-pwned/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 May 2017 20:00:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2017/have-i-been-pwned/</guid><description>&lt;p>Have you heard of the website &lt;a href="https://haveibeenpwned.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://haveibeenpwned.com&lt;/a>
?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Well you should have. Have I Been Pwned is a website created by security expert Troy Hunt that keeps track of data breaches and allows you to search and find ones that affect you. As I write this &lt;a href="https://www.troyhunt.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Troy Hunt&lt;/a>
has tracked 3,752,984,562 pwned accounts from 216 pwned websites.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="what-does-pwned-mean">What does “pwned” mean?&lt;a class="anchor ms-1" href="#what-does-pwned-mean">&lt;i class="fas fa-link">&lt;/i>&lt;/a>&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>pwn means to compromise or control, specifically another computer (server or PC), website, gateway device, or application. (as defined on wikipedia)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Originally, pwn and its variants were pronounced /ˈoʊn/ in the same way as the verb own, the tail of the p being “silent”.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In terms of this site Troy Hunt defines it as:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;quote>A &amp;ldquo;breach&amp;rdquo; is an incident where a hacker illegally obtains data from a vulnerable system, usually by exploiting weaknesses in the software. All the data in the site comes from website breaches which have been made publicly available.&lt;/quote>&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="what-can-i-do">What can I do?&lt;a class="anchor ms-1" href="#what-can-i-do">&lt;i class="fas fa-link">&lt;/i>&lt;/a>&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>As an individual you can search for your email address in Have I Been Pwned, I am in 7 data breaches.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As a person responsible for an email domain you can search and find which of your users are in a data breach.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You can also sign up to get notified of any future data breaches you might get caught up in.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you are in a data breach change your password. If you use the same password across multiple sites or services change them as well. Consider using a &lt;a href="https://www.troyhunt.com/only-secure-password-is-one-you-cant/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">password manager&lt;/a>
so you can have unique complex passwords for every services you use and not have to worry about forgetting them.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you look after a website or service then follow Troy Hunt. Think about security, is your site vulnerable to SQL injection, do you store passwords with reversible encryption?&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="how-worried-should-i-be">How worried should I be?&lt;a class="anchor ms-1" href="#how-worried-should-i-be">&lt;i class="fas fa-link">&lt;/i>&lt;/a>&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Data breaches are happening more and more often. Its not showing any sign of slowing down, in fact I expect there to be lots more in the years to come. However there are things you can do to mitigate the damage of being in a breach.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Use a password manager&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Don’t share passwords between sites&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Regularly change your passwords&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Think of passwords as pass phrases and include spaces between the different words&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Consider what information a company has about you. How worried would you be if this became public knowledge? Consider if you want this online, weigh up the benefits etc&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>