<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>ITAdmin on Funky Si's Blog</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/tags/itadmin/</link><description>Recent content in ITAdmin on Funky Si's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 May 2017 20:00:45 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.funkysi1701.com/tags/itadmin/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Office Move</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/office-move/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2017 20:00:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/office-move/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img class="img-fluid" alt="New Rack" src="https://storageaccountblog9f5d.blob.core.windows.net/blazor/wp-content/uploads/2017/04/20170422_191127-e1493403982560-169x300.jpg?resize=169%2C300&amp;amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy"
/>
For the past few weeks my software developing has been taking a back seat as I planned and coordinated the IT requirements of an office move.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The company I work for has been working out of a converted barn, but as the company has grown we have outgrown the building and for quite a while it has been a real squeeze to get everyone in. We now have a shiny new offices with plenty of room for growth.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It was at the start of the year when I first started getting involved with the new office. At that time building work was about to begin. The office had concrete floors so in order to get network and power points in the floor, channels would have to be cut into the concrete for the floor boxes and cable runs.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>At the old office our servers were in a cabinet in the corner of the room which meant they could be quite loud especially when the fans were going full pelt. Our American owners were supplying brand new IT equipment and we would have a dedicated server room.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Soon a weekly conference call was setup so we could coordinate with the IT people in America and the various different contractors that would help deliver our new office.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>One thing I was particularly proud of was YDS. York Data Services (YDS) is an ISP I have worked with in the past at a previous job and I was able to continue my relationship with them and they were contacted and became our primary internet supplier.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Unfortunately most ISPs have to deal with BTOpenreach who have a bit of a monopoly on getting phone lines or leased lines installed. The initial estimate we were given was two weeks after we were due to move in. It was looking like we would move in and two weeks later we would get an internet connection. We were in the process of getting quotes for a temporary internet connection when BT contacted us and could get us connected up. &lt;img class="img-fluid" alt="New Office" src="https://storageaccountblog9f5d.blob.core.windows.net/blazor/wp-content/uploads/2017/05/18121045_1302238519862436_8711390769620542649_o.jpg?resize=300%2C225&amp;amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy"
/>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Soon afterwards a huge cabinet and two pallets full of equipment was delivered. Two days later a team was dispatched to rack everything up. On the rack we had the following equipment: 4 x UPS, 4 x Network Switches, 2 x Routers (for 2 x Leased Lines from different providers, the secondary connection has not been installed yet), 2 x Palo Alto Firewall devices, 2 x New Servers.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Just prior to our move we had a rack full of equipment but no patch cables, nothing connected up and I was beginning to get concerned that we would not be ready in time.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Thankfully a team was dispatched to help out over the weekend of the move, with the patch cables being delivered only hours beforehand. I worked closely with them and we worked late into the night. By the end of the Friday night our domain controller had been moved and its IP address updated. DHCP scopes had been setup for the new network. Once that was done we could get the WiFi points connected up (These had already been fitted to the ceiling).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The following day we moved our existing servers and updated their IP addresses and got everything patched up. Furniture started arriving so desks could start being setup and phones connected up. Everything was slotting into place, and for the first time our new office was starting to look like an office.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>By the time it got to Monday the only problem was the phone number had not transferred as requested (something else to blame on BT) All staff could either connect via an Ethernet cable or connect to our brand new WiFi network and had access to all the IT services they had at the old office. Another minor issue was the NAS we used for backups had to be reset as it couldn’t communicate with the domain so no one could login, luckily this didn’t affect the data on it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>From my perspective the move was a massive success considering how complex and how many different people had been involved.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Azure Traffic Manager</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/azure-traffic-manager/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Mar 2015 20:00:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/azure-traffic-manager/</guid><description>&lt;p>I have spent most of the day tweaking my Azure websites. Lots of fun!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Last week unfortunately Azure had some problems and many websites that were running in the North Europe data centre were unavailable for several hours. And you guessed it my websites were hosted here.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>All hosting providers are going to have downtime from time to time and this is just something you have to take on the chin. The important thing to do in times like these is communicate with your customers about what is going on and that you are doing everything you can to restore service.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>However Azure has some amazing features that you can configure to help manage when downtime occurs.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Azure is Microsoft’s global cloud platform. And it really is global, there are data centres in North Europe, West Europe, Brazil, Japan, two more in Asia and five in the US. In the event of problems it is highly unlikely that more than one of these would go down at once. If all of these are unavailable, I expect the planet earth is facing some kind of cataclysmic event and the fact that my website is down is not a priority.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://storageaccountblog9f5d.blob.core.windows.net/blazor/wp-content/uploads/2015/03/IC750592.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">&lt;img class="img-fluid" alt="IC750592" src="https://storageaccountblog9f5d.blob.core.windows.net/blazor/wp-content/uploads/2015/03/IC750592.jpg?resize=662%2C347" loading="lazy"
/>
&lt;/a>
To take advantage of these multiple data centres, Azure has something called a Traffic Manager.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Traffic Manager has various settings but I am using it in failover mode. This means that if one website goes down, the next one is used.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>All you need to do is create a traffic manager, add two or more websites to it (called endpoints) and choose a page that needs to be monitored so Azure knows which websites are up and which are down.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you are using SSL or custom domain names, there are a few extra steps you need to do. Your custom domain name needs pointing at the traffic manager, not the individual websites. The websites themselves have three domain names, the traffic manager address, the azure address and the custom domain name. The SSL certificate can then be assigned to each website that you have added to the traffic manager.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That was easy wasn’t it, and now if a website goes down traffic manager will use the next one. While testing this, the transition to the next website was almost immediate. I did notice that if you had a browser showing the website open during a problem you sometimes got an error page, I think this was probably due to browser caching, reopening a tab or browser fixed this issue.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Tidying my desktop</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/tidying-my-desktop/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Mar 2015 20:00:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/tidying-my-desktop/</guid><description>&lt;p>My desktop is always a mess. I constantly download files there and forget all about them.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Every now and then I copy files into sub directories, so my desktop looks sane for a day or two before it gets out of control again.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Why don’t I write a script that I can schedule to do this for me. Then my desktop will always be tidy.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I have written a few simple batch scripts, but of course the best scripting language out there at the moment is PowerShell. Lets use that.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Windows provides a nice little utility for writing scripts called the Windows PowerShell ISE, so let&amp;rsquo;s start by loading that up.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>PS has lots of help included to help you, just run &lt;strong>Get-Help [name of ps command]&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To move files you can use &lt;strong>Move-Item&lt;/strong> which works very similar to copy, specify source and destination. In my case I moved files based on their file extension.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Move-Item *.pdf folder&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now all I need to do is schedule this script to run either every day or so, or maybe every time I login or switch my computer on.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>PowerShell can do lots more interesting things which hopefully I will blog about soon.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>