<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>ITAdmin on Funky Si's Blog</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/tags/itadmin/</link><description>Recent content in ITAdmin on Funky Si's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 May 2017 20:00:45 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.funkysi1701.com/tags/itadmin/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Windows Update – don’t turn it off!</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2017/windows-update-dont-turn-off/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 May 2017 20:00:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2017/windows-update-dont-turn-off/</guid><description>&lt;p>No blog post this week. However why not check out Troy Hunts blog article about &lt;a href="https://www.troyhunt.com/dont-tell-people-to-turn-off-windows-update-just-dont/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Windows Update&lt;/a>
.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img class="img-fluid" alt="" src="https://storageaccountblog9f5d.blob.core.windows.net/blazor/wp-content/uploads/2017/05/ximage7.png.pagespeed.gpjpjwpjwsjsrjrprwricpmd.ic_.OmA4sQpZUA.png?w=464&amp;amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy"
/>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I am probably fairly unique in that I like installing updates whether it be on my phone, my PC or for one of my favourite programs. One of my tasks when I used to work in a sysadmin role was ensuring all windows updates got installed on all servers and client machines. It was a never ending task, as soon as you got almost all updates done, it would be update Tuesday and a new set of updates would be released.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I can think of a couple of times an update got installed that caused a problem and needed to be rolled back. However I have no way of measuring how often it fixed a problem or improved the security of the OS or other software. If you compare the annoyance of waiting for updates to install against having a computer (or worse a server) be hacked or otherwise compromised I think it is fairly clear what you need to do.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As someone who works in IT I feel it is my duty to share the importance of keeping your devices updated. Don’t turn automatic updates off or disable it. It is there to help you and keep your computer safe and secure.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Office Move</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2017/office-move/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2017 20:00:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2017/office-move/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img class="img-fluid" alt="New Rack" src="https://storageaccountblog9f5d.blob.core.windows.net/blazor/wp-content/uploads/2017/04/20170422_191127-e1493403982560-169x300.jpg?resize=169%2C300&amp;amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy"
/>
For the past few weeks my software developing has been taking a back seat as I planned and coordinated the IT requirements of an office move.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The company I work for has been working out of a converted barn, but as the company has grown we have outgrown the building and for quite a while it has been a real squeeze to get everyone in. We now have a shiny new offices with plenty of room for growth.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It was at the start of the year when I first started getting involved with the new office. At that time building work was about to begin. The office had concrete floors so in order to get network and power points in the floor, channels would have to be cut into the concrete for the floor boxes and cable runs.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>At the old office our servers were in a cabinet in the corner of the room which meant they could be quite loud especially when the fans were going full pelt. Our American owners were supplying brand new IT equipment and we would have a dedicated server room.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Soon a weekly conference call was setup so we could coordinate with the IT people in America and the various different contractors that would help deliver our new office.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>One thing I was particularly proud of was YDS. York Data Services (YDS) is an ISP I have worked with in the past at a previous job and I was able to continue my relationship with them and they were contacted and became our primary internet supplier.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Unfortunately most ISPs have to deal with BTOpenreach who have a bit of a monopoly on getting phone lines or leased lines installed. The initial estimate we were given was two weeks after we were due to move in. It was looking like we would move in and two weeks later we would get an internet connection. We were in the process of getting quotes for a temporary internet connection when BT contacted us and could get us connected up. &lt;img class="img-fluid" alt="New Office" src="https://storageaccountblog9f5d.blob.core.windows.net/blazor/wp-content/uploads/2017/05/18121045_1302238519862436_8711390769620542649_o.jpg?resize=300%2C225&amp;amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy"
/>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Soon afterwards a huge cabinet and two pallets full of equipment was delivered. Two days later a team was dispatched to rack everything up. On the rack we had the following equipment: 4 x UPS, 4 x Network Switches, 2 x Routers (for 2 x Leased Lines from different providers, the secondary connection has not been installed yet), 2 x Palo Alto Firewall devices, 2 x New Servers.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Just prior to our move we had a rack full of equipment but no patch cables, nothing connected up and I was beginning to get concerned that we would not be ready in time.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Thankfully a team was dispatched to help out over the weekend of the move, with the patch cables being delivered only hours beforehand. I worked closely with them and we worked late into the night. By the end of the Friday night our domain controller had been moved and its IP address updated. DHCP scopes had been setup for the new network. Once that was done we could get the WiFi points connected up (These had already been fitted to the ceiling).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The following day we moved our existing servers and updated their IP addresses and got everything patched up. Furniture started arriving so desks could start being setup and phones connected up. Everything was slotting into place, and for the first time our new office was starting to look like an office.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>By the time it got to Monday the only problem was the phone number had not transferred as requested (something else to blame on BT) All staff could either connect via an Ethernet cable or connect to our brand new WiFi network and had access to all the IT services they had at the old office. Another minor issue was the NAS we used for backups had to be reset as it couldn’t communicate with the domain so no one could login, luckily this didn’t affect the data on it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>From my perspective the move was a massive success considering how complex and how many different people had been involved.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Runaway SQL Log growth</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2015/runaway-sql-log-growth/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Jun 2015 20:00:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2015/runaway-sql-log-growth/</guid><description>&lt;p>Today is my day off, but I wake up and have a quick look at &lt;a href="https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/i-love-nagios/">nagios&lt;/a>
to see if there is anything I need to worry about. Yes there is, SQL Server has run out of disk space on its data disk.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I race downstairs and VPN onto the server to find out what has happened. One of my monitoring databases has had runaway log growth and is over 80Gb is size.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;">&lt;code class="language-sql" data-lang="sql">&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>BACKUP LOG [DBName] &lt;span style="color:#66d9ef">WITH&lt;/span> TRUNCATE_ONLY
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>DBCC SHRINKFILE(&lt;span style="color:#e6db74">&amp;#39;DBName_Log&amp;#39;&lt;/span>)
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>&lt;p>Free disk space is back to normal, all users will be unaware of the problem and everything is fine again. I create a daily job that runs the above code, that way it should stay a manageable size.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Next I need to find out why it happened and to prevent it happening again in the future (Next time I have a day off I want to lie in!)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I check the SQL logs and notice&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKUP LOG WITH TRUNCATE_ONLY or WITH NO_LOG is deprecated. The simple recovery model should be used to automatically truncate the transaction log.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Then I remember what I have done to cause this issue. I have a separate disk for my backup files and earlier in the week I noticed this disk was filling up, a large amount of space was taken up by transactional backup files. I thought I don’t need to backup the transactions for this non critical database, I will just do a full backup at the start of everyday.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>However what I forgot is that a transactional backup keeps the log file under control, once this backup was stopped the log file grew uncontrollably. The answer, change the database from FULL mode to SIMPLE.&lt;a href="https://storageaccountblog9f5d.blob.core.windows.net/blazor/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/image002.png" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">&lt;img class="img-fluid" alt="image002" src="https://storageaccountblog9f5d.blob.core.windows.net/blazor/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/image002-300x270.png?resize=300%2C270" loading="lazy"
/>
&lt;/a>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is my understanding of how backups work in FULL mode. A full backup is done at the start of the day which resets the log file, then changes in the database are stored in the log file, this is backed up into a transactional backup and the log file gets reset. If you have regular transactional backups throughout the day the log file doesn’t grow too much, however with no transactional backups your log file contains an entire days worth of changes and so for a monitoring database this could be quite large.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In SIMPLE mode you can’t do transactional backups and the log doesn’t grow uncontrollably. This shouldn’t be used for production databases as if there is a problem you could loose data.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Azure Traffic Manager</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2015/azure-traffic-manager/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Mar 2015 20:00:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2015/azure-traffic-manager/</guid><description>&lt;p>I have spent most of the day tweaking my Azure websites. Lots of fun!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Last week unfortunately Azure had some problems and many websites that were running in the North Europe data centre were unavailable for several hours. And you guessed it my websites were hosted here.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>All hosting providers are going to have downtime from time to time and this is just something you have to take on the chin. The important thing to do in times like these is communicate with your customers about what is going on and that you are doing everything you can to restore service.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>However Azure has some amazing features that you can configure to help manage when downtime occurs.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Azure is Microsoft’s global cloud platform. And it really is global, there are data centres in North Europe, West Europe, Brazil, Japan, two more in Asia and five in the US. In the event of problems it is highly unlikely that more than one of these would go down at once. If all of these are unavailable, I expect the planet earth is facing some kind of cataclysmic event and the fact that my website is down is not a priority.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://storageaccountblog9f5d.blob.core.windows.net/blazor/wp-content/uploads/2015/03/IC750592.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">&lt;img class="img-fluid" alt="IC750592" src="https://storageaccountblog9f5d.blob.core.windows.net/blazor/wp-content/uploads/2015/03/IC750592.jpg?resize=662%2C347" loading="lazy"
/>
&lt;/a>
To take advantage of these multiple data centres, Azure has something called a Traffic Manager.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Traffic Manager has various settings but I am using it in failover mode. This means that if one website goes down, the next one is used.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>All you need to do is create a traffic manager, add two or more websites to it (called endpoints) and choose a page that needs to be monitored so Azure knows which websites are up and which are down.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you are using SSL or custom domain names, there are a few extra steps you need to do. Your custom domain name needs pointing at the traffic manager, not the individual websites. The websites themselves have three domain names, the traffic manager address, the azure address and the custom domain name. The SSL certificate can then be assigned to each website that you have added to the traffic manager.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That was easy wasn’t it, and now if a website goes down traffic manager will use the next one. While testing this, the transition to the next website was almost immediate. I did notice that if you had a browser showing the website open during a problem you sometimes got an error page, I think this was probably due to browser caching, reopening a tab or browser fixed this issue.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Tidying my desktop</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2015/tidying-my-desktop/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Mar 2015 20:00:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2015/tidying-my-desktop/</guid><description>&lt;p>My desktop is always a mess. I constantly download files there and forget all about them.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Every now and then I copy files into sub directories, so my desktop looks sane for a day or two before it gets out of control again.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Why don’t I write a script that I can schedule to do this for me. Then my desktop will always be tidy.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I have written a few simple batch scripts, but of course the best scripting language out there at the moment is PowerShell. Lets use that.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Windows provides a nice little utility for writing scripts called the Windows PowerShell ISE, so let&amp;rsquo;s start by loading that up.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>PS has lots of help included to help you, just run &lt;strong>Get-Help [name of ps command]&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To move files you can use &lt;strong>Move-Item&lt;/strong> which works very similar to copy, specify source and destination. In my case I moved files based on their file extension.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Move-Item *.pdf folder&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now all I need to do is schedule this script to run either every day or so, or maybe every time I login or switch my computer on.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>PowerShell can do lots more interesting things which hopefully I will blog about soon.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Laziness</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2015/laziness/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2015 20:00:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2015/laziness/</guid><description>&lt;p>I am lazy, I won’t try and deny that. When my alarm goes off in the morning, I will snooze it for twenty minutes or so before getting out of bed.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img class="img-fluid" alt="" src="https://storageaccountblog9f5d.blob.core.windows.net/blazor/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/bill-gates-quote.jpg" loading="lazy"
/>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In my work my laziness continues. Remote Desktop (or RDP) is probably my number one laziness tool. For those that don’t know RDP allows you to connect to another computer and access it like you were sat in front of it. So I can be sat at my desk and RDP into any other computer in the office including any server. However this laziness tool does sometimes require a bit of effort sometimes, powering on the target computer, logging on locally, making sure the user account you are using is allowed to use RDP.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Writing a script is another example of a laziness tool. I often get asked to do tedious and long-winded task, because I am lazy I will go out of my way to learn how to write a script to do this, so that I can run this script and do this long-winded task in a matter of seconds. There are loads of different types of scripts from database SQL scripts, to PowerShell scripts that can do almost anything on your server.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>PowerShell is something Microsoft are really pushing at the moment, you can even write scripts to create new user accounts, so no longer will you have to remember to tick that tickbox for every new user account. And because PowerShell is part of almost all MS technologies you can link Exchange to Active Directory and you don’t even have to remember the right syntax as PowerShell has a built-in help command to tell you how to run that useful command.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As I am now moving into a more developer role can I continue to be lazy? I sure can. Code should be written once and reused as often as possible and this is one of the features of OOP (Object Oriented Programming).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It can be as simple as creating a master page so you don’t need to recreate the same code on every one of your webpages. Or every time you find yourself rewriting the same code again, you plug it into a method so it can be called again and again.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But of course the ultimate way to be lazy is of course get yourself some staff and spend all day getting them to do everything. If you are lucky they may even try and adopt some of these lazy ideas.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Podcasts</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2015/podcasts/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2015 20:00:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2015/podcasts/</guid><description>&lt;p>For a while now I have been listening to podcasts. For those that don’t know a podcast is an audio file that you can download and listen to, usually about a topic you are interested in. The topics that interest me are obviously Star Trek, Science and Technology and IT stuff. I mainly listen to them in the car when I am driving, but sometimes it will be at home when doing jobs around the house.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I think the first podcast I listened to was &lt;a href="http://www.trekmate.org.uk/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Trekmate&lt;/a>
. Trekmate as the name suggests is about Star Trek, it’s a few guys talking about Star Trek. It’s very similar to those conversations you have in the pub with your mates. Trekmate do lots of podcasts, one for almost every flavour of Star Trek out there, I don’t keep up with all of them, but the ones I listen to I really enjoy.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My favourite podcast that is work related is &lt;a href="http://www.runasradio.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">RunAs Radio&lt;/a>
. If you are a SysAdmin or have an interest in servers or IT you should listen to this. The host Richard Campbell interviews IT experts about a particular piece of technology, one week it will be Exchange, the next Security, and then SQL Server. Often I will learn something that I will want to try out, some weeks I won’t learn something specific but will give be an insight into which way IT for businesses is going. I think it was probably only after listening to RunAs Radio that are started having more of a long term plan for my IT infrastructure at work.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As I have blogged about before I am learning Development so obviously I listen to &lt;a href="http://www.dotnetrocks.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">.NET Rocks&lt;/a>
. This is hosted by Carl Franklin and Richard Campbell (yes the same guy that does RunAs Radio) who talk to developers about code, learning and IT from a more Developer point of view. This is released 3 times a week so is a bit hit and miss sometimes, but most weeks there will be something relevant to me or worth listening to.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A few days ago I did something for the first time, I was a guest on one of the Trekmate pods, TenForward. I reviewed 5 Star Trek episodes. This was a bit of a leap for me as an introvert I don’t like to be the center of attention and I certainly don’t like how my voice sounds recorded. Hopefully when released people will like it and I will do lots more of these in the future. Once it has been released I will put a link up here so you can all have a listen.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Looking back at 2014</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2014/looking-back-at-2014/</link><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2014 20:00:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2014/looking-back-at-2014/</guid><description>&lt;p>As today is New Years eve I thought it would be a good chance to look back over the last year.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img class="img-fluid" alt="" src="https://storageaccountblog9f5d.blob.core.windows.net/blazor/wp-content/uploads/2014/12/tangle.jpg?resize=300%2C256&amp;amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy"
/>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>At the start of the year I finally got agreement for the installation of a 30MB leased line. This was an amazing achievement as I had been really struggling to keep everything working on our ADSL connections and the complexity of the connections was starting to cause problems itself.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>However it was not a smooth process, the site survey revealed a substantial installation cost would be required, however the Council was about to launch a voucher scheme that would give us £3000 off. So most of this was just waiting around for the Council to get things going. By April we had it installed and I have been very happy with the ISP we chose, York Data Service (YDS).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Also during April this year was the end of support for Windows XP and Office 2003. This didn’t impact us too much, mostly due to my constant nagging of the directors to replace our oldest machines. We now only have a couple of machines still running XP and no machines running Office 2003. Most machines are now running Windows 7, I have one Director running Windows 8 for presentations and a few surveyor tablets running windows 8 as well. Like many businesses I am waiting for Windows 10 next year before doing any more substantial replacement of OS.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In May it was decided that I would move more into development work, so I got a new desktop PC and Visual Studio. I am very happy with my new machine (subject to dell fixing a problem later today) So far I have only dipped my toe into development work, this is largely due to needing more time to build up others to do what I do.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In June I made another huge achievement. I got agreement for a new server. This was our first Server 2012 server and allowed us to make huge strides towards virtualizing our services. Once we had this server up and running I was able to decommission two of our Windows Server 2003 machines well before it goes out of support next year.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I am a huge fan of this new server, I have only used a fraction of its memory. Hyper V is really great and I hope to make progress next year into HyperV replication.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Also during 2014 we made huge progress with our clouds software. Within the last few weeks it is running on the Azure platform which will not only make it far easier to expand and create new features it will provide us with cost savings. I am looking forward to learning more about Azure as I get deeper into development.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Wow I achieved a lot didn’t I, on top of this I hired a new IT person and trained him up (still more to do), I have also fixed lots of printers, websites, servers (had a server motherboard die!), and made hundreds of changes to our internal databases.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I don’t know what is in store for 2015. I expect a lots of the same with hopefully more focus on developing in Visual Studio, training myself and my department and getting the last few tweaks into our internal servers.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I would also like to thank everyone that I have worked with over the last 12 months (you know who you are), as you made a lot of what I have just described possible.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Interview questions</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2014/interview-questions/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2014 20:00:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2014/interview-questions/</guid><description>&lt;p>I have done a few interviews from both sides of the table, I’m not very good at either but thought I would have a go at answering my favourite questions.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img class="img-fluid" alt="" src="https://storageaccountblog9f5d.blob.core.windows.net/blazor/wp-content/uploads/2014/10/how-not-to-ace-the-technical-interview.jpg?w=550&amp;amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy"
/>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Describe an IT disaster and what you did to turn it around?&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The question is all about the turn it around bit. I’ve had lots of answers that emphasise the problem rather than what the candidate did to turn things around.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My answer would be: on a Saturday I was rearranging the server room and when I came to turn on our main file server and pdc it wouldn’t boot. My plans for the weekend went out the window it was all about getting this server back up. I tried the usual unplug everything and reconnect still nothing. I rang a friend to get a second opinion and between the two of us we formulated a plan of action. I then rang my director to tell her that I was having problems and what I was going to try. (keeping people informed is an essential skill)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So the server in question was getting power but nothing was happening during boot. The motherboard had died. What I needed to do was connect the raid card to another server so I could copy the data from it to our Nas drive (luckily I had an upgrade plan and this failure had just accelerated it)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A few hours later the data was copying and I could breathe again. I told my director that I had fixed things but there would be minor issues on Monday.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Describe your strengths and weaknesses?&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It wouldn’t be an interview without a strengths and weaknesses question. As an interviewer I want at least one weakness and I want it to actually be a weakness.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My strengths are my problem solving skills, I can look at a problem and investigate what is going on and find a solution. If its a technology I haven’t used before I can read up about it and find out how it works and then use it to solve the issue.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My weakness is my interpersonal skills, I am much better at analysing a computer issue than figuring out why one member of my staff is not performing. This is an area that is improving over the last few years I have taken on more responsibility over people and I am learning more about getting the best out of them.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Technical Questions&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I have never included technical questions in one of my interviews until recently and I think it is a good way to gauge ability. I often come out of an interview unsure how well that person would perform under the stresses of my job. If I have something down on paper it is a good start.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But the personality that comes through during the interview must also be considered as most knowledge can be taught.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A good technical question I have used in the past is write a paragraph explaining DHCP. This question illustrates what their knowledge is like for an essential technology, but it also indicates what their writing style is like. Could the passage they have written be given to a Director or Client?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Good IT people need both technical knowledge and the ability to communicate at all levels, I still struggle to know if someone is good or not and even sometimes if I am any good.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Windows 9 or do I mean 10</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2014/windows-9-or-do-i-mean-10/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2014 20:00:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2014/windows-9-or-do-i-mean-10/</guid><description>&lt;p>Like many systems administrators I watched as the news came out yesterday about the latest version of windows. What would it be like? What would it be called? Would it be better or worse than previous versions?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I was shocked when the name of the new operating system was revealed to be Windows 10. What really!? At first I though someone had tweeted a photoshopped image of the press conference, but no it was really going to be called Windows 10.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img class="img-fluid" alt="Windows 10" src="https://storageaccountblog9f5d.blob.core.windows.net/blazor/wp-content/uploads/2014/10/windows_10_fullwidth.jpg?w=800&amp;amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy"
/>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Windows 10 is the next operating system to be released after windows 8, many had been calling it windows 9 or windows Threshold.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Microsoft has never had a fixed naming convention for its OSes, so should we really be that surprised at its new name.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Windows 1.0 (1985)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Windows 2.0 (1987)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Windows 3.0 (1990)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Windows 95 (1995)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Windows 98 (1998)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Windows ME (2000)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Windows XP (2001)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Windows Vista (2007)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Windows 7 (2009)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Windows 8 (2012)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Windows 10 (2015)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;em>Windows 11 (2021)&lt;/em>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>One reason Microsoft may have gone with with Windows 10 is because they wanted to signify that the coming Windows release would be the last “major” Windows update. What does it mean to be the last major update?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you look at the list of OSes above you will see that between XP and Vista was a huge 6 years, this gap is/has caused a huge headache for IT professionals (me included). Software was written for XP because that is all that was available, when XP moved out of support earlier this year it caused loads as problems as people tried to get this software to work on more modern OSes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If windows 10 is around for a long time we may end up with a similar situation to XP, in that loads of software will run only on it and cause problems if you try and port it to whatever comes next. I am only a trainee developer so I don’t know what is involved with building an OS, but I would imagine there must be things that are very difficult or almost impossible to fix without ripping them out and starting again which is what happens when a new version of an OS is written.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Only time will tell if Windows 10 really is the last version of windows and what will happen to the OS in the future. What ever the case I am downloading a preview so I can have a look (I want my start menu back!)&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>What is the difference between Development and Operations?</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2014/what-is-the-difference-between-dev-and-ops/</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Sep 2014 20:00:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2014/what-is-the-difference-between-dev-and-ops/</guid><description>&lt;p>I want to learn Development and eventually move into a development role. But what is the difference between development and what I already do?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Put simply Development or programming is the creation of new programs, websites or databases.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>IT Operations or System Administration is the administration of existing servers, websites or databases.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I have been doing System Administration since I started my job back in 2006. What you do as part of this role can be very simple like setting up new users or computers to something very complex like upgrading the version of Exchange that the company uses for its emails.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As part of my role I have done a lot of tasks that could be described as development. I have created databases and built new database structures like tables, views and stored procedures. I have also assisted the development department with testing, setting up visual studio, building websites and databases from code.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Can I describe myself as a developer? I would say yes, I have done plenty of work that is development work.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Can I get a job as a developer? Possibly but it would depend on the role. I have many of the skills that developers use, but I have limited knowledge in many areas. What I need to do is concentrate my efforts onto the development work I do and delegate as much administration work as I can so my knowledge can increase.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A Buzz word in IT at the moment is DevOps. I have lost count of the number of times .NetRocks or RunAsRadio have mentioned it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>DevOps is the integration of IT Development and Operations, it emphasises the need for the two departments to work closely together to achieve common goals. In big companies the two departments can pull against each other if you are not careful, but in my case as I do both roles, it would be very difficult for the development side of myself to blame the operations side of myself for a problem.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This I think puts me in a good position, I just need to learn more development and I will make a valuable addition to someone’s development team.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>I love Nagios</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2014/i-love-nagios/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2014 20:00:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2014/i-love-nagios/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://storageaccountblog9f5d.blob.core.windows.net/blazor/wp-content/uploads/2014/09/nagios.png" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">&lt;img class="img-fluid" alt="Nagios" src="https://storageaccountblog9f5d.blob.core.windows.net/blazor/wp-content/uploads/2014/09/nagios.png?resize=212%2C50" loading="lazy"
/>
&lt;/a>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You may not have heard of Nagios but it has saved my bacon quite a few times.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Nagios is an open source server monitoring application that runs on many linux flavours.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I can’t remember exactly when I first installed nagios but I am guessing it was sometime in 2007/8. My boss gave me a book about it (which I never read) and told me to create a system to monitor the companies servers.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Nagios is not simple to set up. It relies on setting up various Hosts and services. Hosts are usually physical servers that you want to monitor and services are all the services you want to monitor. As this is a linux program all these can be configured by editing the right config file&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Nagios is very flexible and can be expanded easily with the use of plugins, if you want to monitor something there is usually a plugin available. If you have a dell server running openmanage software there is even a plugin that allows the temperature of your server to be monitored.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you want to monitor windows servers the use of nsclient++ is a real advantage. This is a simple client that runs as a service on your windows server. This allows nagios to track memory, cpu, disk space, performance and services, in fact almost everything that you would want to monitor.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Over the years I have kept a close eye on Nagios and added extra checks as new services were added or problems encountered. A few years ago I dabbled with sending alerts out via SMS message and once I got a smart phone found an app to keep track of Nagios 24/7.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But recently I have started wondering if Nagios is the best way to monitor modern servers like 2012 or remote services like Azure. I want something that is easy to expand as your IT infrastructure expands. Something that relies on running on a linux OS requires your IT staff have a knowledge of linux and you keep that server maintained and updated.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My question is: Is Nagios still the best way to monitor my servers?&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>