<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>FreeCodeCamp on Funky Si's Blog</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/tags/freecodecamp/</link><description>Recent content in FreeCodeCamp on Funky Si's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2015 20:00:45 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.funkysi1701.com/tags/freecodecamp/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>My Year of Code</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2015/my-year-of-code/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2015 20:00:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2015/my-year-of-code/</guid><description>&lt;p>There is no escaping the fact that we are in 2015 now. My new years resolution is to do more coding.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Over Christmas I thought I would have a go at &lt;a href="http://www.codecademy.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">http://www.codecademy.com&lt;/a>
I completed the javascript course and I was just wondering what I should try next when I saw a tweet about &lt;a href="http://www.freecodecamp.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">http://www.freecodecamp.com&lt;/a>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Since then I have been addicted to doing the exercises that they have, almost everyday I have made a bit of progress.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But this site is not just about teaching you how to code, it has an active forum where you can ask questions and understand more about what it takes to become a developer.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Before I started these exercises I didn’t know much javascript or jquery but I am starting to learn quite a few commands that hopefully I can put into use at some point. Whatever development I end up doing I am sure I am going to need javascript at some point.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>One of the tips I have learnt is that you need to practise daily. Did you ever use flash cards to help pass exams? Well there is an electronic version of them now called Anki. Just add a question/answer pair to your deck of cards and review them each day, the ones you find difficult you review more often than the ones you have learnt.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Hopefully I can keep this up and later in the year I will be well on way to writing lots of useful code.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>