<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>VSTS on Funky Si's Blog</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/tags/vsts/</link><description>Recent content in VSTS on Funky Si's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2017 20:00:45 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.funkysi1701.com/tags/vsts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Github Vs Bitbucket Vs Visual Studio Team Services</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2017/github-vs-bitbucket-vs-vsts/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2017 20:00:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2017/github-vs-bitbucket-vs-vsts/</guid><description>&lt;p>As a developer using source control and git is bread and butter of what we do. Github is probably the most popular and widely known hosting service for source control but I have also used Bitbucket and Visual Studio Team Services. Lets have a look at each one and what they offer. Note while I have included prices I have only tried out the free versions.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="github">Github&lt;a class="anchor ms-1" href="#github">&lt;i class="fas fa-link">&lt;/i>&lt;/a>&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;img class="img-fluid" alt="" src="https://storageaccountblog9f5d.blob.core.windows.net/blazor/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/github-octocat.png?resize=300%2C158&amp;amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy"
/>
&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>URL: &lt;a href="https://github.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://github.com/&lt;/a>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Private Repositories: Not Available for free&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Public Repositories: Unlimited&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Team Size: Unlimited&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Prices: $7 per month for unlimited private repositories, $25 per month for 5 users then $9 per month per user&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>This is probably the most widely used service for hosting code. Over 13 million repositories of code. This is an ideal solution if you want your code to be publicly viewable, but take care not to publish passwords, private keys or your companies trade secrets. Every developer should have a Github account for displaying bits of code they are proud of.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There are a number of externally built APIs that link into Github for doing extra features, like building, code coverage etc&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="bitbucket">Bitbucket&lt;a class="anchor ms-1" href="#bitbucket">&lt;i class="fas fa-link">&lt;/i>&lt;/a>&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;img class="img-fluid" alt="" src="https://storageaccountblog9f5d.blob.core.windows.net/blazor/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/d8TRzzL.png?resize=150%2C150&amp;amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy"
/>
&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>URL: &lt;a href="https://bitbucket.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://bitbucket.org/&lt;/a>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Private Repositories: Unlimited&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Public Repositories: Unlimited&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Team Size: Less than 5&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Prices: $10 per month for 10 Users, $100 per month for 100 Users, $200 per month for Unlimited Users&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>At my last job we used Bitbucket extensively for all our projects. All the code was private so only the team could access it, however before I left we were approaching the 5 user limit (but looking at these prices cost seems very reasonable)&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="visual-studio-team-services">Visual Studio Team Services&lt;a class="anchor ms-1" href="#visual-studio-team-services">&lt;i class="fas fa-link">&lt;/i>&lt;/a>&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;img class="img-fluid" alt="" src="https://storageaccountblog9f5d.blob.core.windows.net/blazor/wp-content/uploads/2016/11/Visual-Studio-Team-Services.png?resize=300%2C136&amp;amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy"
/>
&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>URL: &lt;a href="https://www.visualstudio.com/team-services/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://www.visualstudio.com/team-services/&lt;/a>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Private Repositories: Unlimited&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Public Repositories: Not Available&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Team Size: Less than 5&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Prices: $30 per month for 10 users, and other features paid for via Azure Invoices&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Visual Studio Team Services or VSTS is Microsoft’s version control solution and I have only just started using it, however what I have seen I like. There are lots of options for building your code so VSTS is more than just hosting your code it is verging on a Continuous Integration/Delivery solution. Being a Microsoft product there are numerous links to Azure and it is easy to deploy stuff to that platform.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>All three have options for tracking issues but VSTS have options to add Stakeholder users which would allow none developers to add and keep track of issues and progress with them.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If I want to run tests, look at code coverage VSTS is probably the solution I would go for, if I want something that is public I would go for Github. What do you think which of these is your favourite?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Getting control of a codebase</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2016/getting-control-of-a-codebase/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Nov 2016 20:00:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2016/getting-control-of-a-codebase/</guid><description>&lt;p>So recently I started working on a new codebase. I will be honest when I first saw it, it was a mess. Here are a few of the things I did to try and regain control.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I was given access to the source code on Visual Studio Team Services. However this consisted of a single commit 3 months ago. When I looked at what was running on the production server it was clear that changes were being made live with no regard for source control.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The first thing I did was commit everything that was running live into source control.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Next I created a SQL Server Data Tools (SSDT) project to keep track of all the database objects. Previously there was a folder with some stored procedures in it, but these did not match with what was currently running.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img class="img-fluid" alt="" src="https://storageaccountblog9f5d.blob.core.windows.net/blazor/wp-content/uploads/2015/12/sql-server-2012-management-studio-splash-screen.png?resize=300%2C204&amp;amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy"
/>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I now had in source control the current state of the website and the database, so I knew I could get things back to this state if I made some bad changes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Lets start by looking at the website code I had. There was no solution file, the only way to look at the website was to setup my local IIS to run what was in the website folder. I could then use Visual Studio to &amp;ldquo;open&amp;rdquo; my local IIS website and attach to process to debug it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Next I Looked at Default.aspx to see how the website worked. The majority of the website code was stored in the database stored procedures. After the tag there was a &amp;lt;% %&amp;gt; which contained a Response.Write(RunSP.RunStoredProcedure(Parameter1, Parameter2, &amp;hellip;) command, which executed a stored procedure and the results of the stored procedure was the html code including any javascript that the webpage needed to display. I will be honest I have never seen any code like it. My guess is that the developer was secretly a DBA and wanted to make any web page changes by just changing how the stored procedures work.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This meant that the website is not going to do anything without a backup of the database running, and meant my SSDT project was going to be vital. However the database was in a bad state, it consisted of a fair few broken objects and SSDT would not build.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Using find I went through each of the broken database objects to find where in the code they were being used. Luckily most were referenced in commented out code, so I just removed all the broken database objects. The database could now be built. However there was a dependency on the users table of another database. (This was the developers solution to sharing logins between websites) As I was using SSDT I added a database dependency, problem solved for now.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Next I tried publishing my database. SQL CMD encountered a parsing error. The reason for this was my SPs contained javascript eg $(document), SQL CMD uses $(DatabaseName) as variables for different database so it was getting itself confused.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My solution was to use Find and Replace to replace all the $ with &amp;rsquo; + CHAR(36) + '&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So I now have a SSDT project that builds and publishes but still no website project.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To get the website running from Visual Studio I started off creating a .Net 4 website project and added Entity Framework 5 and MVC 3 via nuget. I then copied all the website code into the new project, and with a bit of work I got it to build. Most of the work was relating to namespaces and referencing the correct one and moving the EF model from AppCode to a custom named folder. A bit of trial and error later I had a version of the website that could be run from Visual Studio.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I have not deployed my new version of the website as it needs further testing. No automated testing or even a smoke test checklist currently exist.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img class="img-fluid" alt="" src="https://storageaccountblog9f5d.blob.core.windows.net/blazor/wp-content/uploads/2016/11/Visual-Studio-Team-Services.png?w=960&amp;amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy"
/>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As my source code is hosted on Visual Studio Team Services (VSTS), I can get VSTS to build each commit and check I haven’t broken the build. This is not that helpful at the moment, hopefully one day I will have automated tests that can be run here as well.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Wow, I feel like I have done loads with this code so far but there is loads more still to do. I need to understand more about the business processes behind the code with a hope to understand why some architectural decisions have been made. I want to refactor the code as much as is possible, I would like to remove much of the html/javascript from the stored procedures as I can’t see that there is any advantage to running a website like this. Please correct my if I am wrong.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>