<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Training on Funky Si's Blog</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/tags/training/</link><description>Recent content in Training on Funky Si's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.funkysi1701.com/tags/training/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Pluralsight</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2018/pluralsight/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2018/pluralsight/</guid><description>&lt;p>Earlier this year I signed up for pluralsight. If you want to sign up to pluralsight as well use this link &lt;a href="http://referral.pluralsight.com/mQd8BJ4" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">http://referral.pluralsight.com/mQd8BJ4&lt;/a>
to get money off.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Pluralsight is a website that sells training videos on a wide variety of technical topics. You sign up for a monthly or annual subscription and you can watch over 6000 courses whenever and where ever you like.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I am not a big fan of videos as if I am sat in front of a screen I would rather be building something, however I do spend a lot of time listening to podcasts. So I have decided to convert this time to listening to pluralsight videos.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If we assume that by not seeing the visual portion of the videos you lose out on 75% of the learning (This is just a guesstimate I am not sure what the exact figure is or how you would calculate it). However this is still 25% more learning than if I hadn’t signed up at all.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Since I signed up I have listened to over 27 hours of technical videos. These have covered topics like C#, Security, Xamarin, MVVM, Interfaces, Getting Involved and Clean architecture. The number one thing I have learnt is that there is a lot that I still don’t understand.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://referral.pluralsight.com/mQd8BJ4" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">&lt;img class="img-fluid" alt="pluralsight" src="https://media-exp2.licdn.com/media-proxy/ext?w=180&amp;amp;h=110&amp;amp;f=c&amp;amp;hash=2DICrZGwAwdh4z0KEMF0kWaIcwc%3D&amp;amp;ora=1%2CaFBCTXdkRmpGL2lvQUFBPQ%2CxAVta5g-0R65wVUKzgkz4aKSpEi48AlESo-TA3PiDmbpp4DeJDT2K5aLLufiuwxcPW5UjVJtPfL8FXa0Tsz8fsisYN51i4rlJY3mNlZeSU4uy3lB6w" loading="lazy"
/>
&lt;/a>
That said I would like to think that since starting to listen to pluralsight concepts have gone from being unknown unknowns (I don’t know about them and I don’t understand them) to known unknowns (I know about them but don’t yet fully understand them)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To keep track of your learning pluralsight has some tests which you can complete. I am particularly proud of my score on the Azure test which ranks me as an expert.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Why not check out what you can learn from pluralsight?&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>