<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Azure on Funky Si's Blog</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/tags/azure/</link><description>Recent content in Azure on Funky Si's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 May 2021 20:00:45 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.funkysi1701.com/tags/azure/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>My road to Certification</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2021/my-road-to-certification/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 May 2021 20:00:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2021/my-road-to-certification/</guid><description>&lt;p>So today I sat the Azure Fundamentals Certification Exam and passed!
&lt;img class="img-fluid" alt="Alt Text" src="https://dev-to-uploads.s3.amazonaws.com/uploads/articles/eytphopn3inx2x77m9n5.png" loading="lazy"
/>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Really pleased with myself at achieving this. It was one of my goals for 2021 so I can tick that off.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Back in January I booked my first exam, however due to technical problems I didn&amp;rsquo;t get as far as the Exam. In order to be able to sit an exam like this you need a webcam and microphone so you can be monitored remotely to check that you are not cheating. Something in my network was blocking them from seeing my video so it got cancelled before it started.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My theory is that either my internet connection was playing up at the time, My Pi Hole was blocking something, or something else on my network was blocking the video feed.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This cancellation put me off Certifications, as I wasn&amp;rsquo;t sure how to debug the issue and find out exactly what the problem was.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A few months back I won a free Azure Certification for taking part in a skills challenge run by &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/gregor_suttie" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Gregor Suttie&lt;/a>
and &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Pixel_Robots" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Richard Hooper&lt;/a>
and this was due to expire at the end of this month so I thought why not book a second exam and see if I can get past the technical problems. I didn&amp;rsquo;t do any exam prep as I thought, I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t get that far.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This time I connected directly to my router, bypassing most of the network, firewall and other items on my network that could possibly cause an issue.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I cleared my desk, took photos of my ID, took pictures of my desk from every orientation, and waited for the technical issues to start.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I was in a queue waiting for the exam to start.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A connection issue has occurred you have been sent to the back of the queue. Oh here we go again!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But no I connected with the invigilator, who asked to confirm my monitors were disconnected and to move my wallet out of reach off my desk.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And we are off, I am answering questions from the exam.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I won&amp;rsquo;t go into detail about the questions, but I whizzed through them, most made me think, some I guessed at. I wasn&amp;rsquo;t expecting to pass, I thought maybe half marks or just under due to my familiarity with Azure. (I have been using it for years which must count for something!)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I was wrong I passed comfortably and now I have my first certification.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My advice for you if you have been using Azure for a while is to book this exam and see how you do, you may well pass like me. There are plenty of opportunities to get a free exam, attending conferences like Ignite often qualify you for one, look out for challenges and competitions by #AzureFamily people on twitter as they are very encouraging and helpful in your Certification journey.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And yes I am thinking about what Certificate to do next!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Azure DevOps Release Pipelines Pre and Post Approval</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2021/azure-devops-release-pipelines-pre-and-post-approval/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Feb 2021 20:00:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2021/azure-devops-release-pipelines-pre-and-post-approval/</guid><description>&lt;p>Azure DevOps release pipelines have lots of options to do things how you want. One of my favourites is the option for approval.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There are two ways you can do approvals Pre and Post deployment. Lets look at both.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="pre-deployment-approval">Pre Deployment Approval&lt;a class="anchor ms-1" href="#pre-deployment-approval">&lt;i class="fas fa-link">&lt;/i>&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;img class="img-fluid" alt="image" src="https://dev-to-uploads.s3.amazonaws.com/i/9k6vo6pfv434u7yq3mt4.png" loading="lazy"
/>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Lets imagine you have a simple deployment pipeline that deploys to a test/development environment before deploying to a production environment.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Pre Deployment Approval happens immediately before the release so in this example, click in the ellipse before the Prod release step.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You will get a screen like the above, you can select what users need to approve it and how long approval waits before timing out, the default is 30 days, but I tend to use a shorter time out of 3 days.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="post-deployment-approval">Post Deployment Approval&lt;a class="anchor ms-1" href="#post-deployment-approval">&lt;i class="fas fa-link">&lt;/i>&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;img class="img-fluid" alt="image" src="https://dev-to-uploads.s3.amazonaws.com/i/reiulrhinzqyyon6mrqi.png" loading="lazy"
/>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Post Deployment Approval happens immediately after the release so in this example, click in the circle after the Test release step.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You will get a screen like the above, with the same settings as before.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That is pretty much all there is to approvals so either option will prompt you to approve before anything gets deployed to your production environment.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="deployment-hours">Deployment Hours&lt;a class="anchor ms-1" href="#deployment-hours">&lt;i class="fas fa-link">&lt;/i>&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>To complicate matters I make use of the following setting to define deployment hours.
&lt;img class="img-fluid" alt="image" src="https://dev-to-uploads.s3.amazonaws.com/i/aku2z0dl3m3xkvfvh7wd.png" loading="lazy"
/>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This setting will start the Prod deployment at 3am Mon-Fri.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If I configure Post Deployment Approval, as soon as my deploy to Test has completed a request for Approval is sent.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If I configure Pre Deployment Approval, at 3am Mon-Fri a request for Approval is sent (not ideal if you tend to be asleep at 3am)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So it looks like Post Deployment Approval is more useful for my use case. However if you deny approval either in Pre or Post approval this will mark the deployment as failed and show Red in your list of deployments.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img class="img-fluid" alt="image" src="https://dev-to-uploads.s3.amazonaws.com/i/vichyb1srgc1ln85hj0o.png" loading="lazy"
/>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>From a casual glance it looks like the deployment to Test is failing, it isn&amp;rsquo;t I am just opting to not continue my deployment to production.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="my-pipeline">My Pipeline&lt;a class="anchor ms-1" href="#my-pipeline">&lt;i class="fas fa-link">&lt;/i>&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;img class="img-fluid" alt="image" src="https://dev-to-uploads.s3.amazonaws.com/i/9kprp90t59owfmsmqkcp.png" loading="lazy"
/>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is how I have my pipeline setup. Deployment happens on Test and doesn&amp;rsquo;t have a post approval step.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After Test an empty stage called Approval runs and that has a post deployment approval, this happens immediately after Test so you get asked straight away for approval.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Prod does not start as I have my deployment hours configured. Once it is time for deployment to Prod to start it executes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now a casual look at my past releases, you can easily see which have been stopped by approval and which have failed due to whatever issue, and which have run all the way through to Prod.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And deployments to Prod can only ever run during my defined deployment window.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I am interested to hear how you have your deployment pipeline setup. Do you make use of Pre or Post Approvals? Do you ensure deployments always happen at specific times?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Weekly Update #002</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2020/weekly-update-002/</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2020/weekly-update-002/</guid><description>&lt;p>I know Active Directory is fussy about clocks being in sync however not sure how todays issue happened.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I run my docker compose file from Visual Studio and I get a weird error.&lt;/p>
&lt;pre tabindex="0">&lt;code>SecurityTokenNotYetValidException: IDX10222: Lifetime validation failed. The token is not yet valid. ValidFrom: &amp;#39;System.DateTime&amp;#39;, Current time: &amp;#39;System.DateTime&amp;#39;.
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;p>I deleted my containers, open and close Visual Studio a few times, nothing helps. Eventually I think to find out what the time is on my container. It has yesterday&amp;rsquo;s date. What has happened here? Surely recreating containers would have caused them to have todays date? I reboot and everything is fine again.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Turns out that it is a know issue, see &lt;a href="https://thorsten-hans.com/docker-on-windows-fix-time-synchronization-issue" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://thorsten-hans.com/docker-on-windows-fix-time-synchronization-issue&lt;/a>
I am using WSL2 and I have now changed back to using Hyper-V and the issue hasn&amp;rsquo;t come back.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Earlier in the week I spotted my build step was failing.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;">&lt;code class="language-yaml" data-lang="yaml">&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> - &lt;span style="color:#f92672">task&lt;/span>: &lt;span style="color:#ae81ff">NuGetToolInstaller@0&lt;/span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>&lt;p>Swapping to the next version of the step is all I needed to do to fix it.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;">&lt;code class="language-yaml" data-lang="yaml">&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> - &lt;span style="color:#f92672">task&lt;/span>: &lt;span style="color:#ae81ff">NuGetToolInstaller@1&lt;/span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>&lt;p>My guess is that support was dropped for this earlier version or there is some other incompatability with .Net 5.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Gated Release</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2019/gated-release/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Apr 2019 20:00:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2019/gated-release/</guid><description>&lt;p>Automated releases of software are great but how can we add an element of feedback so only good releases go live.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I have been using Azure DevOps to release my &lt;a href="https://www.funkysi1701.com/pwned-pass/">PwnedPass&lt;/a>
android app to the Google Play Store for a while now. There are options to deploy to the alpha, Beta or Production tracks and even to set % of users to target. For the full range of options check out the Google Play &lt;a href="https://marketplace.visualstudio.com/items?itemName=ms-vsclient.google-play" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">extension&lt;/a>
for Azure DevOps.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My release starts by publishing to 10% of users on the production track, my next step makes use of the increase rollout option to increase this %, you can have as many of these additional steps as you want until you reach 100% of your users.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img class="img-fluid" alt="Image" src="https://storageaccountblog9f5d.blob.core.windows.net/blazor/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/image.png?fit=662%2C116&amp;amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy"
/>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now if you run this release now it will just run through each of the steps one after the other. Now of course you can add a pre or post approval to your pipeline but this just adds a manual dependency to your release. Whoever does the approving needs to check things are working before approving or worse just approves regardless.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Azure DevOps has the concept of &lt;a href="https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/azure/devops/pipelines/release/deploy-using-approvals?view=azure-devops" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">gated releases&lt;/a>
which allows you to add automated checks before or after a release happens. These automated checks can be any of the following:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>An Azure Function&lt;/li>
&lt;li>A Rest API call&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Azure Monitor Alert&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Query Work Items&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Security and Compliance Assessment&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>We are going to make use of the Azure Monitor Alert, to create an alert from your Application Insights data and only continue the rollout if no failures are detected.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Open up your application insights resource in the Azure portal and look in alerts. Click add new alert rule.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img class="img-fluid" alt="Image" src="https://storageaccountblog9f5d.blob.core.windows.net/blazor/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/image-1.png?fit=662%2C552&amp;amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy"
/>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Select your application insights resource in Resource, In Condition choose a condition to check, I chose Failed Requests, so every time a failure is registered in my API I can stop the deployment. The exact criteria you want to use is entirely up to you.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Create an action group, I just set my alert to send an email to myself but there are other alert actions you may want to try. Give your alert a name and description and click save.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now all we need to do is make Azure DevOps make use of this alert. In your release pipeline select the pre-deployment conditions of your second step and open up the Gates section.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img class="img-fluid" alt="Image" src="https://storageaccountblog9f5d.blob.core.windows.net/blazor/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/image-2.png?fit=662%2C498&amp;amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy"
/>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Choose a suitable time to evaluate, I have been using something long like 12 or 24 hours so if there are problems there is time for it to be noticed. Choose Version 1 of the task (I was not able to get it to work with Version 0)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now select your Azure subscription and Resource Group and leave the rest of the settings as they are. Now your Deployment will stop and analyse application insights for any Failed requests and will halt if it finds any.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img class="img-fluid" alt="Image" src="https://storageaccountblog9f5d.blob.core.windows.net/blazor/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/image-3.png?fit=662%2C88&amp;amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy"
/>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I am still testing this out but it will take a few days to figure out if this what I want due to the large time scales involved. I feel this is going to be an improvement of manually approving release steps.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Azure Key Vault</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2019/azure-key-vault/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2019 20:00:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2019/azure-key-vault/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://docs.microsoft.com/en-gb/azure/key-vault/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Azure Key Vault&lt;/a>
is a secure way of storing your keys, certificates and secrets so your application can access everything it needs to but you don’t have them being stored insecurely anywhere such as in source control.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I have been wanting to give Azure Key Vault a try for a while now as it can make use of Azure Active Directory to give your web app an identity so it can authenticate itself into the key vault to access secrets. Pretty clever but with a lot of moving parts a bit complex.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For my example I am just going to connect to my Key Vault and get a secret and display it somewhere on a web page. This is of course not what you want to do as secrets are secret and shouldn’t be displayed just used to authenticate into whatever, however it is an easy way to prove I am connecting to the Key Vault and everything is working.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Lets look at some code. I have a .net core application and to start with lets install three nuget packages.&lt;/p>
&lt;pre tabindex="0">&lt;code>Microsoft.Azure.KeyVault
Microsoft.Azure.Services.AppAuthentication
Microsoft.Extensions.Configuration.AzureKeyVault
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;p>I’ve not include version numbers as these will no doubt get updated over time but hopefully it will still work.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now in your Program.cs add the following code, replacing [KeyVaultName] with the name of your Key Vault.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;">&lt;code class="language-csharp" data-lang="csharp">&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> &lt;span style="color:#66d9ef">public&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#66d9ef">class&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">Program&lt;/span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> {
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> &lt;span style="color:#66d9ef">public&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#66d9ef">static&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#66d9ef">void&lt;/span> Main(&lt;span style="color:#66d9ef">string&lt;/span>[] args)
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> {
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> CreateWebHostBuilder(args).Build().Run();
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> }
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> &lt;span style="color:#66d9ef">public&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#66d9ef">static&lt;/span> IWebHostBuilder CreateWebHostBuilder(&lt;span style="color:#66d9ef">string&lt;/span>[] args) =&amp;gt;
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> WebHost.CreateDefaultBuilder(args)
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> .ConfigureAppConfiguration((context, config) =&amp;gt;
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> {
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> &lt;span style="color:#66d9ef">var&lt;/span> builtConfig = config.Build();
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> &lt;span style="color:#66d9ef">var&lt;/span> azureServiceTokenProvider = &lt;span style="color:#66d9ef">new&lt;/span> AzureServiceTokenProvider();
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> &lt;span style="color:#66d9ef">var&lt;/span> keyVaultClient = &lt;span style="color:#66d9ef">new&lt;/span> KeyVaultClient(
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> &lt;span style="color:#66d9ef">new&lt;/span> KeyVaultClient.AuthenticationCallback(
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> azureServiceTokenProvider.KeyVaultTokenCallback));
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> config.AddAzureKeyVault(
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> &lt;span style="color:#e6db74">$&amp;#34;https://[KeyVaultName].vault.azure.net/&amp;#34;&lt;/span>,
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> keyVaultClient,
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> &lt;span style="color:#66d9ef">new&lt;/span> DefaultKeyVaultSecretManager());
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> })
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> .UseApplicationInsights()
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> .UseStartup&amp;lt;Startup&amp;gt;();
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> }
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>&lt;p>Now all you need to do is look at your configuration to pull out secrets from your Azure Key Vault. If you have a secret called AppSecret then you can use the following code snippet to retrieve its value, assuming _configuration is an implementation of Microsoft.Extensions.Configuration.IConfiguration.&lt;/p>
&lt;pre tabindex="0">&lt;code>_configuration[&amp;#34;AppSecret&amp;#34;];
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;p>Now if you do all of this and run from an Azure Web App or run locally it will fail to pull anything from the Key Vault. You need to give your web app an identity and configure your key vault to allow access from that identity.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Once my code has been deployed to an Azure Web App I get the following error.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img class="img-fluid" alt="Image" src="https://storageaccountblog9f5d.blob.core.windows.net/blazor/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/image.png?fit=662%2C292&amp;amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy"
/>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Lets look at fixing that, first lets give my web app an Identity. Open up the Azure portal and find the identity section of your web app and turn the setting on.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img class="img-fluid" alt="Image" src="https://storageaccountblog9f5d.blob.core.windows.net/blazor/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/image-1.png?fit=662%2C396&amp;amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy"
/>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now you need to grant that identity permission to your key vault. In the portal open up Access Policies in your key vault and click add Policy, select the identity of your web app in the principal box and select the following settings to grant access to your secret.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img class="img-fluid" alt="Image" src="https://storageaccountblog9f5d.blob.core.windows.net/blazor/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/image-2.png?resize=206%2C428&amp;amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy"
/>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now you have a website that can pull secrets out of Key Vault but only that unique identity. Anyone who has access to your source code will not have access to your secrets, even if they push your code to a different Azure Web App.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Technology I want to learn more about</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2019/technology-i-want-to-learn-more-about/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2019 20:00:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2019/technology-i-want-to-learn-more-about/</guid><description>&lt;p>While at &lt;a href="https://www.funkysi1701.com/2019/02/26/microsoft-ignite-the-tour-london">Microsoft Ignite&lt;/a>
I heard about a lot of cool tech that I want to know more about. The best way to learn something is use it to solve a problem.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So what can I build that is both useful and will let me play with some new tech?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I have a Xamarin Forms app &lt;a href="https://www.funkysi1701.com/pwned-pass/">Pwned Pass&lt;/a>
that has over 500 downloads on &lt;a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=pwnedpasswords.pwnedpasswords" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Google play&lt;/a>
and over 80 downloads on the &lt;a href="https://www.microsoft.com/en-gb/p/pwned-pass/9nm2whnztnlt?rtc=1" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Microsoft Store&lt;/a>
. This has given me a small user base that I can use to make use of whatever I build.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My app makes use of the &lt;a href="https://haveibeenpwned.com/API/v2" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">HIBP API&lt;/a>
created by Troy Hunt. I am going to build my own API, initially it will just make calls to the HIBP API. Building this will give me experience of building something with .net Core from design to deployment. I have made a start already on doing this, I have an empty .net core API project which deploys to an Azure web app using the build and release pipelines from Azure DevOps.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You may be wondering why I am not making use of Azure Functions to build this API. Azure functions is certainly a great technology that is worth learning about. However I have done a little bit with them in the past and I don’t believe I would be able to learn all the things I want to if I used Azure Functions. My primary goal is learning and sharing that learning via this blog. It may well be I move to using Azure Functions later on.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Another tech I am keen to learn more about is &lt;a href="https://docs.microsoft.com/en-gb/azure/key-vault/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Azure Key Vault&lt;/a>
. This is a technology that allows the securing of keys, connection strings and certificates. I want my app to securely get keys and security information without any of it having to be committed to source code or shared insecurely.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Monitoring my app is also a key learning from me. I use application insights already, but I would like to extend my understanding of this so telemetry can be fed back into the build and bad deployments stopped.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Below is my complete list of learning and tech I want to touch on. It is a long list and I imagine it will get longer as I work through it. I want to regularly blog and share what I have been working on. I currently have a working build and release pipeline but nothing of note to build or release. I know Key Vault needs looking at early as the identity of the website in Azure is key to getting that tech working correctly.&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Build API with .net core&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add build and release pipeline&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Make use of Azure KeyVault for secrets, connection strings etc&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Plugin My Xamarin app to make use of it&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Monitor my API with Application Insights&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Secure it with CSPs and log this into &lt;a href="https://report-uri.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Report URI&lt;/a>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Consider building a web frontend to my API using a javascript library or framework. Maybe react but this can be decided later.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Dockerize the API and add the creation of docker images to the build/release pipeline&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Microsoft Ignite | The Tour – London</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2019/microsoft-ignite-the-tour-london/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2019 20:00:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2019/microsoft-ignite-the-tour-london/</guid><description>&lt;p>I have just spent the first day at the conference Microsoft Ignite | The Tour.
&lt;img class="img-fluid" alt="Alt Text" src="https://storageaccountblog9f5d.blob.core.windows.net/blazor/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/D0UTj08XgAEo1YJ.jpg?fit=662%2C440&amp;amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy"
/>
The conference was free I just needed to arrange travel and accommodation. Microsoft have really looked after me and all the other guests, breakfast and lunch has been provided, I got a free t-shirt, coffee (or tea) all day plus a beer or glass of wine to end the day. And that’s before you collect any free stuff the vendors are giving away.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The first session was Designing resilient cloud applications with &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/CodeMillMatt" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Matt Soucoup&lt;/a>
and talked about some cloud technologies like Azure key vault and serving static files from blob storage. Unfortunately this had a few technical issues with the demos. I think it was just connectivity with the MongoDB backend but this slightly spoiled the session. As this was the only technical problem I noticed all day I can let it pass.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Next was a session on Azure DevOps mainly build and release pipelines called Deploying your application faster and safer with &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/bbenz" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Brian Benz&lt;/a>
. A lot of this I knew but good to reinforce I am doing things correctly.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Next was a session on Application Insights called Detecting application anomalies with Telemetry with Matt Soucoup.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Probably the most useful session was on Docker and Kubernetes called Integrate containers and Kubernetes into your Azure DevOps build and release model with &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/crad77" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Marco De Sanctis&lt;/a>
. Going to spend some time looking through the examples from this session.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A session on Serverless covered Azure Functions, Azure Logic apps and the other Azure Serverless offerings. Investing in Serverless: less servers, more code with &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/simona_cotin" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Simona Cotin&lt;/a>
.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Lastly was a panel discussion on the changes facing IT Pros and SysAdmins. What is the future of the IT Pro in a DevOps &amp;amp; Cloudy world? with &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/jenstirrup" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Jennifer Stirrup&lt;/a>
, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/bakionur" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Baki Onur Okutucu&lt;/a>
, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/AmyKateNicho" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Amy Boyd&lt;/a>
and &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/TheOpsMgr" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Stephen Thair&lt;/a>
. Should they learn to code, how should they make sure they keep up.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Tomorrow I have a loads more sessions, including ones about mental health, Azure pipelines, more Kubernetes stuff and dealing with failure.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Yaml Builds on Azure DevOps</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2019/yaml-builds-on-azure-devops/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2019 20:00:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2019/yaml-builds-on-azure-devops/</guid><description>&lt;p>I have been using Azure DevOps (Or VSTS or VSO etc) for a while now and one of the great features is doing automatic builds with every check-in. This is more commonly known as a CI (continuous integration) build.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>More recently I have started playing about with creating my build using YAML files instead of using the web user interface to create my build.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="why">Why?&lt;a class="anchor ms-1" href="#why">&lt;i class="fas fa-link">&lt;/i>&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>You may wonder why go to the effort of learning the YAML syntax when you can just create the build in Azure DevOps and then forget about it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Mostly it is because the build changes over time and you shouldn’t just forget about it. If something changes over time then you might want to version control it, or look at a previous version.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Lets say you create a pull request that replaces a .net 4.7 web service with a .net core web service. If you have a CI build this PR will fail because it won’t build. If you change the build first any other builds going on will fail. What you want in this case is the build to be associated with that branch or PR. Any builds before you merge this change in will continue to work and any after this change will also work.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="how">How?&lt;a class="anchor ms-1" href="#how">&lt;i class="fas fa-link">&lt;/i>&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>How do you get started with YAML builds? Well the first thing is to make sure that YAML builds are turned on, as I write this I believe they are still a feature you can turn on or off. Have a look in Preview features and make sure they are turned on.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Next look at any of your existing builds and click the View YAML link. This will show you an example YAML file of your existing build. You could just save this as azure-pipelines.yml and checkin to the root of your project. You can also click the add new build pipeline option, this will give you some templates to start you off.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The YAML file consists of a series of build steps usually called tasks, with a few settings before to configure things like parameters or build agents. Detailed docs about the syntax of the file can be found &lt;a href="https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/azure/devops/pipelines/yaml-schema?view=azure-devops&amp;amp;tabs=schema" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">here&lt;/a>
.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For my mobile app my YAML files consist of downloading nuget packages, building the solution, building specific projects with desired settings, running powershell or other scripts to set things up and finally publishing the results of the build as artifacts so that they can be used in any releases.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="secure-it">Secure It!&lt;a class="anchor ms-1" href="#secure-it">&lt;i class="fas fa-link">&lt;/i>&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Avoid committing passwords and secure keys into source control. I have found you can upload secure files via Azure DevOps and then add a download secure files step at the start of your build. This allows the secure file to be used during the build but the contents of the file can’t be viewed by anyone with access to the source code.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I find it often takes a bit of thinking about how to achieve this, but it is usually possible to keep keys and secrets secure.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Flexible Architecture with Interfaces</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2018/flexible-architecture/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2018/flexible-architecture/</guid><description>&lt;p>I have blogged a few times about &lt;a href="https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2017/interfaces/">interfaces&lt;/a>
, and how useful they are for producing good quality maintainable code. Let’s look at a problem and the solution I came up with which I am quite proud of.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As previously mentioned I am in the process of moving &lt;a href="https://dev.to/funkysi1701/moving-files-into-blob-storage-1ckh-temp-slug-2044961" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">images&lt;/a>
from AWS to Azure blob storage. Now that the actual files themselves have been moved I need to change the code that references them.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now I could find all the code that uses the AWS API and replace it with the Azure API but I am not very good at predicting the future, we may stay on Azure for a while, we may move to AWS or Google Cloud, or we may want to go back to files sitting on a server.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Lets try and code a solution that is as flexible as possible. As you have probably guessed I am going to create an interface.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>At first I thought about creating an interface called &lt;strong>ICloudStorage&lt;/strong> , however this isn’t flexible enough as what happens if we go back to sticking files on a server so instead I created &lt;strong>IStorage&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I created three classes that implemented IStorage, &lt;strong>AWSStorage&lt;/strong> , &lt;strong>AzureStorage&lt;/strong> and mostly for testing at the moment &lt;strong>FileStorage&lt;/strong>. I then created a class Storage that would call these three classes. Initially I created it like this&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;">&lt;code class="language-csharp" data-lang="csharp">&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>&lt;span style="color:#66d9ef">public&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#66d9ef">class&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">Storage&lt;/span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>{
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> &lt;span style="color:#66d9ef">private&lt;/span> IStorage &lt;span style="color:#ae81ff">_&lt;/span>repo;
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> &lt;span style="color:#66d9ef">public&lt;/span> Storage(IStorage repo)
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> {
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> &lt;span style="color:#ae81ff">_&lt;/span>repo = repo;
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> }
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>}
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>&lt;p>However this would require I call it like Storage(new AzureStorage()) and I would need to know everywhere in my code which implementation I want to use. This isn’t too bad as when we change from AWS to Azure we would need to do a find and replace throughout the code and replace all AWSStorage and make them AzureStorage.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>However we can do better than that.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;">&lt;code class="language-csharp" data-lang="csharp">&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>&lt;span style="color:#66d9ef">public&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#66d9ef">class&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">Storage&lt;/span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>{
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> &lt;span style="color:#66d9ef">private&lt;/span> IStorage &lt;span style="color:#ae81ff">_&lt;/span>repo;
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> &lt;span style="color:#66d9ef">public&lt;/span> Storage()
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> {
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> Type obj = Type.GetType(ConfigurationManager.AppSettings[&lt;span style="color:#e6db74">&amp;#34;DefaultStorageRepository&amp;#34;&lt;/span>]);
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> ConstructorInfo constructor = obj.GetConstructor(&lt;span style="color:#66d9ef">new&lt;/span> Type[] { });
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> &lt;span style="color:#ae81ff">_&lt;/span>repo = (IStorage)constructor.Invoke(&lt;span style="color:#66d9ef">null&lt;/span>);
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> }
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>}
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>&lt;p>This code will read from the web.config which implementation to use and that will decide which class to call. This means that to change from AWS to Azure we do not need to redeploy any code, all we need to do is change the web.config.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Let’s look at the three lines and see if we can understand what is happening.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Type.GetType()&lt;/strong> looks straight forward and gets the type from the web.config&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>obj.GetConstructor()&lt;/strong> This gets the constructor for the type we have just found.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>constructor.Invoke&lt;/strong> This then invokes the constructor and it then gets cast to the interface so can be used by the _repo variable.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is all fairly simple and makes sense, however it has produced some very flexible code and allows the code to be extended without recompiling.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Let’s look at a hypothetical example. We want to add support for Google Cloud Storage. All we need to do is create a class library which implements the IStorage interface, place the compiled binary in the website and update the web.config to reference it. I haven’t tried this hypothetical example so it might be more complex than I think but in theory it should work.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I am pretty excited at how flexible this code can be, hopefully I will use code like this more often now I understand it.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Moving files into blob storage</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2018/moving-blobs-cloud-suppliers/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2018/moving-blobs-cloud-suppliers/</guid><description>&lt;p>We are in the process of moving our companies websites onto the Azure platform. One of the challenges was to move image files out of the website project into blob storage. This week I have moved 150,000 of them.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>One thing I keep banging on about is that your source code should not contain data. If it does every time you do a deployment you need to consider where these images are located and ensure you don’t overwrite or loose any. It also goes without saying that deployments of a few Mb are a lot quicker than deployments of 100s of Mb.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Azure blob storage also gives you advantages like distributing storage across multiple datacenters which would be impossible with traditional files on a server.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So now that we have established that this is a good idea lets look at how we could move large amounts of data. In my case all the filenames are stored in a SQL database so the plan of action was to simply loop through the files in the database, download from current storage (either locally or other cloud storage), upload to Azure and tidy up afterwards. Due to the number of images I am going to update the database and mark when a file has been processed so I can do the move over several days.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is my code&lt;/p>
&lt;style>.gist table { margin-bottom: 0; }&lt;/style>
&lt;p>First of all I create a tmp folder in the root of my website if it doesn’t exist to store my images temporarily.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I then use an entity framework model to query the database that haven’t been moved, and I use the take() method to limit how many results I process. (I have been passing in 1000 at a time)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I then use a foreach loop over all these files to perform the following actions.&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Create additional subfolders if the filename variable stored in the database isn’t actually a filename but a filepath, note you will have to split filename and filepath which I haven’t included code for here.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Download file from the original url and save into the temporary folder&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Upload to Azure&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Delete temporary file&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Update database giving a success or fail&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>Once the foreach is finished I commit the database changes and delete the temporary folder. I am sure there must be other ways to do this transfer but this was quick and easy to setup and now I have a copy of all the files in Azure storage so I can test out other issues with my website.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>One last tip about how to schedule this code. I called the above code from a MVC controller and then wrote a Azure Function to call this code on a schedule.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Mobile App UI Testing</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2018/mobile-app-ui-testing/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2018/mobile-app-ui-testing/</guid><description>&lt;p>Since I started creating an android app I have been writing simple UI tests.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I have been taking advantage of the Visual Studio App Center which allows you to test against hundreds of different devices in the &lt;strong>Test Cloud&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img class="img-fluid" alt="Xamarin UI tests" src="https://storageaccountblog9f5d.blob.core.windows.net/blazor/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/01-newproject-vs.png?resize=300%2C182&amp;amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy"
/>
In order to write a UI test create a UI Test App, this makes use of the nuget package Xamarin UI Test. By default you will now have a test called AppLaunches which will take a screenshot of you app after it starts.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You can now run this test against any device from Visual Studio assuming you have it physically plugged into your machine. However, how do you run against the Test Cloud?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To run against the Test Cloud you need to first install node.js. Now you can install the appcenter cli with the following command.&lt;/p>
&lt;pre tabindex="0">&lt;code>**npm** install -g appcenter-cli
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;p>To run the tests in the Test Cloud run the following command&lt;/p>
&lt;pre tabindex="0">&lt;code>**appcenter** test run uitest --app &amp;#34;&amp;lt;username&amp;gt;/&amp;lt;appname&amp;gt;&amp;#34; --devices &amp;#34;&amp;lt;username&amp;gt;/&amp;lt;deviceset&amp;gt;&amp;#34; --app-path _pathToFile.apk_ --test-series &amp;#34;master&amp;#34; --locale &amp;#34;en_US&amp;#34; --build-dir _pathToUITestBuildDir_
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;p>where &lt;username> is your appcenter username, is the name of your app in appcenter and is the group of apps you have created in app center to test against.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Look at device sets in the test section of the appcenter and click the new device set button. You can then search for any device you like and add it to a set, as I write this there are 244 devices you can test against.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It is currently not possible within app center to run tests against a new build, however if you build your app in VSTS as well you can create build or release step that runs it. As the Visual Studio app center is still under development I wouldn’t be surprised if it is added at some point.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In VSTS look for Mobile Center Test in the definitions and you can specify the same variables as specified in the command line above.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now how do you actually write a useful UI test? I mentioned above you get a default test which contains the following code, this takes a screenshot of your app. However you don’t have to include this when using the Test Cloud as screenshots are included for free.&lt;/p>
&lt;pre tabindex="0">&lt;code>app.Screenshot(&amp;#34;First screen.&amp;#34;);
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;p>Lets look at what else is included in app&lt;/p>
&lt;pre tabindex="0">&lt;code>app.Repl();
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;p>This starts an interactive REPL (Read-Eval-Print-Loop) which lets you explore what is on screen in your app and pauses execution. I don’t include this in my tests, however I do make use of it to explore what is on screen and what tests I might make use of.&lt;/p>
&lt;pre tabindex="0">&lt;code>app.Tap(c =&amp;gt; c.Marked(&amp;#34;Button&amp;#34;));
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;p>This taps an element on screen called Button. There is also a method called TapCoordinates which would allow you to click anywhere you like.&lt;/p>
&lt;pre tabindex="0">&lt;code>app.WaitForElement(c =&amp;gt; c.Marked(&amp;#34;View&amp;#34;));
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;p>After clicking a button you are probably going to want to wait for the app to load extra data or a new screen. The WaitForElement waits for an element to appear on screen. There are also methods that wait a period of time or wait until an element no longer exists.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>These are the main methods I have used so far, however there is an extensive list including methods for scrolling, swiping, pinching and adjusting the volume buttons. So you should be able to test all manner of app functionality and if you make use of the Test Clouds will know which devices are causing problems.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Azure Friday</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2017/azure-friday/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Sep 2017 20:00:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2017/azure-friday/</guid><description>&lt;p>I think Azure is great, but there is loads to it so I can never know about all of its features. There is a video series hosted by Scott Hanselman called &lt;a href="https://channel9.msdn.com/Shows/Azure-Friday" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Azure Fridays&lt;/a>
which I have started to watch in an effort to keep more up to date about some of its cool features.&lt;/p>
&lt;iframe src="https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/shows/azure-friday/debug-net-apps-in-production-snapshot-debugger-in-application-insights/player" width="960" height="540" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen">&lt;/iframe>
&lt;p>I watched this video recently and it is all about application insights and new ways you can debug your web applications by creating snapshots. I am a big fan of application insights so adding extra ways to debug my apps is a big win for me. Once I get this feature working in my code I will no doubt blog about it.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Azure Functions</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2017/azure-functions/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Sep 2017 20:00:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2017/azure-functions/</guid><description>&lt;p>I recently blogged about using &lt;a href="https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/using-azure-webjobs-to-automate-stuff">Azure Web Jobs&lt;/a>
, Azure Function is another way of doing the same thing, lets look at how they work.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>(Sorry its been a while since I blogged but I suspect an erratic schedule will continue for the next few months.)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To create an Azure Function go to the Azure portal and click add new and search for &amp;ldquo;Function App&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Give your app a name and select the usual resource group and location settings.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now when you open Function Apps you should see your new app.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I want my Function App to run on a schedule so I clicked the + next to functions and selected TimerTrigger. I am a c# programmer so I selected this option as well.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Give your function a name and specify using the usual cron notation how often it should run. I want mine to run at 9.30pm each night so use 0 30 21 * * *&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now comes the code bit. By default you get a window with the following code in it&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;">&lt;code class="language-csharp" data-lang="csharp">&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>&lt;span style="color:#66d9ef">using&lt;/span> System;
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>&lt;span style="color:#66d9ef">public&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#66d9ef">static&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#66d9ef">void&lt;/span> Run(TimerInfo myTimer, TraceWriter log)
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>{
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> log.Info(&lt;span style="color:#e6db74">$&amp;#34;C# Timer trigger function executed at: {DateTime.Now}&amp;#34;&lt;/span>);
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>}
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>&lt;p>It is entirely up to you what you get your function to do. In my case I just wanted to call a URL on a schedule so I created some code that used httpclient.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;">&lt;code class="language-csharp" data-lang="csharp">&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>&lt;span style="color:#66d9ef">using&lt;/span> System;
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>&lt;span style="color:#66d9ef">using&lt;/span> System.Net.Http;
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>&lt;span style="color:#66d9ef">public&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#66d9ef">static&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#66d9ef">async&lt;/span> Task Run(TimerInfo myTimer, TraceWriter log)
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>{
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> log.Info(&lt;span style="color:#e6db74">$&amp;#34;Buffer 0 function executed at: {DateTime.Now}&amp;#34;&lt;/span>);
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> HttpClient client = &lt;span style="color:#66d9ef">new&lt;/span> HttpClient();
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> &lt;span style="color:#66d9ef">var&lt;/span> result = &lt;span style="color:#66d9ef">await&lt;/span> client.GetAsync(&lt;span style="color:#e6db74">&amp;#34;URL&amp;#34;&lt;/span>);
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> &lt;span style="color:#66d9ef">string&lt;/span> resultContent = &lt;span style="color:#66d9ef">await&lt;/span> result.Content.ReadAsStringAsync();
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> log.Info(resultContent);
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>}
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>&lt;p>Once you have created your app and it has run you can use the monitor section to view success and failures.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There is loads more you can do with Azure Function but this is a good place to start.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Android App Development and the Visual Studio Mobile Centre</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2017/android-app-development-and-the-visual-studio-mobile-centre/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Aug 2017 20:00:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2017/android-app-development-and-the-visual-studio-mobile-centre/</guid><description>&lt;p>For the past week or so I have been playing around with Xamarin and creating an android app.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Well I now have an app in the Google Play Store. Check out &lt;a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/dev?id=6148298088834956775" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://play.google.com/store/apps/dev?id=6148298088834956775&lt;/a>
. &lt;img class="img-fluid" alt="" src="https://storageaccountblog9f5d.blob.core.windows.net/blazor/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/Screenshot_20170806-190053.png?resize=169%2C300&amp;amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy"
/>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Before you rush and download the app I must warn you that it doesn’t do much yet. It displays some content that is on my website and there are a few links to allow sharing of content. I have some ideas to display content from my blog and allow sharing. I also have some other ideas for apps that might actually be useful to people that are not me. If you have ideas or feature requests do let me know.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ok how did I go about creating this app and getting it in the app store?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Xamarin is now part of Visual Studio so step one is install all the Xamarin features to Visual Studio and build an app.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Next I wanted to monitor my app. Now I know Application Insights doesn’t support apps so what tools are out there? HockeyApp is something I had heard of but they are in the process of being replaced with &lt;a href="https://appcenter.ms/apps" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Visual Studio Mobile Centre&lt;/a>
.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It was relatively easy to hook up my app to Visual Studio Mobile Centre. First install the required nuget packages. Then add using statements and the following line to your MainActivity.cs file (these instructions are available on the Mobile Centre)&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;">&lt;code class="language-csharp" data-lang="csharp">&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>&lt;span style="color:#66d9ef">using&lt;/span> Microsoft.Azure.Mobile;
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>&lt;span style="color:#66d9ef">using&lt;/span> Microsoft.Azure.Mobile.Analytics;
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>&lt;span style="color:#66d9ef">using&lt;/span> Microsoft.Azure.Mobile.Crashes;
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>&lt;span style="color:#66d9ef">using&lt;/span> Microsoft.Azure.Mobile.Distribute;
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>&lt;span style="color:#66d9ef">using&lt;/span> Microsoft.Azure.Mobile.Push;
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;">&lt;code class="language-csharp" data-lang="csharp">&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>MobileCenter.Start(&lt;span style="color:#e6db74">&amp;#34;[Unique ID]&amp;#34;&lt;/span>,&lt;span style="color:#66d9ef">typeof&lt;/span>(Analytics), &lt;span style="color:#66d9ef">typeof&lt;/span>(Crashes), &lt;span style="color:#66d9ef">typeof&lt;/span>(Distribute), &lt;span style="color:#66d9ef">typeof&lt;/span>(Push));
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>&lt;p>Now you can connect the Mobile Centre to your source code (VSTS in my case) and get it to run a build for every commit.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>One complexity of the build is that you need to supply a keystore file (basically a certificate to digitally sign your app). I found the best way to do this was to use Visual Studio to create the file.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In VS2017 there is a option called Archive Manager under the tools menu. In here click the distribute button and select Ad-hoc. In the signing identity section you can create a keystore file. Enter a few details and a keystore file will be created in AppData\Local\Xamarin\Mono for Android\Keystore[keystore name][keystore name.keystore]&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Once you have added the keystore file to your build you can enable the distribute option. Now you will get an email after every build with a link to install your app.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Every time your app crashes the details will be logged in the crashes section for you to explore and fix the issues.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Analytics section allows you to explore how your app is being used. You can also add Analytics.TrackEvent(&amp;ldquo;Feature X&amp;rdquo;) to measure the usage of different features.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There are more things you can do which I will explore more at another time along with how to get your app into the Google Play Store.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Using Azure WebJobs to Automate Stuff</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2017/using-azure-webjobs-to-automate-stuff/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jun 2017 20:00:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2017/using-azure-webjobs-to-automate-stuff/</guid><description>&lt;p>I keep hearing about Azure WebJobs but I have never used them. Time to change this.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>WebJobs are a feature of Azure App Service that can run a script at a specific time. In my case I would like to hit a specific url of my website at the same time every day.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img class="img-fluid" alt="WebJobs" src="https://storageaccountblog9f5d.blob.core.windows.net/blazor/wp-content/uploads/2017/06/addkeepalivewebjob.png?resize=313%2C615&amp;amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy"
/>
To the right you can see an example of the WebJobs form on the Azure portal that you need to fill in.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You need to supply a name for your webjob.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You need to upload the script that will run in my case I used a powershell script. My script consisted of which basically just loads the url specified.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;">&lt;code class="language-powershell" data-lang="powershell">&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>$progressPreference = &lt;span style="color:#e6db74">&amp;#34;silentlyContinue&amp;#34;&lt;/span>;
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>$result = Invoke-WebRequest -Uri (&lt;span style="color:#e6db74">&amp;#34;https://www.google.com&amp;#34;&lt;/span>) -Method Get -UseBasicParsing;
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>&lt;p>Type refers to if your job will be triggered or run continuously, I want it to be triggered.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Triggers refers to if you want it to be scheduled or manual, something that you can run on an ad hoc basis. I of course want scheduled.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you are familiar with the linux CRON then the next box will make sense to you for everyone else I will try and make sense of it. The box consists of 6 numbers which can either have a value or a *. The numbers correspond to the following {second} {minute} {hour} {day} {month} {day of the week}.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A hourly job would be expressed as 0 0 * * * *, ie every day of week, every month, every day, every hour and only when minute and second equals zero. For more help with this check out the &lt;a href="https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/azure/app-service-web/web-sites-create-web-jobs#CreateScheduledCRON" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">MSDN docs&lt;/a>
about it. I want to use 0 30 21 * * * to run daily at 9.30pm.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That’s it everything setup, now time to wait and see if it works.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Oh no!&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It failed to run at the specified time.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The reason for this is the scheduler requires the feature Always On to be turned on which is not available in the free App Service. Before you reach for your wallets, I found a solution on this &lt;a href="https://tomssl.com/2016/12/20/how-to-get-azure-webjobs-to-run-indefinitely-for-free/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">blog post&lt;/a>
that allows them to run on the free tier.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The thinking behind this solution is you need to keep the website alive throughout the day so Tom has created a script that does this. His script can be found on his blog or on his &lt;a href="https://github.com/TomChantler/Self-KeepAlive" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">github page&lt;/a>
.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Set this script up to run every 5 minutes (0 */5 * * * *) like the example above.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The nextthing you need to do is create a Custom connection string in the Application Settings blade called SecretThing. Tom’s script references this to access the website and keep it alive. The password you need to put in SecretThing can be found in you publish profile (downloaded from the Overview blade in the Azure portal). For more details and a better explanation check out &lt;a href="https://tomssl.com/2016/12/20/how-to-get-azure-webjobs-to-run-indefinitely-for-free/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Tom’s blog&lt;/a>
.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>One last thing to mention about WebJobs is that you can see details about when they have run at https://[YourWebAppName].scm.azurewebsites.net/azurejobs/#/jobs and this can be a great place to help debug your scripts.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Amazon Web Services</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2016/amazon-web-services/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Jul 2016 20:00:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2016/amazon-web-services/</guid><description>&lt;p>I am a big fan of Azure but I know zero about its biggest rival – Amazon Web Services or AWS.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So lets sign up for a free trial and see what it can do. &lt;img class="img-fluid" alt="Amazon Web Services" src="https://storageaccountblog9f5d.blob.core.windows.net/blazor/wp-content/uploads/2016/07/aws-300x169.png?resize=300%2C169" loading="lazy"
/>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The AWS free trial is available from &lt;a href="https://aws.amazon.com/free/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://aws.amazon.com/free/&lt;/a>
and lasts for 12 months. From memory I think the Azure free trial lasted only one month.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To start you need to login with your amazon account and create an AWS account. This requires your name and address and your payment info (you will only get billed if use services not covered by your free trial).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Interestingly AWS requires you to verify your identity via an automated phone call. (I don’t recall doing anything like this for Azure but please correct me if I am wrong.)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Once you are logged in you get a series of links displaying all the different services that are available. First impression is this is a simpler view to Azure’s portal with a similar amount of services. At the top right is an option to select which region you want to use, in Azure I use North Europe and West Europe, AWS has Ireland and Frankfurt.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="create-a-web-app">Create a Web App&lt;a class="anchor ms-1" href="#create-a-web-app">&lt;i class="fas fa-link">&lt;/i>&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>First thing to try is setting up a website. I selected create a web app and I get a page asking me for its basic details (very similar to Azure, however AWS asked what language your code is written in, Azure handles all of these) AWS websites appear to support a host of different options similar to Azure.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The actual creation of your website takes a few moments (like on Azure). However the default URL for websites is similar to &lt;a href="http://test.vjbbimyv7w.eu-central-1.elasticbeanstalk.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">http://test.vjbbimyv7w.eu-central-1.elasticbeanstalk.com/&lt;/a>
which is not quite as nice as the Azure equivalent &lt;a href="http://test.azurewebsites.net" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">http://test.azurewebsites.net&lt;/a>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Azure has a host of command lines available via powershell. AWS has a similar command line interface called AWS CLI, including the option to deploy from git to your website.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>AWS Toolkit for Visual Studio is an extension that allows for the publishing of websites to AWS. (Just like you can publish to Azure)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As I learn more about AWS I will continue to blog about it. &lt;a href="https://www.funkysi1701.com/2016/08/04/amazon-web-services-pt-2/">Amazon Web Services Pt 2&lt;/a>
&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Azure Traffic Manager</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2015/azure-traffic-manager/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Mar 2015 20:00:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2015/azure-traffic-manager/</guid><description>&lt;p>I have spent most of the day tweaking my Azure websites. Lots of fun!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Last week unfortunately Azure had some problems and many websites that were running in the North Europe data centre were unavailable for several hours. And you guessed it my websites were hosted here.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>All hosting providers are going to have downtime from time to time and this is just something you have to take on the chin. The important thing to do in times like these is communicate with your customers about what is going on and that you are doing everything you can to restore service.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>However Azure has some amazing features that you can configure to help manage when downtime occurs.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Azure is Microsoft’s global cloud platform. And it really is global, there are data centres in North Europe, West Europe, Brazil, Japan, two more in Asia and five in the US. In the event of problems it is highly unlikely that more than one of these would go down at once. If all of these are unavailable, I expect the planet earth is facing some kind of cataclysmic event and the fact that my website is down is not a priority.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://storageaccountblog9f5d.blob.core.windows.net/blazor/wp-content/uploads/2015/03/IC750592.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">&lt;img class="img-fluid" alt="IC750592" src="https://storageaccountblog9f5d.blob.core.windows.net/blazor/wp-content/uploads/2015/03/IC750592.jpg?resize=662%2C347" loading="lazy"
/>
&lt;/a>
To take advantage of these multiple data centres, Azure has something called a Traffic Manager.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Traffic Manager has various settings but I am using it in failover mode. This means that if one website goes down, the next one is used.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>All you need to do is create a traffic manager, add two or more websites to it (called endpoints) and choose a page that needs to be monitored so Azure knows which websites are up and which are down.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you are using SSL or custom domain names, there are a few extra steps you need to do. Your custom domain name needs pointing at the traffic manager, not the individual websites. The websites themselves have three domain names, the traffic manager address, the azure address and the custom domain name. The SSL certificate can then be assigned to each website that you have added to the traffic manager.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That was easy wasn’t it, and now if a website goes down traffic manager will use the next one. While testing this, the transition to the next website was almost immediate. I did notice that if you had a browser showing the website open during a problem you sometimes got an error page, I think this was probably due to browser caching, reopening a tab or browser fixed this issue.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Looking back at 2014</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2014/looking-back-at-2014/</link><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2014 20:00:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2014/looking-back-at-2014/</guid><description>&lt;p>As today is New Years eve I thought it would be a good chance to look back over the last year.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img class="img-fluid" alt="" src="https://storageaccountblog9f5d.blob.core.windows.net/blazor/wp-content/uploads/2014/12/tangle.jpg?resize=300%2C256&amp;amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy"
/>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>At the start of the year I finally got agreement for the installation of a 30MB leased line. This was an amazing achievement as I had been really struggling to keep everything working on our ADSL connections and the complexity of the connections was starting to cause problems itself.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>However it was not a smooth process, the site survey revealed a substantial installation cost would be required, however the Council was about to launch a voucher scheme that would give us £3000 off. So most of this was just waiting around for the Council to get things going. By April we had it installed and I have been very happy with the ISP we chose, York Data Service (YDS).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Also during April this year was the end of support for Windows XP and Office 2003. This didn’t impact us too much, mostly due to my constant nagging of the directors to replace our oldest machines. We now only have a couple of machines still running XP and no machines running Office 2003. Most machines are now running Windows 7, I have one Director running Windows 8 for presentations and a few surveyor tablets running windows 8 as well. Like many businesses I am waiting for Windows 10 next year before doing any more substantial replacement of OS.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In May it was decided that I would move more into development work, so I got a new desktop PC and Visual Studio. I am very happy with my new machine (subject to dell fixing a problem later today) So far I have only dipped my toe into development work, this is largely due to needing more time to build up others to do what I do.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In June I made another huge achievement. I got agreement for a new server. This was our first Server 2012 server and allowed us to make huge strides towards virtualizing our services. Once we had this server up and running I was able to decommission two of our Windows Server 2003 machines well before it goes out of support next year.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I am a huge fan of this new server, I have only used a fraction of its memory. Hyper V is really great and I hope to make progress next year into HyperV replication.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Also during 2014 we made huge progress with our clouds software. Within the last few weeks it is running on the Azure platform which will not only make it far easier to expand and create new features it will provide us with cost savings. I am looking forward to learning more about Azure as I get deeper into development.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Wow I achieved a lot didn’t I, on top of this I hired a new IT person and trained him up (still more to do), I have also fixed lots of printers, websites, servers (had a server motherboard die!), and made hundreds of changes to our internal databases.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I don’t know what is in store for 2015. I expect a lots of the same with hopefully more focus on developing in Visual Studio, training myself and my department and getting the last few tweaks into our internal servers.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I would also like to thank everyone that I have worked with over the last 12 months (you know who you are), as you made a lot of what I have just described possible.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>