<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Blogging on Funky Si's Blog</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/tags/blogging/</link><description>Recent content in Blogging on Funky Si's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 25 Sep 2020 20:00:45 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.funkysi1701.com/tags/blogging/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Back to Blogging</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/back-to-blogging/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Sep 2020 20:00:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/back-to-blogging/</guid><description>&lt;p>My last blog post was over six months ago.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Covid 19 has hit the world, and I will be honest I have found it a challenging time.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My Blog had gotten into a bit of a mess. It had become fragmented with different versions of the same thing; I will attempt to explain what has become of my blog.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The original WordPress site can currently be found at &lt;a href="https://www.pwnedpass.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://www.pwnedpass.com/&lt;/a>
I would prefer it to be on a sub-domain of funkysi1701.com but for some reason I haven&amp;rsquo;t been able to get that to work, not sure if it is a limitation of my hosting package. I like WordPress, it is very flexible, easy to get blog posts out there. But I want to write content about development and having a site I can tinker with is important to me.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Most of my WordPress blogs have been imported into dev.to and a few extra have been written on this platform. I like dev.to it is a wonderful place to share content and it has one or two extra features I like.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>dev.to has an integration with Stackbit/Netlify and this became &lt;a href="https://dev.funkysi1701.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://dev.funkysi1701.com&lt;/a>
. I like having a personal site, but having the same content as dev.to. To add content to this site all I need to do is write it on dev.to and some magic will go on behind the scenes and new content will be published.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>However, as a developer I don&amp;rsquo;t like magic, I want to understand what is going on a fiddle with all the settings and make it do what I want.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>dev.to has an API, I can build a site in .Net Core and make API calls to fetch the content I want. I understand APIs, I understand .Net and can customise my site exactly how I want it, plus play about with a .net website. This is what &lt;a href="https://www.funkysi1701.com">https://www.funkysi1701.com&lt;/a>
is now.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So what have I built so far. I have a Server Side Blazor site running .Net 5. Why Server Side and not Client Side I hear you ask? Well only because I have more experience with Server Side and know how to quickly create a website with that technology, I may change it as time goes by, but we will see.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I have two pages a list of my blog posts and a page that displays the content. Both of these use the dev.to API. I lied, there is a third page I hacked together to do some page redirection from the WordPress URLs. This is something I will change as time goes on.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There are lots of improvements I want to do, there are probably also lots of broken images or links as well. Hopefully, this will result in a good platform to blog about as well as on.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>I’m 100 blog posts old</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/i-m-100-blog-posts-old/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Jun 2016 20:00:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/i-m-100-blog-posts-old/</guid><description>&lt;p>That’s right this is the one hundredth post that I have written on this blog.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img class="img-fluid" alt="100-posts-old-L-fwCF_f" src="https://storageaccountblog9f5d.blob.core.windows.net/blazor/wp-content/uploads/2016/06/100-posts-old-L-fwCF_f-300x247.jpeg?resize=300%2C247" loading="lazy"
/>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>So what have I learned in the past 100 posts?&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>It is easier to write a blog before you become a parent. More recently I am increasingly finding it difficult to find the time to blog. It used to be that I could write on an evening, but now James is around I often prefer to play with him, or more often stop him crawling where he shouldn’t.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>I like my job. The inspiration for most of this site is my day job and as you can read, I do a wide variety of different things, but I have a lot more to learn as well.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Finding your niche is hard. 100 posts in and I am still not sure what my niche is. I started out with the broad niche of IT and what I do, I then considered something about IT and fatherhood but I don’t think that topic is really me. My current thinking is maybe DevOps especially as my role these days fits squarely between Development and Operations.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Its time for a refresh. I have been meaning to change the theme of this site for some time and I feel after 100 posts now is as good as time as any. I want to emphasise my skills and what I am learning and increase the emphasis on DevOps, which I think will be my niche.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Watching visitor numbers is addictive. Every day I look at how many people have looked at my blog, but I have yet to see a pattern between what I write and how many reads I get. Is my writing getting better? I don’t know. Are more people reading? Probably not. Will I keep going? Yes&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>So what is next?&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Hopefully a refreshed look in the next few months. Hopefully regular posts. If there is something you want to see on here drop me a message via any of the social media links or put a comment below.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>What is my favourite post?&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Maybe &lt;a href="https://www.funkysi1701.com/2015/05/30/user-groups-and-f/">User Groups and F#&lt;/a>
which proved very popular and got me to start going to user groups something I still enjoy today. I also like &lt;a href="https://www.funkysi1701.com/2016/02/25/coding-myself-into-a-corner/">Coding Myself Into A Corner&lt;/a>
which got me to start thinking more if I was giving myself future problems. But there are many others I like such as &lt;a href="https://www.funkysi1701.com/2015/09/03/baby-magic-and-becoming-a-father/">James and Becoming a father&lt;/a>
&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>