<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Blogging on Funky Si's Blog</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/tags/blogging/</link><description>Recent content in Blogging on Funky Si's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 25 Sep 2020 20:00:45 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.funkysi1701.com/tags/blogging/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Back to Blogging</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2020/back-to-blogging/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Sep 2020 20:00:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2020/back-to-blogging/</guid><description>&lt;p>My last blog post was over six months ago.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Covid 19 has hit the world, and I will be honest I have found it a challenging time.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My Blog had gotten into a bit of a mess. It had become fragmented with different versions of the same thing; I will attempt to explain what has become of my blog.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The original WordPress site can currently be found at &lt;a href="https://www.pwnedpass.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://www.pwnedpass.com/&lt;/a>
I would prefer it to be on a sub-domain of funkysi1701.com but for some reason I haven&amp;rsquo;t been able to get that to work, not sure if it is a limitation of my hosting package. I like WordPress, it is very flexible, easy to get blog posts out there. But I want to write content about development and having a site I can tinker with is important to me.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Most of my WordPress blogs have been imported into dev.to and a few extra have been written on this platform. I like dev.to it is a wonderful place to share content and it has one or two extra features I like.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>dev.to has an integration with Stackbit/Netlify and this became &lt;a href="https://dev.funkysi1701.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://dev.funkysi1701.com&lt;/a>
. I like having a personal site, but having the same content as dev.to. To add content to this site all I need to do is write it on dev.to and some magic will go on behind the scenes and new content will be published.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>However, as a developer I don&amp;rsquo;t like magic, I want to understand what is going on a fiddle with all the settings and make it do what I want.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>dev.to has an API, I can build a site in .Net Core and make API calls to fetch the content I want. I understand APIs, I understand .Net and can customise my site exactly how I want it, plus play about with a .net website. This is what &lt;a href="https://www.funkysi1701.com">https://www.funkysi1701.com&lt;/a>
is now.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So what have I built so far. I have a Server Side Blazor site running .Net 5. Why Server Side and not Client Side I hear you ask? Well only because I have more experience with Server Side and know how to quickly create a website with that technology, I may change it as time goes by, but we will see.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I have two pages a list of my blog posts and a page that displays the content. Both of these use the dev.to API. I lied, there is a third page I hacked together to do some page redirection from the WordPress URLs. This is something I will change as time goes on.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There are lots of improvements I want to do, there are probably also lots of broken images or links as well. Hopefully, this will result in a good platform to blog about as well as on.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Tips for Developing Yourself</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2018/tips-for-developing-yourself/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2018/tips-for-developing-yourself/</guid><description>&lt;p>For a while I have been mentoring a friend and I thought I might share some top tips I have implemented in my career so far.&lt;/p>
&lt;h5 id="hard-work">Hard Work&lt;a class="anchor ms-1" href="#hard-work">&lt;i class="fas fa-link">&lt;/i>&lt;/a>&lt;/h5>
&lt;p>At school I was told: “&lt;em>Only in the dictionary does Success come before Work&lt;/em>“. Yes it is a bit of a corny saying however it has stuck in my head and it’s true. If you want to get anywhere you need to work at it. For many years I just drifted along, but as soon as I knuckled down and worked hard my career started going somewhere.&lt;/p>
&lt;h5 id="write-a-blog">Write a Blog&lt;a class="anchor ms-1" href="#write-a-blog">&lt;i class="fas fa-link">&lt;/i>&lt;/a>&lt;/h5>
&lt;p>Writing is an important skill that you need to work at to improve. If you commit to writing one blog post a week this will help to improve this skill. Even after 150+ blog posts I still feel I need to improve. Not only that it will also help others learn something from you and shows a willingness to contribute to the community. If a Hiring Manager reads your blog he can see some of the stuff you know or care about and may help give you the edge over more experienced candidates.&lt;/p>
&lt;h5 id="soft-skills">Soft Skills&lt;a class="anchor ms-1" href="#soft-skills">&lt;i class="fas fa-link">&lt;/i>&lt;/a>&lt;/h5>
&lt;p>This is one I need to work on but you should concentrate on the so called “&lt;em>Soft Skills&lt;/em>“. Soft Skills are the skills you have for dealing with others. Are you good at talking to people? Or good at getting requirements out of business owners? If so you have some soft skills, don’t underestimate the value that these bring to a team and keep developing them.&lt;/p>
&lt;h5 id="build-a-side-project">Build a Side Project&lt;a class="anchor ms-1" href="#build-a-side-project">&lt;i class="fas fa-link">&lt;/i>&lt;/a>&lt;/h5>
&lt;p>Start building a side project, it doesn’t matter what it is but start building something. I started building a Xamarin app but I have learnt loads of other connected things while doing this, ViewModels, APIs, Build and Deployment processes, Azure Functions. It also gives you ammunition for things to blog about. If you are short of ideas try solving a problem or rebuild something you use.&lt;/p>
&lt;h5 id="use-your-spare-time">Use your spare time&lt;a class="anchor ms-1" href="#use-your-spare-time">&lt;i class="fas fa-link">&lt;/i>&lt;/a>&lt;/h5>
&lt;p>During the day there are moments you can reclaim for learning stuff. There are lots of &lt;a href="https://www.funkysi1701.com/podcasts">podcast&lt;/a>
which discuss useful development topics, listen to these while driving to work. Subscribe to &lt;a href="https://www.funkysi1701.com/pluralsight">pluralsight&lt;/a>
and listen to this while washing up. Don’t get too concerned with learning everything, however think how much more you are learning than not listening at all.&lt;/p>
&lt;h5 id="im-not-ready">I’m not ready!&lt;a class="anchor ms-1" href="#im-not-ready">&lt;i class="fas fa-link">&lt;/i>&lt;/a>&lt;/h5>
&lt;p>We are never ready to take that next step, it is so easy to make excuses like I need to learn x, or know y. The only way to know if you are ready is to try and to keep trying. Iterate as you go so you keep improving yourself. If you wait before you start trying you will end up waiting forever. If you start trying now you will make some small progress and have a better idea of what you need to do to achieve your goals.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Automation of the Promotion of my Blog</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2017/automation-promotion/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2017 20:00:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2017/automation-promotion/</guid><description>&lt;p>I would like to automate the promotion of this blog. Currently to promote this blog on social media I use a few different services.
&lt;img class="img-fluid" alt="" src="https://storageaccountblog9f5d.blob.core.windows.net/blazor/wp-content/uploads/2017/04/img-buffer-illustration-hub-960@2x.png?w=1780&amp;amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy"
/>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Buffer (&lt;a href="https://buffer.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">buffer.com&lt;/a>
) is a service that allows you to schedule updates to the main social media channels (Facebook, Twitter, LinkedIn and Google+)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>IFTTT or If This Then That (&lt;a href="https://ifttt.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">ifttt.com&lt;/a>
) is a service that allows you to connect different online services. You can send an email when a specific event occurs in your calendar for example.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I have been using a combination of these services to share to social media some of my past blog posts. I then add to my calendar details of my blog posts. Then I use IFTTT to add the event to Buffer, and then buffer tweets on a schedule.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This works great however it is a manual process to add my posts to my calendar. I have been using a spreadsheet to help me generate an ics calendar file which I import into my google calendar. There must be a better way of doing this.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I have written some code that reads the RSS feed of my blog and then shares that to Buffer using the Buffer API. The code I am creating is far from finished however I am trying to use the concepts of clean code to make it as flexible as possible.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I have an interface called ISocial which my buffer code implements, but it would be easy to add a class that implements the same interface but uses the twitter or facebook APIs. My code reads from a specific WordPress RSS feed, but it should be easy enough to adapt to read from a SQL database or any other data source.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I am currently unsure what kind of interface to use for this application. I could create a web page that controls the functionality, or maybe just a windows application, or maybe both of these are complicating things and all I need is just a console application that could be added as a scheduled task.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>DZone</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2016/dzone/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Aug 2016 20:00:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2016/dzone/</guid><description>&lt;p>For a while now I have been sharing some of my blog posts on the &lt;a href="https://dzone.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Dzone&lt;/a>
website.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img class="img-fluid" alt="" src="https://storageaccountblog9f5d.blob.core.windows.net/blazor/wp-content/uploads/2016/08/dzone_02.png?w=400&amp;amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy"
/>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Dzone website allows users to submit links to content and I have been submitting the content I have created on this website. This is how Dzone describes themselves:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>With over 1 Million members, DZone.com is one of the web’s largest communities and publishers of technical content for software professionals. Developers from all over the world come to DZone for the latest and best content to hone their skills and advance their careers.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Well this week I have been invited to join the &lt;a href="https://dzone.com/pages/mvb" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">MVB&lt;/a>
(Most Valuable Blogger) programme. The hope is that more of my readers will find my content from the DZone website.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The DZone team will soon start sharing my content on the DZone website and I hope this will result in even more people reading what I have to say.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If nothing else this is clearly telling me that my blog is making a difference, people are taking note of me and what I have to say. I need to keep going and keep writing articles and be more consistent.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>I’m 100 blog posts old</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2016/i-m-100-blog-posts-old/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Jun 2016 20:00:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2016/i-m-100-blog-posts-old/</guid><description>&lt;p>That’s right this is the one hundredth post that I have written on this blog.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img class="img-fluid" alt="100-posts-old-L-fwCF_f" src="https://storageaccountblog9f5d.blob.core.windows.net/blazor/wp-content/uploads/2016/06/100-posts-old-L-fwCF_f-300x247.jpeg?resize=300%2C247" loading="lazy"
/>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>So what have I learned in the past 100 posts?&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>It is easier to write a blog before you become a parent. More recently I am increasingly finding it difficult to find the time to blog. It used to be that I could write on an evening, but now James is around I often prefer to play with him, or more often stop him crawling where he shouldn’t.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>I like my job. The inspiration for most of this site is my day job and as you can read, I do a wide variety of different things, but I have a lot more to learn as well.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Finding your niche is hard. 100 posts in and I am still not sure what my niche is. I started out with the broad niche of IT and what I do, I then considered something about IT and fatherhood but I don’t think that topic is really me. My current thinking is maybe DevOps especially as my role these days fits squarely between Development and Operations.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Its time for a refresh. I have been meaning to change the theme of this site for some time and I feel after 100 posts now is as good as time as any. I want to emphasise my skills and what I am learning and increase the emphasis on DevOps, which I think will be my niche.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Watching visitor numbers is addictive. Every day I look at how many people have looked at my blog, but I have yet to see a pattern between what I write and how many reads I get. Is my writing getting better? I don’t know. Are more people reading? Probably not. Will I keep going? Yes&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>So what is next?&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Hopefully a refreshed look in the next few months. Hopefully regular posts. If there is something you want to see on here drop me a message via any of the social media links or put a comment below.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>What is my favourite post?&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Maybe &lt;a href="https://www.funkysi1701.com/2015/05/30/user-groups-and-f/">User Groups and F#&lt;/a>
which proved very popular and got me to start going to user groups something I still enjoy today. I also like &lt;a href="https://www.funkysi1701.com/2016/02/25/coding-myself-into-a-corner/">Coding Myself Into A Corner&lt;/a>
which got me to start thinking more if I was giving myself future problems. But there are many others I like such as &lt;a href="https://www.funkysi1701.com/2015/09/03/baby-magic-and-becoming-a-father/">James and Becoming a father&lt;/a>
&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>A look back at 2015</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2015/look-back-2015/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2015 20:00:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2015/look-back-2015/</guid><description>&lt;p>Wow! What an amazing year 2015 has been and with 2015 about to end I thought it would be good to look back at what happened in this amazing year.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img class="img-fluid" alt="" src="https://storageaccountblog9f5d.blob.core.windows.net/blazor/wp-content/uploads/2015/12/151218181153-2015-year-in-review-biggest-stories-wrap-up-orig-00025316-large-169.jpg?w=460&amp;amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy"
/>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>January&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I started the year with a declaration that 2015 would be my year of code. Well I have had a few breaks from programming but I have learnt loads this year. I have flitted a bit concentrating on different areas of programming but I think that has broadened my knowledge. I consider myself to be a &lt;a href="http://www.funkysi1701.com/2015/06/03/im-a-developer-now/">programmer now&lt;/a>
, which I didn’t at the start of 2015.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>February&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A first for 2015 was appearing on a &lt;a href="http://www.funkysi1701.com/2015/01/27/podcasts/">podcast&lt;/a>
. The Trekmate podcast &lt;a href="http://www.funkysi1701.com/2015/02/13/ten-forward-episode-135-anti-firbob-is-back-or-simons-desert-island-trek/">Ten Forward&lt;/a>
were the lucky ones that got to experience my first attempt at talking to the world. This continued throughout the year with appearances on &lt;a href="http://www.funkysi1701.com/2015/07/30/upper-pylon-2-1-x-09-the-passenger/">Upper Pylon 2&lt;/a>
, &lt;a href="http://www.funkysi1701.com/2015/10/08/the-hunted-tng-s3-e11-the-battle-bridge/">The Battle Bridge&lt;/a>
and even the &lt;a href="http://www.funkysi1701.com/2015/11/12/star-trek-is-back-in-2017/">Sci-Fi Waffle&lt;/a>
podcast.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It was a sad time for Trekkies at the end of February when &lt;a href="http://www.funkysi1701.com/2015/02/28/hes-really-not-dead-as-long-as-we-remember-him/">Leonard Nimoy&lt;/a>
passed away.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>March&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In March I talked about my recent efforts with &lt;a href="http://www.funkysi1701.com/2015/03/12/azure-traffic-manager/">Azure Traffic Manager&lt;/a>
to help prevent downtime. I also spent a lot of time improving &lt;a href="http://www.funkysi1701.com/2015/03/05/database-deployment/">databases&lt;/a>
which led me to consider ways to deploy it better.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Also in March I attended an IT networking event called &lt;a href="http://www.funkysi1701.com/2015/03/22/networking-event/">ITBoss&lt;/a>
. Free food and drinks and a discussion with fellow IT Managers.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>April&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>April was a bit of a mixed bag. I celebrated my second wedding anniversary but I also said goodbye to my car due to financial reasons.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I played about with a &lt;a href="http://www.funkysi1701.com/2015/04/11/the-raspberry-pi-adventure-starts/">Raspberry Pi&lt;/a>
, mostly with the &lt;a href="http://www.funkysi1701.com/2015/04/15/security-camera-with-raspberry-pi-camera/">camera&lt;/a>
. I really must make some time to play with it more.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>May&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In May I went to a C# User Group called Leeds Sharp, was great fun and I really need to make more time and go back in 2016. It did result in one of my &lt;a href="http://www.funkysi1701.com/2015/05/30/user-groups-and-f/">most popular blog posts&lt;/a>
.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Usually developers don’t enjoy finding bugs in their software but I had great fun when I realised I had a &lt;a href="http://www.funkysi1701.com/2015/05/22/overflow/">Stack Overflow&lt;/a>
in one of my databases, it was easy to fix once I worked out what was going on.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In May the UK went to the polls as we had another General Election.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>June&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In June I celebrated my &lt;a href="http://www.funkysi1701.com/2015/06/17/50th-blog-post/">50th Blog Post&lt;/a>
. Amazing to think I had already written 50 Blog posts, even more now!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Leeds Sharp had a coding challenge, to solve &lt;a href="http://www.funkysi1701.com/2015/06/26/sudoku-challenge/">Sodoku&lt;/a>
puzzle programatically. Didn’t get it finished but made a good stab at it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>July&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In July it was SysAdmin Day and I celebrated with my staff the amazing work we do keeping everything working.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Microsoft launched &lt;a href="http://www.funkysi1701.com/2015/07/11/how-to-upgrade-to-windows-10/">Windows 10&lt;/a>
in July, the latest operating system is being offered for free for a year.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>August&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In August everything changed as my son &lt;a href="http://www.funkysi1701.com/2015/09/03/baby-magic-and-becoming-a-father/">James&lt;/a>
was born. I took time out from blogging and work during this time to spend with James.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Before James was born I stepped down from my involvement with the &lt;a href="http://www.funkysi1701.com/2015/08/03/volunteering-for-a-technical-team/">technical team&lt;/a>
at St Michael le Belfrey.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>September&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In september it was back to work, where I started planning how to add &lt;a href="http://www.funkysi1701.com/2015/09/24/adding-internet-connection-resiliency/">internet connections&lt;/a>
to reduce the chance of outages.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>October&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In October I took James to a &lt;a href="http://www.funkysi1701.com/2015/10/22/james-goes-on-an-adventure-with-daddy/">dads group&lt;/a>
. This was the first time Dad spent time with James without Mummy and it was awesome.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I also celebrated my first birthday after becoming a father, was great to have a card from James. James also got the chance to spend time with my family in Nottingham.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>November&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In November the countdown to Christmas began with James appearing in his first Nativity as Jesus and dressed up as an Elf at a Christingle service.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Exciting Star Trek news was announced this month, a new &lt;a href="http://www.funkysi1701.com/2015/11/12/star-trek-is-back-in-2017/">TV series&lt;/a>
is to be aired in January 2017. No other details yet but very exciting.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>December&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>December is all about &lt;a href="http://www.funkysi1701.com/2015/12/24/christmas-2015-fosters/">Christmas&lt;/a>
and we had a great Christmas time as a family.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sadly York was hit by Floods just after Christmas, luckily my family was not affected but many others have been. Hopefully by the time you read this the cleanup will be well underway.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Before Christmas I spent my time counting down the days with the &lt;a href="http://www.funkysi1701.com/2015/12/17/christmas-count-code/">Advent of Code&lt;/a>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>What will 2016 bring?&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I don’t know. There will be lots more time with James as he continues to learn and develop. I will continue to learn and develop my coding skills. Watch this space as I keep blogging about it.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Black Friday Deals</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2015/black-friday-deals/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Nov 2015 20:00:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2015/black-friday-deals/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="over-50-off-this-black-friday">Over 50% Off this Black Friday!&lt;a class="anchor ms-1" href="#over-50-off-this-black-friday">&lt;i class="fas fa-link">&lt;/i>&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;img class="img-fluid" alt="" src="https://storageaccountblog9f5d.blob.core.windows.net/blazor/wp-content/uploads/2015/11/86910937_t053ll31.jpg?w=660&amp;amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy"
/>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yes your heard it correctly even &lt;a href="https://www.funkysi1701.com">www.funkysi1701.com&lt;/a>
has amazing offers.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It is like the whole world has gone “Black Friday” mad, with every company in the world offering amazing and unmissable deals.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So in an attempt to cash in on all the Black Friday fuss I will write a quick blog post about it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I mentioned 50% off well this month I have blogged 50% less than usual. There is one main reason for this, my new born son James is taking a lot of my time and energy and I think it will take a few months of sporadic blog posts before I get the balance right.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I am not a big fan of spending just for the sake of it. Encouraging people to spend money they don’t have, on things they don’t need shouldn’t be encouraged. However times are hard so companies need to do what they need to, to try and make money.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How to speak to the whole world</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2015/how-to-speak-to-the-whole-world/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Nov 2015 20:00:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2015/how-to-speak-to-the-whole-world/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img class="img-fluid" alt="" src="https://storageaccountblog9f5d.blob.core.windows.net/blazor/wp-content/uploads/2015/10/world.png?w=648&amp;amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy"
/>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Having a website is an easy way to reach people across the globe. This website has reached people in almost every continent.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I have had visitors in each of the following countries.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>United States&lt;/li>
&lt;li>United Kingdom&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Canada&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Germany&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Australia&lt;/li>
&lt;li>India&lt;/li>
&lt;li>France&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Vietnam&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Netherlands&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Poland&lt;/li>
&lt;li>China&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Russia&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Sweden&lt;/li>
&lt;li>European Union&lt;/li>
&lt;li>New Zealand&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Hungary&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Norway&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Spain&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Brazil&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Hong Kong SAR China&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Belgium&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Denmark&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Italy&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Switzerland&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Finland&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Turkey&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Romania&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Singapore&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Israel&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Indonesia&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Serbia&lt;/li>
&lt;li>South Africa&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Lithuania&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Mexico&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Ireland&lt;/li>
&lt;li>South Korea&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Taiwan&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Greece&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Bulgaria&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Ukraine&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Japan&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Austria&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Kenya&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Portugal&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Czech Republic&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Colombia&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Philippines&lt;/li>
&lt;li>United Arab Emirates&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Moldova&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Slovenia&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Malaysia&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Ghana&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Argentina&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Venezuela&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Bangladesh&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Iceland&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Croatia&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Panama&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Belarus&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Slovakia&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Albania&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Kazakhstan&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Algeria&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Puerto Rico&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Thailand&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Estonia&lt;/li>
&lt;li>U.S. Virgin Islands&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Pakistan&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Latvia&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Chile&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Sri Lanka&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Malta&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Costa Rica&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Morocco&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Ethiopia&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Réunion&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Uruguay&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Honduras&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Cyprus&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Tunisia&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Nepal&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Cameroon&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Paraguay&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Gambia&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Peru&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Mauritius&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Bermuda&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Cambodia&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Jersey&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Egypt&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Macedonia&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>How cool is that! If you know anyone from any country not mentioned above, send them a link to this page and lets see if we can get this blog seen in even more countries.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Only a few years ago it would have been incredibly difficult to communicate your ideas to the whole world, now it is available to everyone at a touch of a button.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The internet has a lot to answer for. On the one hand it is blamed for a decrease of communication between people as they stare at their devices all the time, but on the other hand it has greatly improved communication over larger distances like the use of Skype or the ability to broadcast your ideas on websites and social media.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Choosing a Blog Theme</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2015/blog-theme/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2015 20:00:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2015/blog-theme/</guid><description>&lt;p>You may have noticed that my blog has a new home. It can now be found on its own domain &lt;a href="http://www.funkysi1701.com">http://www.funkysi1701.com&lt;/a>
. This change not only gives me more flexibility to make any change I like, it also feels good to have a website again. If you had followed my blog, do keep following it at the new location.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I have also been playing about with giving the site a new look, hope you all like it. I have gone for a more image focussed front page. No doubt in a few weeks I will be bored and change the look again.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I have recently been reading about blogging and one suggestion is to have a clear theme, or idea of what the blog is about. I am not sure my blog has a clear theme.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When I started blogging I was more interested in blogging than thinking about what I was blogging about. The vague theme I worked off was to talk about what I do, to answer the question, &amp;ldquo;What do you do?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I think this is a fairly good theme, but it could probably do with some refinement. The best themed blogs are specialist or about something specific. As I am generally learning about development, rather than doing development I think this should be part of what I concentrate my blogs about. A minority of my blogs can continue to be about the other things I spend my time doing, as it’s always good to have a break from the main “meat” of the blog every now and then.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The people who read my blogs are split between technical people and non-technical people, so I would like to continue to explain what I do in non-technical terms. This is an essential skill for a developer (or SysAdmin) as you will always need to explain what you are doing, or discuss requirements. It is not an easy skill and like development itself, the more I do it the better at it I will become.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So watch this space for the blogs to come. I know I will be working with Azure over the next few weeks so maybe some blogs about that, maybe some more SQL blogs or maybe about what I learn next.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>