<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>2015-06 on Funky Si's Blog</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/2015/06/</link><description>Recent content in 2015-06 on Funky Si's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 Jun 2015 20:00:45 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.funkysi1701.com/2015/06/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Sudoku Challenge</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2015/sudoku-challenge/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Jun 2015 20:00:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2015/sudoku-challenge/</guid><description>&lt;p>Last night I went to a Code Dojo at Leeds Sharp (the coding user group I have started going to). A Code Dojo is a programming challenge that people work on usually in pairs.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The challenge that we worked on was to code a solution to the puzzle game Sudoku. The code we worked with can be found on github.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img class="img-fluid" alt="" src="https://storageaccountblog9f5d.blob.core.windows.net/blazor/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/2000px-Sudoku-by-L2G-20050714.svg_.png?resize=660%2C660&amp;amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy"
/>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I don’t know much about Sudoku but the game goes like this. You start with a 9×9 grid, and the idea is to fill in all the missing numbers.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Each Row can only use each digit 1 to 9 once, each column can only use each digit 1 to 9 once and each subgrid (3×3) can only use each digit once.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I worked with Richard one of the Leeds Sharp organisers, we started by trying to loop through each empty cell and insert values in a brute force attack, but this approach didn’t get us very far (literally as the application crashed!)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The approach that we needed to use was to loop through calculating possible values.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It was only when I sat down at this dojo did I realise how much I still have to learn, but while talking with Richard about different approaches and different coding structures I started to learn.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Fathers Day</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2015/fathers-day/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Jun 2015 20:00:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2015/fathers-day/</guid><description>&lt;p>In the UK today is Fathers Day. Happy Fathers Day Dad!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I thought I might talk about how he encouraged my interest in technology, especially as in about 8 weeks I will become a parent and will have someone to encourage and inspire.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I am going to sound really old but when I was born there was no internet, no mobile phones and computers more often appeared in sci-fi than in your home.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The first computer I remember us owning was a Lynx. A quick google reveals there were a number of different models, I have no idea what we had but here is what I found.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img class="img-fluid" alt="" src="https://storageaccountblog9f5d.blob.core.windows.net/blazor/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/PRODPIC-2926.jpg?resize=300%2C185&amp;amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy"
/>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In March 1983 the Lynx 48K was released, in September this was upgraded to 96K. In December 1983 a new Lynx was released with 128K. To put these numbers in perspective on my desktop is an image file that is 123K! The CPU in this computer was rated at between 4 and 6Mhz. (Modern PCs have CPUs around the 1.5Ghz or 1500Mhz)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Lynx we had, didn’t have a disk drive or a mouse. Programs were loaded from audio tapes (Audio tape was a form of data storage that came before CDs where data was stored on magnetic tape, most often used for music) The tapes we had would often get stuck and data wouldn’t load. The answer to this was to fast-forward/rewind the tape or hit the tape on your leg. For some reason this is a memory I still have of my dad hitting a tape on his leg to get a game or something else to load on the lynx. We also had a joystick for playing some of the games. I believe we also had an early thermal printer.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My memory of the Lynx is in black and white. The reason for this is that the Lynx was connected to an old black and white TV, it was a special treat when we connected the main colour TV to the Lynx.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We had a wide range of games for the Lynx, I can remember Jet Set Willy, and Diggerman. But there were also programs which my father had created. The Lynx had a form of BASIC where you can write you own programs and my father spent many hours writing programs for me and my sister. (We actually never realized this at the time)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>With that as my introduction to computers is it any wonder that I do what I do now? Now what should I do for my child to encourage them in a similar way?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As a family we never owned a games console. Not sure if this was a financial or moral choice but it is something I will have to think about. I want my child to be knowledgeable about computers and able to compete in the competitive job market, but I also want them to know about science and nature and to enjoy their childhood. Lots of technology choices to make over the next few years.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Runaway SQL Log growth</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2015/runaway-sql-log-growth/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Jun 2015 20:00:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2015/runaway-sql-log-growth/</guid><description>&lt;p>Today is my day off, but I wake up and have a quick look at &lt;a href="https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/i-love-nagios/">nagios&lt;/a>
to see if there is anything I need to worry about. Yes there is, SQL Server has run out of disk space on its data disk.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I race downstairs and VPN onto the server to find out what has happened. One of my monitoring databases has had runaway log growth and is over 80Gb is size.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;">&lt;code class="language-sql" data-lang="sql">&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>BACKUP LOG [DBName] &lt;span style="color:#66d9ef">WITH&lt;/span> TRUNCATE_ONLY
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>DBCC SHRINKFILE(&lt;span style="color:#e6db74">&amp;#39;DBName_Log&amp;#39;&lt;/span>)
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>&lt;p>Free disk space is back to normal, all users will be unaware of the problem and everything is fine again. I create a daily job that runs the above code, that way it should stay a manageable size.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Next I need to find out why it happened and to prevent it happening again in the future (Next time I have a day off I want to lie in!)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I check the SQL logs and notice&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BACKUP LOG WITH TRUNCATE_ONLY or WITH NO_LOG is deprecated. The simple recovery model should be used to automatically truncate the transaction log.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Then I remember what I have done to cause this issue. I have a separate disk for my backup files and earlier in the week I noticed this disk was filling up, a large amount of space was taken up by transactional backup files. I thought I don’t need to backup the transactions for this non critical database, I will just do a full backup at the start of everyday.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>However what I forgot is that a transactional backup keeps the log file under control, once this backup was stopped the log file grew uncontrollably. The answer, change the database from FULL mode to SIMPLE.&lt;a href="https://storageaccountblog9f5d.blob.core.windows.net/blazor/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/image002.png" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">&lt;img class="img-fluid" alt="image002" src="https://storageaccountblog9f5d.blob.core.windows.net/blazor/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/image002-300x270.png?resize=300%2C270" loading="lazy"
/>
&lt;/a>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is my understanding of how backups work in FULL mode. A full backup is done at the start of the day which resets the log file, then changes in the database are stored in the log file, this is backed up into a transactional backup and the log file gets reset. If you have regular transactional backups throughout the day the log file doesn’t grow too much, however with no transactional backups your log file contains an entire days worth of changes and so for a monitoring database this could be quite large.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In SIMPLE mode you can’t do transactional backups and the log doesn’t grow uncontrollably. This shouldn’t be used for production databases as if there is a problem you could loose data.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>