<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>100 on Funky Si's Blog</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/tags/100/</link><description>Recent content in 100 on Funky Si's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Jun 2016 20:00:45 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.funkysi1701.com/tags/100/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>I’m 100 blog posts old</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts-old/i-m-100-blog-posts-old/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Jun 2016 20:00:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts-old/i-m-100-blog-posts-old/</guid><description>&lt;p>That’s right this is the one hundredth post that I have written on this blog.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img class="img-fluid" alt="100-posts-old-L-fwCF_f" src="https://storageaccountblog9f5d.blob.core.windows.net/blazor/wp-content/uploads/2016/06/100-posts-old-L-fwCF_f-300x247.jpeg?resize=300%2C247" loading="lazy"
/>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>So what have I learned in the past 100 posts?&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>It is easier to write a blog before you become a parent. More recently I am increasingly finding it difficult to find the time to blog. It used to be that I could write on an evening, but now James is around I often prefer to play with him, or more often stop him crawling where he shouldn’t.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>I like my job. The inspiration for most of this site is my day job and as you can read, I do a wide variety of different things, but I have a lot more to learn as well.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Finding your niche is hard. 100 posts in and I am still not sure what my niche is. I started out with the broad niche of IT and what I do, I then considered something about IT and fatherhood but I don’t think that topic is really me. My current thinking is maybe DevOps especially as my role these days fits squarely between Development and Operations.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Its time for a refresh. I have been meaning to change the theme of this site for some time and I feel after 100 posts now is as good as time as any. I want to emphasise my skills and what I am learning and increase the emphasis on DevOps, which I think will be my niche.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Watching visitor numbers is addictive. Every day I look at how many people have looked at my blog, but I have yet to see a pattern between what I write and how many reads I get. Is my writing getting better? I don’t know. Are more people reading? Probably not. Will I keep going? Yes&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>So what is next?&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Hopefully a refreshed look in the next few months. Hopefully regular posts. If there is something you want to see on here drop me a message via any of the social media links or put a comment below.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>What is my favourite post?&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Maybe &lt;a href="https://www.funkysi1701.com/2015/05/30/user-groups-and-f/">User Groups and F#&lt;/a>
which proved very popular and got me to start going to user groups something I still enjoy today. I also like &lt;a href="https://www.funkysi1701.com/2016/02/25/coding-myself-into-a-corner/">Coding Myself Into A Corner&lt;/a>
which got me to start thinking more if I was giving myself future problems. But there are many others I like such as &lt;a href="https://www.funkysi1701.com/2015/09/03/baby-magic-and-becoming-a-father/">James and Becoming a father&lt;/a>
&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>