<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>WordPress on Funky Si's Blog</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/tags/wordpress/</link><description>Recent content in WordPress on Funky Si's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2015 20:00:45 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.funkysi1701.com/tags/wordpress/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Choosing a Blog Theme</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2015/blog-theme/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2015 20:00:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2015/blog-theme/</guid><description>&lt;p>You may have noticed that my blog has a new home. It can now be found on its own domain &lt;a href="http://www.funkysi1701.com">http://www.funkysi1701.com&lt;/a>
. This change not only gives me more flexibility to make any change I like, it also feels good to have a website again. If you had followed my blog, do keep following it at the new location.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I have also been playing about with giving the site a new look, hope you all like it. I have gone for a more image focussed front page. No doubt in a few weeks I will be bored and change the look again.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I have recently been reading about blogging and one suggestion is to have a clear theme, or idea of what the blog is about. I am not sure my blog has a clear theme.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When I started blogging I was more interested in blogging than thinking about what I was blogging about. The vague theme I worked off was to talk about what I do, to answer the question, &amp;ldquo;What do you do?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I think this is a fairly good theme, but it could probably do with some refinement. The best themed blogs are specialist or about something specific. As I am generally learning about development, rather than doing development I think this should be part of what I concentrate my blogs about. A minority of my blogs can continue to be about the other things I spend my time doing, as it’s always good to have a break from the main “meat” of the blog every now and then.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The people who read my blogs are split between technical people and non-technical people, so I would like to continue to explain what I do in non-technical terms. This is an essential skill for a developer (or SysAdmin) as you will always need to explain what you are doing, or discuss requirements. It is not an easy skill and like development itself, the more I do it the better at it I will become.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So watch this space for the blogs to come. I know I will be working with Azure over the next few weeks so maybe some blogs about that, maybe some more SQL blogs or maybe about what I learn next.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>