<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>2015-02 on Funky Si's Blog</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/2015/02/</link><description>Recent content in 2015-02 on Funky Si's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2015 09:00:45 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.funkysi1701.com/2015/02/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Source Code for Game of Life</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2015/source-code-for-game-of-life/</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2015 09:00:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2015/source-code-for-game-of-life/</guid><description>&lt;p>Last week I blogged about the Game of Life.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Well it took some searching through dead hard drives and old USB storage but I found the program I wrote, and better than that I have figured out how to turn it back into source code.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The file date is November 2004 and the source code has no comments so I don’t know what was going through my head when I wrote it, or even what some of it does.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To view the source code download &lt;a href="https://storageaccountblog9f5d.blob.core.windows.net/blazor/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/Life.src_.zip" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Life.src&lt;/a>
, to download the finished program download &lt;a href="https://storageaccountblog9f5d.blob.core.windows.net/blazor/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/Life.zip" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Life&lt;/a>
.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img class="img-fluid" alt="Life" src="https://storageaccountblog9f5d.blob.core.windows.net/blazor/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/Life.jpg" loading="lazy"
/>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I am actually surprised I was expected the code to be much worse than it was, I am not saying it is good, but I can see more than one method and I can’t see any code that obviously is repeated. I can see some terrible variable names. Note to future self don’t use tmp676_674!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Assuming that I wrote this in 2004 what would I have been doing then? It was before I started working in IT. (Hard to imagine I know!) It may even have been before I started living with Keith, before he recruited me for my first IT role. I think I was probably working as an administrator for Defra at this point.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If we put 2004 in technical terms, it was before I joined facebook, Office 2003 and XP would have been installed on my PC, and probably felt brand new.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Choosing a Blog Theme</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2015/blog-theme/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2015 20:00:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2015/blog-theme/</guid><description>&lt;p>You may have noticed that my blog has a new home. It can now be found on its own domain &lt;a href="http://www.funkysi1701.com">http://www.funkysi1701.com&lt;/a>
. This change not only gives me more flexibility to make any change I like, it also feels good to have a website again. If you had followed my blog, do keep following it at the new location.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I have also been playing about with giving the site a new look, hope you all like it. I have gone for a more image focussed front page. No doubt in a few weeks I will be bored and change the look again.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I have recently been reading about blogging and one suggestion is to have a clear theme, or idea of what the blog is about. I am not sure my blog has a clear theme.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When I started blogging I was more interested in blogging than thinking about what I was blogging about. The vague theme I worked off was to talk about what I do, to answer the question, &amp;ldquo;What do you do?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I think this is a fairly good theme, but it could probably do with some refinement. The best themed blogs are specialist or about something specific. As I am generally learning about development, rather than doing development I think this should be part of what I concentrate my blogs about. A minority of my blogs can continue to be about the other things I spend my time doing, as it’s always good to have a break from the main “meat” of the blog every now and then.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The people who read my blogs are split between technical people and non-technical people, so I would like to continue to explain what I do in non-technical terms. This is an essential skill for a developer (or SysAdmin) as you will always need to explain what you are doing, or discuss requirements. It is not an easy skill and like development itself, the more I do it the better at it I will become.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So watch this space for the blogs to come. I know I will be working with Azure over the next few weeks so maybe some blogs about that, maybe some more SQL blogs or maybe about what I learn next.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Ten Forward Episode #135 – Anti Firbob is Back or Simon’s Desert Island Trek</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2015/ten-forward-episode-135-anti-firbob-is-back-or-simons-desert-island-trek/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2015 20:00:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2015/ten-forward-episode-135-anti-firbob-is-back-or-simons-desert-island-trek/</guid><description>&lt;p>The podcast I recorded the other week has been released, why not have a listen by heading over to &lt;a href="http://www.trekmate.org.uk/ten-forward-episode-135-anti-firbob-is-back-or-simons-desert-island-trek/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">trekmate.org.uk&lt;/a>
and comment on their &lt;a href="http://forum.trekmatefamily.com/2015/02/ten-forward-135-antifirbob-is-back-or-simons-desert-island-trek/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">forums&lt;/a>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This week Sina, Chris and Paul welcome Simon Foster, Trek Mate’s News Editor, to do discuss his Desert Island Trek choices. Paul becomes Firbob, or AntiFirbob, or&amp;hellip;something like that. Boo hiss Firbob. Every one listen and decide – Simon or Firbob?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You can reach Simon here:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/funkysi1701" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">@funkysi1701&lt;/a>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Complaints to @firbob1&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You can reach the rest of the gang here:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/queenkatblue" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">@queenkatblue&lt;/a>
, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/chriscantfly" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">@chriscantfly&lt;/a>
, or &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/TenForwardPod" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">facebook.com/TenForwardPod&lt;/a>
&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Game of Life</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2015/game-of-life/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2015 09:00:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2015/game-of-life/</guid><description>&lt;p>Many, many years ago I tried to learn Java. I didn’t get very far but one of the things I built was The Game of Life.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Unfortunately I can not find the code I wrote, probably a good things as it is probably amusingly bad.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now you are probably asking what is the &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Conway%27s_Game_of_Life" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Game of Life&lt;/a>
? The game of life, sometimes called cellular automation, is a simulation of cells being born and dying. It is sometimes called Conway’s Game of Life after the British mathematician who devised it in 1970.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img class="img-fluid" alt="" src="https://www.funkysi1701.com/images/Gospers_glider_gun.gif" loading="lazy"
width="250" height="180"
/>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The game has several rules:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Any cell with less than three neighbours will die on the next turn&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Any cell with three neighbours lives on to the next turn&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Any cell with more than three neighbours will die on the next turn&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Any dead cell with three live neighbours will be born on the next turn&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>Now I had not thought about this game until the other day when I came across a &lt;a href="https://chaosnil.wordpress.com/2015/02/09/new-project-conways-game-of-life-in-every-language/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">blog&lt;/a>
and a &lt;a href="https://github.com/chaomodus/gameoflife" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">github page&lt;/a>
which sparked my interest again. This version is written in javascript, but the blog mentions a desire to build this program in many different languages. I want to build this with visual studio in C# as it should provide a good training exercise.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There are several problems I need to overcome to achieve this, I am currently trying to work out how to &amp;ldquo;draw&amp;rdquo; the cells. My current thinking is that maybe I can code it using characters to display the cells and then replace with pixels once I have the logic correct. Well lots for me to learn!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Great British Code Off</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2015/great-british-code-off/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2015 20:00:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2015/great-british-code-off/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img class="img-fluid" alt="Great British Code Off" src="https://storageaccountblog9f5d.blob.core.windows.net/blazor/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/logo.jpg" loading="lazy"
/>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Great British Bake Off and The Great British Sewing Bee are very popular TV shows. Each week the contestants take part in a baking or sewing challenge and the judges choose the best and the worst, with the worst having to leave. This is very entertaining as you watch the drama between the contestants and the reactions as the judges tell them they are rubbish.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Could this simple format be applied to computer programming? I think it could.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The only developers I know argue about the best way of tackling different problems, despite being friends. I am going to assume that this is typical behaviour and not unique to them. So for this TV show, we will split the contestants into pairs, that way we would get the added drama of how well they work together.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I am still undecided if the pairs stick together each week with one pair leaving or if we randomize the pairs with one person leaves. The second option would cause there to be a group of three every other week, not sure if this would be a benefit or a curse for that group.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My friends who are experienced programmers have agreed to be the judges, they both have experience of hiring and firing people, know what to look for in good code, and never agree so should be entertaining enough.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On the bake off the contestants don’t really know how well they have done until the judges cut into their cake and take a bite. For the code off we could not compile the code until the judges run it, would make coding extra difficult as if the contestants are anything like me, I run my code every five minutes to see what affect that change has made.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So what challenges can we come up with?&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Web Design week&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Stored Procedure week&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Mobile App week&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Loops&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Logic problems&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Bugs weeks&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Performance issues&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>I think we are onto a winner here. What does everyone else think?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Laziness</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2015/laziness/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2015 20:00:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2015/laziness/</guid><description>&lt;p>I am lazy, I won’t try and deny that. When my alarm goes off in the morning, I will snooze it for twenty minutes or so before getting out of bed.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img class="img-fluid" alt="" src="https://storageaccountblog9f5d.blob.core.windows.net/blazor/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/bill-gates-quote.jpg" loading="lazy"
/>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In my work my laziness continues. Remote Desktop (or RDP) is probably my number one laziness tool. For those that don’t know RDP allows you to connect to another computer and access it like you were sat in front of it. So I can be sat at my desk and RDP into any other computer in the office including any server. However this laziness tool does sometimes require a bit of effort sometimes, powering on the target computer, logging on locally, making sure the user account you are using is allowed to use RDP.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Writing a script is another example of a laziness tool. I often get asked to do tedious and long-winded task, because I am lazy I will go out of my way to learn how to write a script to do this, so that I can run this script and do this long-winded task in a matter of seconds. There are loads of different types of scripts from database SQL scripts, to PowerShell scripts that can do almost anything on your server.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>PowerShell is something Microsoft are really pushing at the moment, you can even write scripts to create new user accounts, so no longer will you have to remember to tick that tickbox for every new user account. And because PowerShell is part of almost all MS technologies you can link Exchange to Active Directory and you don’t even have to remember the right syntax as PowerShell has a built-in help command to tell you how to run that useful command.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As I am now moving into a more developer role can I continue to be lazy? I sure can. Code should be written once and reused as often as possible and this is one of the features of OOP (Object Oriented Programming).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It can be as simple as creating a master page so you don’t need to recreate the same code on every one of your webpages. Or every time you find yourself rewriting the same code again, you plug it into a method so it can be called again and again.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But of course the ultimate way to be lazy is of course get yourself some staff and spend all day getting them to do everything. If you are lucky they may even try and adopt some of these lazy ideas.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>