<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Microsoft on Funky Si's Blog</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/tags/microsoft/</link><description>Recent content in Microsoft on Funky Si's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 14 Jun 2022 18:00:45 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.funkysi1701.com/tags/microsoft/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Scottish Summit 2022</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2022/scottishsummit/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Jun 2022 18:00:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2022/scottishsummit/</guid><description>&lt;p>On the 10th and 11th June 2022 &lt;a href="https://scottishsummit.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Scottish Summit 2022&lt;/a>
happened and I was there. It was an awesome event and I will attempt to summarise what happened.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="thursday-9th">Thursday 9th&lt;a class="anchor ms-1" href="#thursday-9th">&lt;i class="fas fa-link">&lt;/i>&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>On Thursday 9th I travelled down on the train full of excitement about the event. Once I got to the hotel, I was immediately greeted by &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/OfficialCookJ" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">James Cook&lt;/a>
, I was obviously in the right place, this weekend is going to be good.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="friday-10th">Friday 10th&lt;a class="anchor ms-1" href="#friday-10th">&lt;i class="fas fa-link">&lt;/i>&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The hotel was less then 5 mins walk to the conference, which was being held at the Technology and Innovation Centre, University of Strathclyde. Registration was simple wave your tickets (which were free, apart from a contribution to charity), and you get your badge and a wrist band. (Pink for people contact, blue for hold back) I then got chatting to &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/MrKeithAtherton" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Keith Atherton&lt;/a>
, who amazingly lived in part of the world where I grew up. (Amazing what you learn at conferences!)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://www.funkysi1701.com/images/scottishsummit.jpg" align="left" >Time for the Keynote talk. Which of course because we are in scotland was introduced by bagpipes marching through the room! The talk was given by &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/cmcginley" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Connell McGinley&lt;/a>
and was titled Disability Awareness &amp;amp; Inclusivity. This talk was amazing. Connell is deaf and gave the entire talk with sign language and this was translated for the rest of us to hear. Connell talked about his career and the barriers he faced. Microsoft Teams was an amazing improvement to his work life, as the captioning allowed him to talk with customers for the first time!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The purple pound is the amount of spending power people with some kind of disability (15% of the worlds population) have and it is approx $13 trillion. If businesses can open their products up to more people it is a win for everyone. This was a really powerful way to open up the conference.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Next up was &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/davesmall28" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">David Small&lt;/a>
talking about Azure DevOps pipelines and Power Platform. I don&amp;rsquo;t know much about Power Platform however all the DevOps stuff was great, some of it reinforced stuff I already knew, some was new.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/samcogan" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Sam Cogan&lt;/a>
was next talking about Infrastructure as Code. Resources for this talk are on his &lt;a href="https://github.com/sam-cogan/events/tree/main/Scottish%20Summit%202022" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">github&lt;/a>
This was a great comparison of different tools for doing Infrastructure as Code. Terraform, Pulumi, Bicep, ARM templates where all covered. The difference between stateless and stateful tools. If you have a state file you need to look after it, so if you don&amp;rsquo;t need this think about using a stateless tool. If you are only using Azure consider Azure. If you are a C# (other languages are available) think about using Pulumi (which I have used and quite like)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Getting Started with Static Web Apps was next with &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/PoornimaNayar" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Poornima Nayar&lt;/a>
this was a great overview of Static Web Apps but as I already use Static Web Apps this was mainly reinforcing what I already knew. However the Static Web App CLI was mentioned which I didn&amp;rsquo;t know about so I am going to spend some time looking at that! Another thing that was mentioned was GraphQL which is a language agnostic way of building APIs which I also want to learn more about. Resources for this talk can be found &lt;a href="https://poornimanayar.co.uk/community/resources-for-my-talk-at-azure-thursdays-july-2021/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">here&lt;/a>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Next was Naming stuff in Azure with &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Ba4bes" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Barbara Forbes&lt;/a>
, she went through the challenges of getting naming right, especially with all the exceptions Azure throws into the mix. Tagging your resources can really help. Also Azure Policy can help report on what you have (and even enforce it, if you are careful). Lots of interesting stuff, as my naming strategy is non existent at the moment!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Defender for Cloud Apps with &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/getofmeland" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Charlie Gough&lt;/a>
. This was his first talk and he did really well despite technical problems. This was a security talk, I thought it was going to be about securing the apps you have built, but it was more about securing the apps that the users in your company are using. Still useful to know about, but not really my thing. Sorry Charlie!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Last talk of the day was &amp;lsquo;What I didn&amp;rsquo;t know about Office 365&amp;rsquo; with &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/sharoneweaver" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Sharon Weaver&lt;/a>
Sharon went through Shifts, Planner and Forms all included in your Office 365 subscription.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="saturday-11th">Saturday 11th&lt;a class="anchor ms-1" href="#saturday-11th">&lt;i class="fas fa-link">&lt;/i>&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>To start the second day I had &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/webmaxru" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Maxim Salnikov&lt;/a>
talk about Static Web apps, if I had know it was about Static Web Apps again I may have chosen a different talk but this was still a great talk. Again the CLI was mentioned which I really need to investigate further.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Next up was James Cook&amp;rsquo;s talk Monitor Azure DevOps and GitHub with Sentinel. This was all about securing your code repositories with Sentinel and looking through the logs at what is happening. To use this tech you need either a GitHub Enterprise subscription or Azure DevOps using Azure AD Logins as it is designed more for the Enterprise than a one man band kind like me, however I will see if I can have a play around with it and see what I can learn.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/TechieLass" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Sarah Lean&lt;/a>
gave a talk about the state of IT Ops tools in the hybrid age. I enjoyed this talk, Sarah added extra fun elements like talking about the Scottish language and the highland cow. The first tool mentioned was Windows Admin Centre. I have heard about this but never used it, must have come out after I switched from Ops to Dev. Looks very Azure like. Azure Update Management was mentioned next, which I have used and works really well. This is the next generation of Update Management, a bit like WSUS from my server days. Azure Policy was mentioned again, a great tool for reporting and/or enforcing things. Azure Arc was mentioned, a way to bring Azure to you. With all these tools consider why you want to use them, what benefits do they bring, not just because it it shiny!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Mental Health with &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/AzureRory" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Rory Neary&lt;/a>
. This was one of my favourite talks. Rory talked about his mental health problems, his challenges, some of his coping mechanisms some of which involved the power platform. He encouraged us all to be more open about talking about Mental Health. Lots of talks have a solution to a problem, this one didn&amp;rsquo;t, but that Ok. We are all on a journey complete with its ups and downs.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Accessibility for Blazor with &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/DennieDeclercq" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Dennie Declercq&lt;/a>
. I wasn&amp;rsquo;t as keen on this talk as some of the others, while I agree Accessibility is very important the solutions presented felt very generic and not really specific to Blazor. However I do have some ideas to try now and the accessibility browser extension sounds like a great idea.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="after-hours">After Hours&lt;a class="anchor ms-1" href="#after-hours">&lt;i class="fas fa-link">&lt;/i>&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>One of the best things about the conference was talking to people between sessions and afterwards. I am an introvert and tend to keep quiet but even I managed to talk to (for me) loads of people. Some of these I had previously connected to on twitter, and some were brand new on the day. I would encourage anyone reading this to reach out to the community, go to an event like this, you will be surprised how friendly and helpful people can be.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Microsoft Ignite | The Tour – London</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2019/microsoft-ignite-the-tour-london/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2019 20:00:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2019/microsoft-ignite-the-tour-london/</guid><description>&lt;p>I have just spent the first day at the conference Microsoft Ignite | The Tour.
&lt;img class="img-fluid" alt="Alt Text" src="https://storageaccountblog9f5d.blob.core.windows.net/blazor/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/D0UTj08XgAEo1YJ.jpg?fit=662%2C440&amp;amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy"
/>
The conference was free I just needed to arrange travel and accommodation. Microsoft have really looked after me and all the other guests, breakfast and lunch has been provided, I got a free t-shirt, coffee (or tea) all day plus a beer or glass of wine to end the day. And that’s before you collect any free stuff the vendors are giving away.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The first session was Designing resilient cloud applications with &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/CodeMillMatt" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Matt Soucoup&lt;/a>
and talked about some cloud technologies like Azure key vault and serving static files from blob storage. Unfortunately this had a few technical issues with the demos. I think it was just connectivity with the MongoDB backend but this slightly spoiled the session. As this was the only technical problem I noticed all day I can let it pass.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Next was a session on Azure DevOps mainly build and release pipelines called Deploying your application faster and safer with &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/bbenz" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Brian Benz&lt;/a>
. A lot of this I knew but good to reinforce I am doing things correctly.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Next was a session on Application Insights called Detecting application anomalies with Telemetry with Matt Soucoup.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Probably the most useful session was on Docker and Kubernetes called Integrate containers and Kubernetes into your Azure DevOps build and release model with &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/crad77" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Marco De Sanctis&lt;/a>
. Going to spend some time looking through the examples from this session.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A session on Serverless covered Azure Functions, Azure Logic apps and the other Azure Serverless offerings. Investing in Serverless: less servers, more code with &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/simona_cotin" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Simona Cotin&lt;/a>
.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Lastly was a panel discussion on the changes facing IT Pros and SysAdmins. What is the future of the IT Pro in a DevOps &amp;amp; Cloudy world? with &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/jenstirrup" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Jennifer Stirrup&lt;/a>
, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/bakionur" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Baki Onur Okutucu&lt;/a>
, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/AmyKateNicho" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Amy Boyd&lt;/a>
and &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/TheOpsMgr" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Stephen Thair&lt;/a>
. Should they learn to code, how should they make sure they keep up.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Tomorrow I have a loads more sessions, including ones about mental health, Azure pipelines, more Kubernetes stuff and dealing with failure.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Surface Book Review</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2016/surface-book-review/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2016 20:00:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2016/surface-book-review/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img class="img-fluid" alt="" src="https://storageaccountblog9f5d.blob.core.windows.net/blazor/wp-content/uploads/2016/02/en-INTL-PDP0-Surface-Book-CR9-00001-P2.jpg?w=780&amp;amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy"
/>
I have just bought myself a new laptop, but it is not just any laptop it is a &lt;a href="https://www.microsoftstore.com/store/msuk/en_GB/pdp/productID.332604800" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Microsoft Surface Book&lt;/a>
.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I think this is probably the first time I have bought myself a top of the range laptop and after a few days of use I am loving it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Surface Book is the latest in Microsoft’s Surface line of tablets but the first to feature a keyboard and be more like a traditional laptop. The keyboard is detachable from the keyboard so you can use the Surface Book like a tablet.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As it is a top of the range laptop, it was not cheap, so if price is a significant factor in your laptop choice this is not the machine for you. Microsoft are trying to compete with Apple’s Macbook range.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So what did I get for my money:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Windows 10 Pro&lt;/li>
&lt;li>16Gb RAM&lt;/li>
&lt;li>512Gb SSD (Formatted Size nearer 474Gb)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>6th Generation Intel Core i7 Processor&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Surface Pen&lt;/li>
&lt;li>13.5-inch touch screen&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>I have only had the device for a few days but these are my thoughts so far. My primary reason for buying this is for doing development work with Visual Studio and SQL Server.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I really like the Surface Pen. This is a feature that I didn’t think I would use much. The Pen connects via bluetooth and allows interaction with the touch screen. The pressure sensitive screen allows all sort of touch actions to be performed.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I especially like the choice of keyboards that are offered when the physical keyboard is detached. You can have either a on screen keyboard which you can type with pen or fingers, an on screen keyboard that splits in half or you can write with the pen. This is an amazing feature. My handwriting is not good but most of the time it understands my scrawl. With this option you can hand write a tweet or fill in a form on a webpage. For speed I would not recommend this form of input for large amounts of text, but for browsing the web of when you are just clicking on links it is great.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Windows Hello – I can unlock windows just by looking at my screen. How cool is that! It was really easy to setup, it just takes a photo of your face and next time you login all you need to do it look at the screen. Note if you are working in tablet mode, make sure the tablet is the correct way up.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It’s not all brilliant though. Detaching the screen is fiddly and sometimes takes a few moments to do. A few times I have felt I needed another hand but I am sure the more I do this the easier I will find it to do.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Battery life isn’t great especially when running off the tablet only. This is due to the machine having two batteries, one in the base and one in the screen so with keyboard attached you have much longer use times. Actually I am finding the battery is lasting longer now that I have used it for a few days.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The screen has a very high resolution 3000 x 2000 but using clever zooming technology everything is still readable and not tiny. However I use Remote Desktop a lot and this caused me a problem. When RDPing the remote session used the host screen resolution which made everything tiny on my servers. The solution to this can be found on &lt;a href="https://superuser.com/questions/891413/remote-connection-desktop-manager-2-7-does-not-support-dpi-scaling-anymore" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">SuperUser&lt;/a>
and involved using Microsoft’s Remote Desktop Connection Manager, a cool bit of software for managing multiple RDP sessions. This is actually an improvement on the way I usually work, but until I found the answer this was annoying.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Another minor annoyance with the keyboard is that you can’t press Ctrl-Alt-Del with one hand. Normally this isn’t a requirement but if the screen locks while I have my son on my lap I am stuck, but I won’t blame the surface book for this.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When I got my Surface Book I was also given a Microsoft Wireless Display Adapter. I am not a fan of this bit of tech as I can’t get it to work. I briefly got my old laptop to connect but my Surface Book keeps telling me NO!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Overall I like the Surface Book. It is certainly the nicest laptop I have ever used. Now that I have the docking station I can connect two monitors, have a wired internet connection and it becomes a proper work horse. What does everyone else think? Better than Apple’s range of laptops?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Windows 9 or do I mean 10</title><link>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2014/windows-9-or-do-i-mean-10/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2014 20:00:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.funkysi1701.com/posts/2014/windows-9-or-do-i-mean-10/</guid><description>&lt;p>Like many systems administrators I watched as the news came out yesterday about the latest version of windows. What would it be like? What would it be called? Would it be better or worse than previous versions?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I was shocked when the name of the new operating system was revealed to be Windows 10. What really!? At first I though someone had tweeted a photoshopped image of the press conference, but no it was really going to be called Windows 10.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img class="img-fluid" alt="Windows 10" src="https://storageaccountblog9f5d.blob.core.windows.net/blazor/wp-content/uploads/2014/10/windows_10_fullwidth.jpg?w=800&amp;amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy"
/>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Windows 10 is the next operating system to be released after windows 8, many had been calling it windows 9 or windows Threshold.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Microsoft has never had a fixed naming convention for its OSes, so should we really be that surprised at its new name.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Windows 1.0 (1985)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Windows 2.0 (1987)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Windows 3.0 (1990)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Windows 95 (1995)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Windows 98 (1998)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Windows ME (2000)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Windows XP (2001)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Windows Vista (2007)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Windows 7 (2009)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Windows 8 (2012)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Windows 10 (2015)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;em>Windows 11 (2021)&lt;/em>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>One reason Microsoft may have gone with with Windows 10 is because they wanted to signify that the coming Windows release would be the last “major” Windows update. What does it mean to be the last major update?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you look at the list of OSes above you will see that between XP and Vista was a huge 6 years, this gap is/has caused a huge headache for IT professionals (me included). Software was written for XP because that is all that was available, when XP moved out of support earlier this year it caused loads as problems as people tried to get this software to work on more modern OSes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If windows 10 is around for a long time we may end up with a similar situation to XP, in that loads of software will run only on it and cause problems if you try and port it to whatever comes next. I am only a trainee developer so I don’t know what is involved with building an OS, but I would imagine there must be things that are very difficult or almost impossible to fix without ripping them out and starting again which is what happens when a new version of an OS is written.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Only time will tell if Windows 10 really is the last version of windows and what will happen to the OS in the future. What ever the case I am downloading a preview so I can have a look (I want my start menu back!)&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>